<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Phoenix Flavour – Prelude</title><link>http://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/01-prelude/</link><description>Recent content in Prelude on The Phoenix Flavour</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="http://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/01-prelude/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Skyrim-Se: About the guide</title><link>http://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/01-prelude/01-about-the-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/01-prelude/01-about-the-guide/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Phoenix Flavour, at its core, is a modding guide like many others, teaching you how to set up a certain set of tools and mods for best results. Unlike other modding guides, it contains many optional mods as well as a dedicated Customisation section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, the guide is highly accessible for modding beginners with its countless additional notes, explanations and screenshots. The less experience you have with modding Skyrim, the more important it is that you read everything carefully.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The guide was written with the assumption that most readers have little previous knowledge about modding and supplies the basics before going more in-depth. Whenever you feel confident about your knowledge in a certain area, feel free to skip ahead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are unwilling to dig deep into the topic of modding Skyrim, there is always the Wabbajack option (more on that below).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="wabbajack">Wabbajack&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Anyone who does not want to or is unable to invest large amounts of time into modding Skyrim SE should look into the &lt;strong>Wabbajack&lt;/strong> version of The Phoenix Flavour instead of the &lt;strong>Classic Guide&lt;/strong> (manual installation).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wabbajack is an auto-installer capable of &amp;ldquo;cloning&amp;rdquo; a full mod setup including all tweaks and changes to someone else&amp;rsquo;s system. It requires virtually no modding experiences and little effort, although the automated download process does require a Nexus Premium account.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Advantages and Disadvantages of Wabbajack&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;span style= "color: green">&lt;i class="fas fa-plus-circle">&lt;/i>&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The actual mod installation can be done over night with zero effort.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;span style= "color: green">&lt;i class="fas fa-plus-circle">&lt;/i>&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>All additional instructions will take much less time to follow and complete than a full run of the Classic Guide would.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;span style= "color: green">&lt;i class="fas fa-plus-circle">&lt;/i>&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Since most of the process is automated, it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely that you will make a mistake that takes time to track and fix.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;span style= "color: red">&lt;i class="fas fa-minus-circle">&lt;/i>&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>At least one month&amp;rsquo;s Nexus Premium subscription is required for Wabbajack to automatically download the files.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;span style= "color: red">&lt;i class="fas fa-minus-circle">&lt;/i>&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>You will learn nothing about modding or utilising the required tools.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;span style= "color: red">&lt;i class="fas fa-minus-circle">&lt;/i>&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>You will miss out on the Customisation options that the Classic Guide features.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="about-the-guide">About the guide&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="features">Features&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Regardless of whether you build the setup manually with the &lt;strong>Classic Guide&lt;/strong> or automated with the &lt;strong>Wabbajack Installer&lt;/strong>, here is what the resulting mod setup will feature:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>A Better Skyrim:&lt;/strong> The guide includes hundreds of mods across forty categories, all carefully selected to fit my vision of a lore-friendly, improved but not radically changed Skyrim. The Phoenix Flavour strives to provide a solid upgrade of the vanilla experience with modern visuals and additional content.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Custom Files and Patches:&lt;/strong> Both the final patch as well as some patches and plugin replacers installed during the mod setup have been made specifically for the guide by Umgak and myself. They ensure compatibility as well as consistency between all included mods.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Customisability:&lt;/strong> In order to account for differences in taste among all users, a large amount of mods were marked as optional and are not required to be installed. Other mods come with extensive customisation options usually provided ingame through Mod Configuration Menus. A list of additional compatible mods and optional tweaks is available in a dedicated section of the guide.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Performance:&lt;/strong> The Phoenix Flavour was created for gameplay instead of screen-archery and will for most people deliver solid results on a 1080p monitor resolution. For higher resolutions, better hardware is required. Through INI changes, reasonable texture resolutions, a performance-friendly grass overhaul as well as optional ENB installation and the choice to use low settings in DynDOLOD you can tweak your game until you reach a stable 60FPS.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="vanilla-plus">Vanilla Plus&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The concept of &amp;ldquo;vanilla plus&amp;rdquo; simply refers to a mod or mod setup that improves the existing game without attempting to turn it into something entirely different. It is a matter of preference and there are guides with different approaches out there for those who are tired of Skyrim&amp;rsquo;s core gameplay.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="included-mods">Included Mods&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can find a full list of mods &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1XFcvzBLykdkSxjX225S9tmqNWFFoTeNWUxBEK5YOIZQ/edit?usp=drive_web&amp;amp;ouid=118321045324288884377">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Visuals:&lt;/strong> Obsidian Weathers, Luminosity and Relighting Skyrim, Cathedral Landscapes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Textures:&lt;/strong> Skyrim Realistic Overhaul as base, then Noble Skyrim 2K overwritten by dozens of smaller mods.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Distant Level of Detail (LOD):&lt;/strong> DynDOLOD is included and mandatory, 3D tree LOD is optional.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ENBSeries:&lt;/strong> Using ENB is optional, there are instructions to add a preset and related mods.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Body Replacer:&lt;/strong> Caliente&amp;rsquo;s Beautiful Bodies Enhancer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Perk Overhaul:&lt;/strong> Featuring Adamant - A Perk Overhaul, vanilla-plus-style and very light-weight.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat:&lt;/strong> Based around Wildcat, both vanilla difficulty as well as lethal, fast-paced combat are possible.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Loot and Rarity:&lt;/strong> Concept borrowed from Morrowloot, although much lighter and more stream-lined.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Companions:&lt;/strong> Custom-voiced companions of (arguably) the highest quality are included: Inigo, Lucien and 3DNPCs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>DLC-Sized Mods:&lt;/strong> None included (although 3DNPC could be described as such).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Needs and Survival Mods:&lt;/strong> None included.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="our-tools">Our Tools&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Phoenix Flavour is built using the most advanced, feature-rich mod manager out there: &lt;strong>Mod Organizer 2&lt;/strong>, a tool vastly superior to both the outdated Nexus Mod Manager as well as the newer Vortex.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to MO2, we will routinely utilise the official Creation Kit as well as SSEEdit and the Cathedral Assets Optimizer in the &lt;strong>Classic Guide&lt;/strong>. Over its course you will be provided with detailed instructions for all these tools (and more) in order to teach you how and when to use them correctly.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This guide neither supports nor recommends &lt;strong>LOOT&lt;/strong>. You should not use it at any point on a TPF installation.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="recommended-hardware">Recommended Hardware&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="suggested-setup">Suggested Setup&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The specs below are recommended for those looking to install all visual mods with high settings as well as 3D tree LOD through DynDOLOD and a full ENB preset. There are plenty options within the guide that allow you to lower its performance impact so that the modded game remains playable even on weaker machines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Modded Skyrim is highly GPU-dependent. A fast card with plenty of VRAM will considerably improve performance. Installing the game on an SSD will improve load times dramatically and prevent stutter.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>CPU:&lt;/strong> Processor with high single core performance (3.2GHz or more).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>RAM:&lt;/strong> 8-16 GB of DDR3 or DDR4 memory, running at 2400MHz or faster.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>GPU:&lt;/strong> A modern card with at least 4GB of VRAM (ideally 6-8GB).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Hard Drive:&lt;/strong> At least 80GB of free space, ideally on an SSD.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Monitor:&lt;/strong> With a standard (16:9) or widescreen (21:9) aspect ratio.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Free space:&lt;/strong> The full TPF installation is about 60GB large, excluding downloads (they can easily be saved to a different hard drive). Skyrim SE is another 13GB. Obviously you need to remember that your hard drive needs to have some free space left, around 20% for optimal performance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Widescreen support:&lt;/strong> UI patches and replacers can be found in the Customisation section to be installed after the main guide.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="phoenixs-build">Phoenix&amp;rsquo;s Build&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>CPU:&lt;/strong> Intel i5 7600k @4.2GHz, hybrid-cooled&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>RAM:&lt;/strong> Corsair Vengeance 16GB DDR4-3200 Memory&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>GPU:&lt;/strong> EVGA GTX 1070 Founder’s Edition (8192MB VRAM)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SSD:&lt;/strong> Samsung 850 Evo Series 256GB SSD (OS)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SSD:&lt;/strong> Samsung 860 Evo Series 1TB SSD (Games)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Monitor:&lt;/strong> LG 27GL850-B UltraGear 1440p @144Hz (primary)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Monitor:&lt;/strong> Acer S242HL 1080p @60Hz (secondary)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="monitor-resolution">Monitor Resolution&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Never underestimate the impact that high monitor resolutions have on performance. I would consider my setup to be on the higher end of the mid-tier spectrum, and when playing at 1080p I can get stable 60-100 FPS everywhere. At 1440p, I notice a considerable performance impact, losing 20 FPS on average. With the amount of additional pixels to render on resolutions like 1440p and upwards, the hardware requirement does go up quite harshly. And don’t expect 60FPS when playing on 4K with ENB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The guide includes instructions to change the game&amp;rsquo;s resolution.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-started">Getting Started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now that you have an idea of what the guide can offer you, it is your turn to decide which route to take. Continue with the &lt;strong>Setup&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://foreverphoenix.github.io/docs/02-setup/step-01/">here&lt;/a> to install the guide manually or find the &lt;strong>Wabbajack&lt;/strong> installer with instructions &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1wl3p-Nd0JZLohjJjDAV6SmxHDW6O4fYt7pngn8Es8DU/edit#heading=h.vqn9sw772v98">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="discord">Discord&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>On our dedicated Discord server for The Phoenix Flavour, we are providing support for the main guide as well as the Wabbajack version of TPF. We are also talking guide changes, Skyrim modding, and gaming in general. Feel free to join us &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/BpwXX5f">here&lt;/a>!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skyrim-Se: Skyrim Modding</title><link>http://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/01-prelude/02-skyrim-modding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/01-prelude/02-skyrim-modding/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="what-are-mods">What are mods?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Mods are fan-made modifications that change or add to the original game. It can do anything from changing the texture of apples to adding a massive new worldspace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/">Nexus&lt;/a>, the primary hub for mods, there are around &lt;strong>85.000&lt;/strong> mods available for Skyrim and Skyrim Special Edition (including duplicates). Some of them are absolutely essential, for some better alternatives exist, some are very specific patches, some are redundant, outdated or outright broken. Some require the Script Extender or other mods. Some need additional steps to be completed before they work properly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Navigating the sheer amount of mods out there requires time, patience and some understanding of how mods work (or a guide that takes you through the process).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="modding">&amp;ldquo;Modding&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The term &amp;ldquo;modding&amp;rdquo; is fairly ambiguous: It can mean &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>creating mods&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo; as well as &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>installing mods&lt;/strong>&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Creating mods&lt;/strong> is fairly complex. The Creation Kit (Bethesda&amp;rsquo;s official modding tool) is notoriously clunky and prone to crashes (until at least the Skyrim SE version got fixed by a modder). Writing scripts in the engine’s scripting language Papyrus requires a good deal of prior coding experience. Script extender plugins are written in C++. Tinkering with textures requires at least basic skills in Photoshop, Gimp or a similar program. Modelling (editing or creating new meshes) requires very specific software like Blender which is extremely complex and cannot be learned overnight.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Installing mods&lt;/strong> is quite a bit easier and certainly more accessible. In fact, when it comes down to it, the only hard requirement is the ability to read closely. &amp;ldquo;Casual&amp;rdquo; modding - installing perhaps five or ten interesting mods - does not really require any extra steps, it is enough to drop all files into a certain folder. Depending on what these five or ten mods do, this may work out perfectly, but for anything more than that, you will have to go the extra mile, and you will have to invest time.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In order to learn how to create mods, one needs to know how mods work, what components they are made of and how they can be edited. On the other hand, installing mods is not usually a matter of &amp;ldquo;plug and play&amp;rdquo; as some instructions would have you believe, at least not if you are using more than three or four mods. Eventually the line between the two will blur, and the better you get at installing mods and making them work together, the closer you get to actually making mods yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="permissions">Permissions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Unlike other modding communities (such as Minecraft&amp;rsquo;s), sharing permissions are very strict for the vast majority of Skyrim mods. Mods for Bethesda games have a long history of being re-used without credits to the original author which explains the general unwillingness of most mod authors to grant free permissions, especially not for unedited re-uploads. As such, mod packs do not exist. The term &amp;ldquo;mod pack&amp;rdquo; is extremely controversial in the community. It is not advisable to use it in any context.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the Wabbajack tool, it is now possible to share modded setups without re-uploading the mods themselves, effectively replacing mod packs. Put simply, Wabbajack can scan a mod list, compile a list of links for all files and take note of edits made to mods. The generated output can be shared and used to replicate the setup, automatically downloading the same files and applying the edits made in the source setup.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="skyrim-le-vs-skyrim-se">Skyrim LE vs Skyrim SE&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The original game released in 2011 – &lt;strong>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim&lt;/strong> – was re-released later as the &lt;strong>Legendary Edition&lt;/strong> packaged with all three DLCs (Dawnguard, Hearthfire, Dragonborn). This version of the game is known as &lt;strong>Skyrim LE&lt;/strong>, Classic Skyrim or Oldrim, built on an older 32-bit version of the Creation Engine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 2016, Skyrim was re-released in remastered form as &lt;strong>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim - Special Edition&lt;/strong>, now based on an updated and improved 64-bit version of the Creation Engine with marginally better visuals and substantially improved stability. It is referred to as &lt;strong>Skyrim SE&lt;/strong> and was released alongside the dreaded Creation Club but revitalised the modding scene in spite of initial doubts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Several years after the release of the Special Edition, the modding community has long caught up. With many new mods available exclusively for this version of the game as well as stability being much so easier to achieve, Skyrim Special Edition is the better choice for modded setups.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most Wabbajack mod lists are made for Skyrim SE.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hosting-platforms">Hosting Platforms&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As mentioned, the vast majority of mods are hosted on &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/">Nexus Mods&lt;/a>, a massive hub for mods supporting over 250 games. Unsurprisingly, Bethesda games are ranking at the top with tens of thousands of mods each. The Nexus features detailed mod pages giving authors a comprehensive tool set to publish, document and support their work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another host for Skyrim Special Edition mods is Bethesda&amp;rsquo;s own &lt;a href="https://bethesda.net/">Beth.net&lt;/a> platform which includes a very rudimentary mod hub with a fraction of the features that the Nexus offers. Many popular mods are available on both platforms, although Bethnet “exclusives” are usually inferior to Nexus alternatives because they were made for consoles. Bethnet mods can be downloaded through the in-game mod manager which is capable of loading plugins and nothing else. While this may be interesting for XBOX or Playstation owners, Bethesda&amp;rsquo;s modding platform and integration is so vastly inferior to the Nexus that it is simply irrelevant for actual PC modding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Similarly irrelevant is the &lt;a href="https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/">Steam Workshop&lt;/a> for Skyrim SE, also hosting a number of mods that are available on the Nexus already - either directly or through a (usually superior) alternative. Like on Beth.net, mods installed through the Steam Workshop are simply dumped into your game folder with no way to properly manage them beyond installing / uninstalling.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-script-extender">The Script Extender&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The most important tool / resource / mod available for Skyrim is the &lt;strong>Skyrim Script Extender&lt;/strong>, or &lt;strong>SKSE&lt;/strong> for short. The Script Extender for Skyrim Special Edition is usually referred to as &lt;strong>SKSE64&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While the Creation Kit allows modders to work with a tool set similar to what the developers used, the Script Extender goes a step further and hooks directly into the engine. In order for it to function properly, the game must be run through the Script Extender executable instead of the original launcher. As the name suggests, it &amp;ldquo;extends scripts&amp;rdquo;, or more specifically the available functions modders can call in their scripts. It is not exactly a mod but rather a modder’s resource.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through the added functionality of the Script Extender, mods like the interface overhaul &lt;strong>SkyUI&lt;/strong> and its &lt;strong>Mod Configuration Menu&lt;/strong> component are made possible in the first place. Many features that would otherwise be difficult to implement can be realised through Script Extender plugins such as the mod &lt;strong>SSE Engine Fixes&lt;/strong> which rewrites sections of the Creation Engine itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Script Extender and any SKSE plugin is &lt;strong>version dependent&lt;/strong> and only works with the game version it was made for. For example, SKSE64 2.0.17 is only compatible with Skyrim SE 1.5.97, and will not work with any other version of the game.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-note-on-consoles">A Note on Consoles&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For Skyrim Special Edition and Fallout 4, modding is &amp;ldquo;supported&amp;rdquo; on consoles (XBOX One and Playstation 4) through Bethesda’s own platform. However, the available options as far as mod installation and configuration go are so severely limited on consoles that it isn’t even comparable to what is possible on PC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To give a few examples:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>No assets on PS4.&lt;/strong> Thanks to Sony, only plugins (a central component of many mods) can be installed on Playstations. Without the ability to include scripts, textures, meshes or other loose files, mod authors are severely limited in their options.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>No script extender.&lt;/strong> Most complex mods will never work for consoles because they require SKSE. Others need workarounds and extremely jarring ingame items for their configuration. You cannot install any mods that fix engine bugs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>No tweaking of mods.&lt;/strong> There is no way to remove or edit files from a mod (unless you are the author and repackage it on PC), or edit the INI files of either the game or mods.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Limited space.&lt;/strong> If memory serves, there is about 5GB of space for mods on the XBOX. Compare this to a decent modded setup on PC which easily cracks 100GB.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Limited hardware.&lt;/strong> Graphic improvements are possible but only on a very small scale due to hardware restrictions. Post processing injectors like ENBSeries or even ReShade cannot be installed.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you truly intend to get into modding, you need a PC. There is simply no way around it. And yes, you can play modded Skyrim with a controller on PC.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-creation-club">The Creation Club&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For all the engine improvements we enjoy on the Special Edition, there is a catch and it&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://creationclub.bethesda.net/en">Creation Club&lt;/a>&amp;quot;. Additional content for Skyrim SE made by Bethesda devs or independent contractors (many of them well-known modders) is sold for &amp;ldquo;credits&amp;rdquo; which must be bought with real-world currency. While Beth goes through great pains to argue that these &amp;ldquo;creations&amp;rdquo; are not in fact paid mods, they certainly are micro-transactions, and in a single-player game no less.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The most immediate problem with the Creation Club is that nobody can ignore it. Even those who are totally uninterested in buying micro DLC for Skyrim will be affected every time the shop is updated with more content as these updates somehow require Bethesda to update the game executable (SkyrimSE.exe) every time. This in turn requires the Script Extender and all SKSE plugins to be updated, a huge inconvenience for everyone involved.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skyrim-Se: Modding Basics</title><link>http://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/01-prelude/03-modding-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/01-prelude/03-modding-basics/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>