<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Phoenix Flavour – Initial Setup</title><link>http://thephoenixflavour.com/beginners-guide/initial-setup/</link><description>Recent content in Initial Setup on The Phoenix Flavour</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="http://thephoenixflavour.com/beginners-guide/initial-setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beginners-Guide: Prerequisites</title><link>http://thephoenixflavour.com/beginners-guide/initial-setup/prerequisites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://thephoenixflavour.com/beginners-guide/initial-setup/prerequisites/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="11-requirements">1.1 Requirements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The ability to read closely and attentively.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/489830/The_Elder_Scrolls_V_Skyrim_Special_Edition/">Skyrim Special Edition&lt;/a> on Steam.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A legit Windows 7 / 8 / 8.1 / 10 installation (64bit).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Editing software such as &lt;a href="https://notepad-plus-plus.org/">Notepad++&lt;/a> (freeware).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>An archiving tool like &lt;a href="https://www.7-zip.org/download.html">7zip&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://www.win-rar.com/start.html?&amp;amp;L=0">WinRAR&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Latest drivers for your GPU (&lt;a href="https://www.nvidia.de/Download/index.aspx">NVIDIA&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://www.amd.com/en/support">AMD&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A free (or Premium) account on &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/">Nexus Mods&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>With a &lt;strong>Nexus Premium&lt;/strong> subscription you will benefit from uncapped download speeds as well skipping a second confirmation button before a file is downloaded. If you use the Nexus a lot, modding different games, it is absolutely worth it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="12-show-file-extensions">1.2 Show File Extensions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By default, file extensions (such as EXE, PNG or ESP) are hidden in the Windows Explorer. Make sure that you have them set to visible, otherwise you will have a hard time following some instructions.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open the Windows Explorer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>View&lt;/strong> tab at the top.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure &lt;strong>File name extensions&lt;/strong> is checked.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/setup/file_extensions_visible.png" alt="File Extensions Visible">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="13-your-modding-folder">1.3 Your Modding Folder&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In order to keep all files related to modding Skyrim SE in one place, we will create a dedicated directory. It will serve as a hub for all tools, downloaded mod archives, custom files, notes, backups, screenshots, and whatever else you can think of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Throughout the guide I will refer to this folder as &lt;strong>Your Modding Folder&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="131-main-directory">1.3.1 Main Directory&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Create a new folder anywhere on an HDD with at least 200GB of free space. Don&amp;rsquo;t waste SSD space on this.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Name it whatever you like, for example &lt;strong>Skyrim SE Modding&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add several more new folders inside:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>ARCHIVE&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Backups&lt;/li>
&lt;li>temp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tools&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="132-mod-archive">1.3.2 Mod Archive&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Proper organisation is key when modding Skyrim. You will come back many times to update or re-install mods, or selectively extract files without installing the whole package. This is where the previously created &lt;strong>ARCHIVE&lt;/strong> comes into play - it will contain the majority of downloaded mod archives.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Create several more folders inside the &lt;strong>ARCHIVE&lt;/strong> folder:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>ENBSeries - Binaries&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ENBSeries - Presets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MO2 Downloads&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SKSE64&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="14-monitor-calibration">1.4 Monitor Calibration&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="141-gamma-and-brightness">1.4.1 Gamma and Brightness&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Assuming you already have your monitor configured with your preferred settings for resolution and refresh rate (in my case that is 2560x1440 and 144Hz), you might still want to adjust the brightness and/or gamma either through your graphics card control panel or Windows&amp;rsquo; inbuilt calibration tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Your monitor should have been running for at least 30 minutes before you adjust it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>WINDOWS:&lt;/strong> Control Panel &amp;gt; Colour Management &amp;gt; Advanced &amp;gt; Calibrate display&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NVIDIA:&lt;/strong> Control Panel &amp;gt; NVIDIA Control Panel &amp;gt; Adjust Desktop Color Settings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>AMD:&lt;/strong> Unfortunately I do not own an AMD GPU and never have so I cannot give advice here. Use the inbuilt Windows calibration tool.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>To help you find the sweet spot for your monitor, check out these resources:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://i.imgur.com/k1v8p1M.png">CLF ENB - monitor calibration help&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.photofriday.com/info/calibrate">Photo Friday Monitor Calibration Tool&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.lagom.nl/lcd-test/">Lagom: LCD monitor test images&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="142-dynamic-range">1.4.2 Dynamic Range&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It is recommended that you ensure your monitor&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Dynamic Range&lt;/strong> is set to &amp;ldquo;Full&amp;rdquo; if it is connected to your PC via DisplayPort or HDMI. Instructions for both NVIDIA and AMD based systems can be found &lt;a href="https://pcmonitors.info/articles/correcting-hdmi-colour-on-nvidia-and-amd-gpus/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It turns out I actually had my monitor set to &amp;ldquo;Limited&amp;rdquo; for many years and grew so used to it that setting the Dynamic Range to &amp;ldquo;Full&amp;rdquo; only irritated me. Eventually I set it back to &amp;ldquo;Limited&amp;rdquo; with no regrets. Your mileage may vary.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Beginners-Guide: Skyrim SE</title><link>http://thephoenixflavour.com/beginners-guide/initial-setup/skyrim-se/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://thephoenixflavour.com/beginners-guide/initial-setup/skyrim-se/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="21-recommended-directory">2.1 Recommended Directory&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The point of reinstalling Skyrim SE is not only to make sure you have a clean, vanilla setup but also to be able to control where the game is installed on your drive. Here is what you need to keep in mind:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>UAC protected folders.&lt;/strong> UAC protected folders and their contents have higher security standards than other folders which can cause all kinds of issues for modding tools. To prevent any such issues from occuring in the future, avoid installing any modding tools or the game under &lt;code>C:\Program Files&lt;/code> or &lt;code>C:\Program Files x86&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Further considerations:&lt;/strong> While it is highly recommend to install the modded game on an SSD for faster loading screens and potential decrease or elimination of stuttering, be aware that a large amount of free space is required. This is because Skyrim SE and Mod Organizer 2 should be installed on the same drive. While the Skyrim SE base installation reaches around 13GB, your MO2 directory may eventually grow well beyond 50GB in size, depending on the amount and types of mods you add. If you can spare 100GB or more of SSD space, it is highly recommended you do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Installing Skyrim SE or any related tools in an UAC protected folder will disqualify from getting support on our Discord server.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="22-uninstalling-skyrim-se">2.2 Uninstalling Skyrim SE&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Skip this step if you do not have Skyrim SE installed.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open Steam and go to your &lt;strong>Library&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find &lt;strong>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Special Edition&lt;/strong> in the list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click it and select &lt;strong>Uninstall&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait for the process to complete before you continue.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="23-new-steam-library">2.3 New Steam Library&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For the purpose of the guide (in order to prevent confusion) I will refer to the Library in Steam as the &lt;strong>Game Library&lt;/strong>. It is the second of four items in the top menu in Steam and contains a list of all your games.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Steam Library&lt;/strong> on the other hand is a directory on your hard drive into which your Steam games are installed. By default this would be &lt;code>C:\Program Files x86\Steam\steamapps\common\&lt;/code>. Since we do not want to have files inside an UAC protected folder like Program Files x86, we should not install Skyrim SE in the default directory. A new &lt;strong>Steam Library&lt;/strong> is required.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It is important to note that Steam only allows one &lt;strong>Steam Library&lt;/strong> per hard drive, although there is a workaround. If for instance you already have a &lt;strong>Steam Library&lt;/strong> on your C:\ drive, but you want to have your modding files on the same drive, you need to create a new &lt;strong>Steam Library&lt;/strong> manually following the instructions &lt;a href="https://steamcommunity.com/discussions/forum/1/135511294066324002">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>If you already have a separate Steam Library outside the UAC protected folders on the drive you want to install Skyrim SE and Mod Organizer 2 on, skip ahead to section 2.4. Otherwise follow the instructions below to create a new &lt;strong>Steam Library&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open Steam and go into the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the &lt;strong>Downloads&lt;/strong> tab, select &lt;strong>Steam Library Folders&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Add Library Folder&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Point it to a location somewhere outside the UAC protected folders, for example: &lt;code>G:\Steam Library\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Close all windows when you’re done.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="24-reinstallation">2.4 Reinstallation&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open Steam and go into your &lt;strong>Game Library&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find &lt;strong>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Special Edition&lt;/strong> in the list and click &lt;strong>Install&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>As location, select the Steam Library you just created.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait for Skyrim SE to be downloaded and installed.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="25-version-number">2.5 Version Number&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Because the Script Extender and certain other mods are version dependent, you must run a specific version of Skyrim SE. That is typically the latest version unless there was an update recently and the community hasn&amp;rsquo;t caught up yet in which case you need to roll back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The currently supported version of Skyrim SE is: &lt;strong>1.5.97&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you accidentally updated to a newer version, please refer to &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/19658">this guide here&lt;/a> in order to roll back.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="251-how-to-check-version-number">2.5.1 How to check version number&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Navigate to your &lt;strong>root&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click &lt;strong>SkyrimSE.exe&lt;/strong> and select &lt;strong>Properties&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Switch to the &lt;strong>Details&lt;/strong> tab and check under &lt;strong>Product version&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/setup/skyrim_se_1_5_97_0.png" alt="Skyrim SE 1.5.97.0">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="26-disable-auto-updates">2.6 Disable Auto Updates&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When Skyrim SE receives another update - which, thanks to the Creation Club, happens every once in a while - SKSE64 and all SKSE plugins will need to be updated as well. This usually takes at least a week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, you can continue playing the previous version with SKSE64 and all your mods by simply setting Skyrim SE to only update when launching the game. Since you start the game through the SKSE64 launcher, Steam will never update.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open Steam and find &lt;strong>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Special Edition&lt;/strong> in your &lt;strong>Game Library&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click it, select &lt;strong>Properties&lt;/strong> and switch to the &lt;strong>Updates&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure &lt;strong>Automatic updates&lt;/strong> is set to &lt;strong>Only update this game when I launch it&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Problem solved!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/setup/sse_disable_auto_updates.png" alt="Disable Auto Updates">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="27-executables-backup">2.7 Executables Backup&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Although Steam will no longer update Skyrim SE automatically, I still recommend keeping backups of the two executables (&lt;strong>SkyrimSE.exe&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>SkyrimSELauncher.exe&lt;/strong>), just in case. If you accidentally updated, all you need to do to roll back is replace the executables in your &lt;strong>root&lt;/strong> folder with the ones you backed up. This also comes in handy if you had to regenerate INI files or validate game files through Steam for whatever reason and were forced to update.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Create a new folder: &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\Backups\Skyrim SE 1.x.x&lt;/code> (enter the current version number).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Copy the following two files from your &lt;strong>root&lt;/strong> folder into the new directory:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SkyrimSE.exe&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SkyrimSELauncher.exe&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="28-creations">2.8 Creations&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you ever bought anything from the Creation Club (or grabbed &amp;ldquo;creations&amp;rdquo; while they were up for free), they will be re-installed alongside Skyrim. Treat them like any other mod and consider compatibility issues if you want to include them in your setup. Guides, including The Phoenix Flavour, do not normally support &amp;ldquo;creations&amp;rdquo;. I highly recommend moving them out of your Data folder, at least for now.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Create a new folder: &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\Backups\Creation Club&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select all files beginning with &lt;strong>cc&lt;/strong> (ESLs and BSAs) in your Data folder and hit CTRL+X.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to your new Creation Club folder and paste them there (CTRL+V)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="29-disable-steam-overlay">2.9 Disable Steam Overlay&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This step is optional.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While I’ve personally never had any issues with the Steam Overlay in modded Skyrim SE, that seems to be an exception and it is indeed common practice to disable it as a precaution. Note that we will only disable it for Skyrim SE. The overlay will still work as usual for all other games.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since disabling the Steam Overlay will also prevent you from taking screenshots with Steam, I keep it enabled - as I said, without problems so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Once again, open Steam.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find &lt;strong>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Special Edition&lt;/strong> in your Library.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click it and select &lt;strong>Properties&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Uncheck &lt;strong>Enable the Steam Overlay while in-game&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Close the window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Beginners-Guide: The Creation Kit</title><link>http://thephoenixflavour.com/beginners-guide/initial-setup/the-creation-kit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://thephoenixflavour.com/beginners-guide/initial-setup/the-creation-kit/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="31-acquisition">3.1 Acquisition&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With the release of Skyrim SE, Bethesda also published a new version of their official tool kit, the Creation Kit (or CK for short), updated for the new 64bit engine. Unfortunately the CK 2.0 can no longer be downloaded directly from Steam but requires the Bethesda Launcher and a Beth.net account.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Go to Bethesda.net, the official website.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scroll all the way down to the footer (bottom of the page).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>Download&lt;/strong> button in the &lt;strong>Bethesda Launcher&lt;/strong> section.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Double-click the downloaded executable.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/setup/download_beth_launcher.png" alt="Download Beth Launcher">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="32-installation">3.2 Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Let the executable guide you through the installation process.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When that is done, you must log-in with your Beth.net account or register a new one.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once you’re logged in, check the list of game icons on the left.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the two arrows &lt;code>&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code> at the top to open the full list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select &lt;strong>Creation Kit: Skyrim&lt;/strong> (with the white icon) and click &lt;strong>Install&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The CK should be installed directly into your &lt;strong>root&lt;/strong> folder (see picture).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait for the files to download.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Bethesda Launcher is not required to launch the Creation Kit but it is used to update it and I recommend keeping it installed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/setup/ck_installation_path.png" alt="Creation Kit Installation Path">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="33-disable-auto-updates">3.3 Disable Auto Updates&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In the Bethesda Launcher, go to &lt;strong>Game Options&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Toggle off &lt;strong>Auto Updates&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Close the Bethesda Launcher.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/setup/ck_disable_auto_updates.png" alt="Disable Auto Updates">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="34-custom-ini">3.4 Custom INI&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The custom INI file will allow you to load mods with multiple master files as well as fix some Creation Kit issues and crashes.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download this tweaked &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/19817">Creation Kit Custom INI&lt;/a> (the main file) manually from the Nexus.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract the INI file into your &lt;strong>root&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="35-creation-kit-fixes">3.5 Creation Kit Fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Nukem&amp;rsquo;s CK Fixes greatly improves the Creation Kit even for regular users. Simple procedures such as resaving a plugin are sped up and take less than half the time they used to. It also fixes bugs and crashes, and adds many convenience features for mod authors.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/20061">SSE Creation Kit Fixes&lt;/a> (CK64 Fixes release 2.x) manually from the Nexus.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract the three DLL files and the INI into your &lt;strong>root&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Optional:&lt;/strong> Move the archive to &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\ARCHIVE\CK Fixes&lt;/code> to keep as a backup.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We are not downloading the other CK Fixes main file because it is not needed for anyone except mod authors.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="36-vanilla-scripts">3.6 Vanilla Scripts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Creation Kit installation includes a &lt;strong>Scripts.zip&lt;/strong> which contains all source files for the vanilla Skyrim scripts. With these source files it is possible to edit and recompile vanilla scripts. This is usually unnecessary unless you plan on tinkering with the scripts themselves which we are in fact going to do at the very end of the guide.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="361-unpacking-scriptszip">3.6.1 Unpacking Scripts.zip&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Navigate to your &lt;strong>root&lt;/strong> folder and launch &lt;strong>CreationKit.exe&lt;/strong> from there.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You will be asked to unpack &lt;strong>Scripts.zip&lt;/strong>, click &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once that is done, you can close the Creation Kit.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="362-fixing-filepaths">3.6.2 Fixing Filepaths&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Correct script file paths will only ever matter to users looking to edit and recompile scripts. You can skip this step if you don&amp;rsquo;t think it will ever be relevant to you. It is not required for either SkyPlus or TPF.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>For some yet uncovered reason, Bethesda decided to flip the file paths for the &lt;strong>scripts&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>source&lt;/strong> folders for Skyrim SE. Instead of &lt;code>Data\Scripts\Source&lt;/code>, it&amp;rsquo;s now &lt;code>Data\Source\Scripts&lt;/code>. The majority of mods, particularly those originally created for SLE, still come with the old file path for scripts. The &lt;strong>CreationKitCustom.ini&lt;/strong> we installed a few steps earlier resets the file path to the SLE default.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To complement the INI change, revert the folder names for the vanilla script source files to the SLE default:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Rename the &lt;strong>Source&lt;/strong> folder in your &lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong> folder to &lt;strong>Scripts&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Double-click the &lt;strong>Scripts&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rename the &lt;strong>Scripts&lt;/strong> folder inside to &lt;strong>Source&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The resulting filepath should be &lt;code>Data\Scripts\Source&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>