<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Phoenix Flavour – Appendix</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/wtp/appendix/</link><description>Recent content in Appendix on The Phoenix Flavour</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/wtp/appendix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Wtp: Troubleshooting</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/wtp/appendix/troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/wtp/appendix/troubleshooting/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="getting-stuck-when-interacting-with-a-terminal">Getting stuck when interacting with a terminal&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>This is not a WTP-specific issue.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Occasionally you may get stuck when attempting to access a terminal. This can be fixed by opening the console (tilde key, right above TAB on your keyboard) and typing in &lt;code>tcl&lt;/code>. Upon closing the console (hitting tilde again), you should be able to use the terminal. Remember to open the console and type in &lt;code>tcl&lt;/code> again to re-enable collision.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/appendix/stuck-terminal.jpg" alt="Stuck Terminal">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="subtitles-get-stuck-during-first-minutemen-quest">Subtitles get stuck during first Minutemen quest&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>This is not a WTP-specific issue.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When talking to Preston and Sturges in the Museum of Freedom, the subtitles usually get stuck for a time during the conversation. This happens in vanilla too and cannot be fixed as far as I know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/appendix/subtitles-stuck.jpg" alt="Subtitles Stuck">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="issues-with-the-pip-boy-map-when-playing-with-a-controller">Issues with the Pip-Boy map when playing with a controller&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By default, the Pip-boy UI is of a &lt;a href="https://staticdelivery.nexusmods.com/mods/1151/images/48758/48758-1609598190-107962601.jpeg">pitifully low resolution&lt;/a>. Unfortunately, increasing it will cause a bug when playing with a controller that restrict the cursor to the upper left corner on the Pip-boy map.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can work around this by turning off your controlling, opening your map, then turning it back on again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The alternative is to revert the high resolution tweak in the INI files. To do so, follow these instructions:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open the &lt;strong>INI Editor&lt;/strong> in Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>fallout4prefs.ini&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scroll down to the &lt;code>[Display]&lt;/code> section.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Revert the values for the Pip-boy height and width to the default (see below).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>uPipboyTargetHeight=700
uPipboyTargetWidth=876
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button at the bottom and close the window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/appendix/map-gamepad.jpg" alt="Map Cursor Stuck">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="flickering-puddles">Flickering puddles&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is a persistent issue with cubemaps. We have a fix for it, &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/46787">Fixed flickering puddles&lt;/a>, &lt;del>but the bug still occurs and I&amp;rsquo;m honestly clueless.&lt;/del> I fixed the fix in WTP 1.6 and it should be fine now.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="nights-are-too-dark">Nights are too dark&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can change (night) brightness in the ENB settings. Please refer to the sticky comment on the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/9253?tab=posts">True Nights&lt;/a> mod page for instructions (note that in WTP, the ENB GUI is open with F11).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wtp: Changelog</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/wtp/appendix/changelog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/wtp/appendix/changelog/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="release-16">Release 1.6&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>03/06/2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Starting a new game is required.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For this update I checked out the new &lt;strong>FallUI&lt;/strong> suite of interface replacers and took the opportunity to review WTP&amp;rsquo;s existing interface mods. I came to the decision to once again remove &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/27216">Extended Dialogue Interface&lt;/a> and revert to &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/1235">Full Dialogue Interface&lt;/a> which I like far better. After careful consideration, I decided &lt;em>against&lt;/em> including &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/51813">FallUI - HUD&lt;/a> because even with my DEF_UI HUD preset, it would make item pickup prompts look &lt;a href="https://i.imgur.com/Bd9w9VZ.jpg">weird&lt;/a> with a huge gap between the item name and the button prompts. I also removed FallUI - Map because I didn&amp;rsquo;t like it. However, FallUI - HUD and FallUI - Map are still going to be installed in case someone wants them (but are disabled by default).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also removed &lt;strong>Widescreen&lt;/strong> support. I can&amp;rsquo;t test it, it&amp;rsquo;s additional headache, I&amp;rsquo;d have to write extra instructions for changing the aspect ratio in the various FallUI MCMs. Sorry to everyone on ultrawide monitors, it&amp;rsquo;s just not worth the effort to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When updating, please also move the Game Folder Files into your root folder and overwrite (ENB binaries updated).&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added zEdit (I needed it for one merge)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added deorder&amp;rsquo;s MO2 Plugins (only useful for me)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added F4 Creation Kit Fixes (only useful for me)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added DEF_HUD - My Preset (smaller vanilla, crosshair to dot)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Tactical Reload&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Jamaica Plain Navmesh Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Weston Water LOD Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Assaultron Left Hand Hydraulic Frame Arm Mesh Bug Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Perception Bug Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Carlisle Typewriter Mesh Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Car Physics Death Bug Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added 1 Rad Bugfix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Far Harbor Marine Armor Boots Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Cryo Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Cryolator Cryo-Cell Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Pool Rack Fix (finally the game is playable)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added X-01 Power Armor Neck and Minor Light FX Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FallUI - HUD (disabled by default)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Full Dialogue Interface&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added String Patches for Full Dialogue Interface&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added UNLIMITED POWER - Tesla Rifle Projectiles Create Visual Effect on Impact&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fix for Forsythia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Far Harbor Pine Branches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Natural Bundle - Masonry Set&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Natural Bundle - Submarine Set&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Defined Hightech Floor Tiles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fix for Tiles02&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added ADs 2X Rez&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Wall Worldmap&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Globes (retexture)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Library and Subway Tokens HD Remastered&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Deathclaws HD Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Flamer Project&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Leafblower Junk Jet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Synthkind Redefined&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Auto Lockpick&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Auto Hack&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Better Explosives Redux&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fortune Finder 4 Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vault 88 Template - Optimised&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Workshop Power Pack&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vault 88 Essentials&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vault 88 Essentials - WTP Tweaks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Whose Quest Is It Anyway&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added River Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mod Organizer 2 to 2.4.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ENBSeries to 0.455&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout to 1.23.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Bullet Counted Reload System to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.0.14a&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Wetness Shader Fix to 3.41&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Companion Stealth Distance Fix to 7.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated FallUI Confirm Boxes to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated FallUI Workbench to 1.2.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Fallout 4 Ultimate Window Overhaul to 3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Visible Idle Markers to 1.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated LOST Audio Tweaks to 1.7a&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated the LOST Audio Tweaks - True Storms and RAO Patch to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Extended Dialogue Interface&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Scrolling Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Change PoV&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Valentine Jaw Sync (part of Synthkind Redefined)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Weapon Rack Fixes (largely covered by UFO4P)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Detailed Deathclaws&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Fallout 3 NV Feral Ghouls Replacer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Simple Crafting Station - K-9 Harness Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Sprint Engine Limitations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reinstalled Fixed Flickering Puddles (was missing one file, may fix lingering issues)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FallUI - Map is now disabled by default&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rebuilt the Weapons BA2s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rebuilt the Creatures BA2s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deleted the broken IMAD record in True Nights to be on the safe side (I tweaked it before but can&amp;rsquo;t remember how)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated precombines for the area around the new Sanctuary bridge (thanks for talking me through that, Lively!)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Fortune Finder tweaks from Loot Logic Scrounger Fortune Finder Rebalance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reverted UNLIMITED POWER changes to Tesla Rifle damage, capacity, and reload speed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added new &amp;lsquo;Backpack&amp;rsquo; tag to DEV_INV_TAGS.xml&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Merged the three music plugins together and removed the separate plugins&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Replaced the now redundant music patch with the merged plugin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extracted the Fallout Suite BA2 since there is no longer a plugin to load it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed some conflicts between Better Explosives Redux and other mods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated INI files from scratch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>K-9 Harness&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Until now fadingsignal&amp;rsquo;s K-9 Harness for Dogmeat could be crafted at the crafting station which was the original implementation. I have never been happy with this and in this update I finally did something about it. You can now find exactly &lt;em>one&lt;/em> K-9 Harness in the world. The location happens to be a police station for obvious reasons - if you want to know where exactly you can find it, double-click the new K-9 Integration Patch in Mod Organizer 2 and check the &lt;strong>Notes&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Creation Club&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WTP 1.6 adds &lt;em>optional&lt;/em> support for some &amp;ldquo;creations&amp;rdquo; (only the Modular Military Backpack so far). You can find details and instructions &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/wtp/wtp-resources/creation-club">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated a bunch of pages. Added stuff on the &lt;strong>Finalisation&lt;/strong> page. Don&amp;rsquo;t remember everything.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added a link for LostDragonist&amp;rsquo;s Steam Library Setup Tool on the &lt;strong>Fallout 4&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Widescreen support stuff from the &lt;strong>Finalisation&lt;/strong> page (sorry).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added new &lt;strong>Creation Club&lt;/strong> page under Resources for Modular Military Backpack support.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed the Custom Files page. All relevant documentation was moved into Mod Organizer 2 (check the Notes for each mod).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Linked to True Nights for instructions on how to change night brightness on &lt;strong>Troubleshooting&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-152">Release 1.5.2&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>06/04/2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This update is safe-save. Copy over the GFF into your root folder and overwrite (ENB binaries updated).&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-1">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Mod Organizer 2 to 2.4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Re-arranged and re-coloured MO2 separators&lt;/li>
&lt;li>WTP changelogs are no longer available through MO2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ENBSeries (no version change)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout 4 to 1.22.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated PrivateProfileRedirector to 0.5.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated High FPS Physics Fix to 0.8.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated What&amp;rsquo;s Your Name to 1.12.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Less Annoying Water Foam Circles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added No Quest Autostart - BoS Fire Support&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added No Quest Autostart - Automatron&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added No Quest Autostart - Vault-Tec&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added No Quest Autostart - Far Harbor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added No Quest Autostart - Nuka World&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed some unnecessary stuff from the Phoenix Tweaks plugin&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-1">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Finalisation:&lt;/strong> Shortened the Resolution section and moved Ultrawide tweaks to this page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ultrawide:&lt;/strong> Removed this page.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Turns out that Wabbajack auto-sets the resolution in the INI files.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="release-151">Release 1.5.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>08/03/2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I fixed some errors in &lt;code>Power Armor Lore-Friendly Distribution.esp&lt;/code> by reverting the levelled lists for Atom Cats power armor to vanilla. That means they&amp;rsquo;ll be wearing T-60 armor again (instead of T-51). I know I had Atom Cats T-51 armor &lt;em>somewhere&lt;/em> but it seems to have gotten lost, resulting in these errors. I fully admit that this is a lazy solution but it works and that was always enough for Todd anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While recompiling for WJ, I also updated the links to the website (see below).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="global-site-update">Global Site Update&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>08/03/2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I finally did some spring cleaning. For the longest time it annoyed me that in my original folder structure I had categorised pages by games, for example the TPF part of the website was called &amp;ldquo;Skyrim SE&amp;rdquo; in the top menu. But what if I want to start another SE project? And you don&amp;rsquo;t want to know the chaos in my pictures folder either.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The reason I hesitated for so long to change the folder names is because it breaks every, single, link. And while fixing the internal links and file paths was merely a minor annoyance, fixing all external links is more difficult - especially considering that other people may link to TPF as well and those links are now broken. Of course I also need to recompile both TPF and WTP for Wabbajack to update the links that open automatically upon installing a Wabbajack list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I finally updated now and I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with the changes. It likely will take some time for all external links to get fix plus I suspect I may have missing some internal links and file paths.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="changes">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed the Bioware section (see below).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Renamed &amp;ldquo;Skyrim SE&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;The Phoenix Flavour&amp;rdquo; (link changed from skyrim-se to tpf).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Renamed &amp;ldquo;Fallout 4&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Welcome to Paradise&amp;rdquo; (link changed from fallout to wtp).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated all internal links and file paths - hopefully.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cleaned up my pictures folder to remove any pictures that are no longer in the guide.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated the home page, it has two buttons now and a combination of the TPF and WTP pics.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="bioware">Bioware&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The current state of things is that I have published a guide for ME1 with a draft for an ME2 version waiting for revision. But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: Modding Bioware games is quite different from modding Bethesda games. I&amp;rsquo;ve only really dipped my toes in it and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t call myself an expert by any stretch of the imagination. Something I often criticise about various smaller Skyrim modding &amp;ldquo;guides&amp;rdquo; is that their authors barely know what they&amp;rsquo;re doing. It occured to me that my Mass Effect &amp;ldquo;guides&amp;rdquo; are in essence the same thing &lt;del>with better formatting&lt;/del>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To keep a longer story short, I have developed a strong sense of imposter syndrome over those excursions into Bioware land that is causing me a fair amount of stress. Something I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the past couple years is that if you have too many things putting pressure on you at once, cut out everything that&amp;rsquo;s non-essential. Well, this time the scissors are for the Bioware section of the TPF website.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="release-15">Release 1.5&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>06/03/2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-2">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Mod Organizer 2 to 2.4.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tweaked Pipboy INI settings (increased resolution, disabled fx)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Mator&amp;rsquo;s xEdit Patching Framework&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FO4Edit cache is now saved into the Tools\FO4Edit folder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated xSE Plugin Preloader to 0.2.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Changed xSE Plugin Preloader load method to OnThreadAttach&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout to 1.20.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated the Unofficial Fallout 4 Patch to 2.1.2b&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated High FPS Physics Fix to 0.8.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed additional High FPS Physics Fix INIs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Default settings for WTP are now 60FPS and no VSYNC&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Documentation includes instructions to change the settings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reinstalled DEF_UI and only chose DEF_HUD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reverted to vanilla DEF_UI profile&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FallUI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FallUI Workbench&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FallUI Map&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Re-added LooksMenu&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Better Confirm Boxes for PC&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added TRUBY9 ULTRAWIDE DEF_UI Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Better Confirm Boxes for PC - Widescreen Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Neutral Look Up Tables LUT&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fallout 4 Enhanced Color Correction&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Retro Radio Replacer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Classic Wasteland Survival Guide - Magazine Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added U.S. Covert Operations Manual - Magazine Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Total Hack - Magazine Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Hunting Rifle Set&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Ballistic Series&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fixed Creature Death Drops&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FO4 Photo Mode&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.0.10&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simple Sorting Overhaul to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Wetness Shader Fix to 3.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Sprint Stuttering Fix to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Hazmat Suit Redux to 0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skeletal Adjustments for CBBE to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated What&amp;rsquo;s Your Name to 1.11.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Fixed and Cleaned Homeplate to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated LOST Audio Tweaks to 1.6.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated LOST Audio Tweaks - True Storms and RAO Patch to Beta&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Pip-Boy Dual Color section&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Small Map Markers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed The Humble Hunting Rifle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed ScratchMade - New Combat Shotgun and Rifle Textures&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed The Top-Notch Tommy Gun&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Assault Rifle Retexture 2K&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed HUD Customisation stuff&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repacked the Clutter BA2s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repacked the Weapon BA2s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Changed ENB hotkeys to mirror TPF&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="simple-sorting-overhaul">Simple Sorting Overhaul&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>As we have now switched to FallUI from DEF_INV, I updated my INNRs (naming rules) to have the same format as Ruddy&amp;rsquo;s sorting patcher that FallUI was intended for. That means mods for armors and weapons will be displayed in smaller font below the item name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did take a look at the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/48826">Complex Sorter&lt;/a> for FallUI which would be very convenient for me but ultimately I prefer my own icons and INNRs. Plus they already cover my power armor changes and include my preferred power armor naming scheme.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-2">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I went over all pages and fixed what I thought needed fixing. Screenshots were updated, sentences were rephrased, and instructions were clarified.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Finalisation:&lt;/strong> Added instructions for the optional LUTs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Finalisation:&lt;/strong> Added Controller Fix instructions (required because of an issue with FallUI).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Finalisation:&lt;/strong> Expanded FPS and VSYNCs instructions (they are DIY now).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Game:&lt;/strong> Removed Hotkey instructions. No longer necessary with TPF ENB hotkeys.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mod Configuration:&lt;/strong> Added instructions for Photo Mode.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Renamed the &amp;ldquo;Documentation&amp;rdquo; section to &amp;ldquo;Resources&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ultrawide:&lt;/strong> Moved this page to the Resources section.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Customisation:&lt;/strong> Removed this section. Use the FallUI MCM to customise your UI.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Troubleshooting:&lt;/strong> Added a note about flickering puddles.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-141">Release 1.4.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>26/11/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-3">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Re-enabled Authentic Handmade Weaponry (accidentally disabled the plugin in 1.4)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-14">Release 1.4&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>23/11/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-4">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Weapon Debris Crash Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Sprint Stuttering Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Less Ugly Intercom&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Laser Series&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Plasma Project&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed The Lavish Laser Musket&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed The Lavish Laser Collection&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rebuilt the Weapons BA2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout to 1.17.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Wetness Shader Fix to 3.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Handmade Turrets to 1.3.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.0.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Indubitably Ivy to 0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated What&amp;rsquo;s Your Name to 1.10.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skeletal Adjustments for CBBE - Knee Fix to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated LOST Audio Tweaks to 1.5.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated custom Sound Slider Tweaks plugin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slightly tweaked High FPS Physics Fix presets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Unhid message box and tutorial messages in my DEF_UI preset&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-131">Release 1.3.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>24/10/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Just a minor fix and clean-up for yesterday&amp;rsquo;s update.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-5">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Bullet Counted Reload System to 1.05b&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added missing ALWAYS INCLUDE flags to High FPS Physics Fix profiles&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-13">Release 1.3&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>23/10/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This update fixes a number of issues reported by users (thanks, guys!). I am also officially changing the list name to &lt;strong>Welcome to Paradise&lt;/strong>. The website, Discord channels, and Mod Organizer 2 profile have all been edited accordingly.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-6">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Hopefully fixed radio songs not playing for good&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated xSE Plugin Preloader to 0.2.3 (XML unchanged, let me know if there are issues)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout 4 to 1.16.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed some untranslated UI bits (missing strings)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Auto Gamepad Switch (caused some issues)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed scrap tag for Stogie&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added High FPS Physics Fix plus pre-configured INIs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed the separate DEF_UI preset, now editing the one packaged with the main mod&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Re-enabled compass markers for locations / Dogmeat / PA in DEF_UI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turns out Archive2 is unreliable so I repacked a bunch of BA2s with CAO&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Unpacked custom BA2 for Bleak Beauty, Musical Lore, More Where That Came From, and Elvani&amp;rsquo;s Track Pack&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed some purple cars by reverting them to vanilla, it&amp;rsquo;s a band-aid fix but the best I could do&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-3">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Finalisation:&lt;/strong> Removed instructions for NVIDIA Inspector.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Finalisation:&lt;/strong> Added instructions for the newly-added High FPS Physics Fix and my pre-configured INIs.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-121">Release 1.2.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>01/10/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-7">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Actually fixed radio tracks not playing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated xSE Plugin Preloader to 0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Please delete &lt;strong>xSE PluginPreloader.ini&lt;/strong> from your &lt;strong>root&lt;/strong> folder. Move the new &lt;strong>xSE PluginPreloader.xml&lt;/strong> and updated &lt;strong>IpHlpAPI.dll&lt;/strong> into your &lt;strong>root&lt;/strong> folder and overwrite when prompted.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="release-12">Release 1.2&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>30/09/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-8">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout to 1.12.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Placed the new Buffout TBB Redist plugin in the Game Folder Files folder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Achievements (this is now a feature in Buffout)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Actually fixed the problematic True Nights record instead of bruteforce deleting it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Classic Hostered Weapons System to 1.04c&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Start Me Up - Basic Version&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Lively&amp;rsquo;s Start Me Up Tweak&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Resolved a conflict between Start Me Up and the UFO4P&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Inlined Lively&amp;rsquo;s PPPL INI file&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Sweet Roll 5000 and rebuilt Clutter BA2s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed Diamond City Radio tracks not playing (thanks Archie!)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-4">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/wtp/installation/finalisation/">Finalisation&lt;/a>: Added this new page and moved the game resolution instructions here.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/wtp/installation/finalisation/">Finalisation&lt;/a>: Added instructions on how to force VSYNC and cap the framerate.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/wtp/installation/new-game/">New Game&lt;/a>: Removed LooksMenu related instructions as that mod was removed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/wtp/installation/new-game/">New Game&lt;/a>: Added &lt;em>seriously&lt;/em> detailed instructions for Start Me Up.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-11">Release 1.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>27/09/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-9">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Now using Lively&amp;rsquo;s pppl.ini file&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout to 1.11.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed one record from True Nights which can cause memory corruption according to Buffout&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed LooksMenu (don&amp;rsquo;t really need it anyway)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enabled the Classic Holstered Weapons Systems patch in Buffout&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adjusted loot / interact prompt and window position in my DEF_UI preset&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Switched to the Alternative Version of Fixed Flickering Puddles (hopefully fixing black pre-war Codsworth)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Skip raiding your own settlements (no time to troubleshoot the compilation error it causes)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-5">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/wtp/installation/wabbajack/">Wabbajack&lt;/a>: Added new section on how change the game resolution.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/wtp/appendix/troubleshooting/">Troubleshooting&lt;/a>: Added this page with a few known issues.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-101">Release 1.0.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>26/09/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Rolled back to &lt;strong>Buffout 4&lt;/strong> 1.7.0 as the latest version is causing crashes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-10">Release 1.0&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>26/09/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Initial release. For more info, check the &lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/phoenix-flavour-42049352">Patreon post&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Please rebuilt the site, kthxbye.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wtp: Credits</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/wtp/appendix/credits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/wtp/appendix/credits/</guid><description>
&lt;h4 id="mod-list-curated-and-maintained-by-phoenix">Mod list curated and maintained by Phoenix.&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>With tons of moral support from Lively, who is beyond a doubt the definitive Fallout 4 expert.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thanks to Halgari and the crew for creating Wabbajack. Please considering supporting Wabbajack on &lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/user?u=11907933">Patreon&lt;/a>!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/users/17506149">HoosteenElGuero&lt;/a> for &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/16541">Disable Dismemberment By Weapon&lt;/a> of which a tweaked, merged version is included.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/users/33123946">Herby&lt;/a> for &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/41121">LootBalance&lt;/a> of which an older, tweaked version is included.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thanks to the authors of all tools used in the creation of this list, primarily &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/6194">Mod Organizer 2&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/2737">FO4Edit&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/67">BethINI&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thanks to the authors of all mods featured in the mod list, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t exist without you!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thanks to all the wonderful folks on our Discord server and especially my supporters on Patreon. &amp;lt;3&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>