<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Phoenix Flavour – Documentation</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/documentation/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation on The Phoenix Flavour</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/documentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tpf: Gameplay</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/documentation/gameplay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/documentation/gameplay/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="the-tldr">The TL;DR&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>TL;DR - too long; didn&amp;rsquo;t read.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Like in vanilla, you are limited to &lt;strong>one follower&lt;/strong> at a time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Leveling is &lt;strong>slower&lt;/strong> than in vanilla until level 34-40, but you receive more perk points as you level up.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Combat is &lt;strong>more difficult&lt;/strong> than in vanilla. The recommended difficulty is &lt;strong>Adept&lt;/strong> but you are free to increase or lower it anytime.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="perks--leveling">Perks &amp;amp; Leveling&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In vanilla Skyrim, you gain levels by increasing your proficiency in various skills. Proficiency is gained by using said skills. For example, if you sneak a lot around enemies, your sneak skill will eventually increase which will also give you progress toward the next level up. Leveling up, you will then be given a choice between the three main attributes (Health, Stamina, Magicka) as well as a perk point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Levelling in TPF works the same way with some adjustments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The rate at which you gain skill progression, level-ups, perk points, and attributes is controlled by &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/35366">&lt;strong>Cheshyr’s Skyrim Uncapper&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> preset for Adamant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Among other things, Cheshyr&amp;rsquo;s Uncapper preset rebalances crafting skill gains so that they do not contribute as much to your overall progression toward the next level. Otherwise, due to the abundance of crafting material, you would be able to quickly grind out a few levels with crafting alone (like in vanilla). If skill gain for crafting professions was simply slowed down, increasing your skill level for access to higher level perks would become a frustrating grind. Thus, the best solution was to decrease the amount of progress toward a level-up a skill-up in crafting skills grants.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="leveling-up">Leveling Up&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The speed at which you level up (which is determined by how quickly you gain skill proficiency and how much the gained skill proficiency progresses you toward the next level-up) is adjusted for different periods in your playthrough. Leveling was slowed down for the early- and mid-game so that you spend more time in the arguably most interesting phase of any playthrough. As you approach level 40, level-ups will become progressively faster until they surpass the vanilla rate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This makes sense in multiple ways: The leveled loot and encounter system of vanilla Skyrim will progress you very quickly through loot tiers and enemy variants until it spits you out north of level 35, having seen the vast majority of what the game has to offer. By slowing down progression before that happens, you spend more time in that part of the game where leveling up constantly unlocks new enemy types and gear variants as you play. This part of the game is also where many of the unique quests unlock, Daedric quests among them. You’ll be collecting your first artifacts and catch glimpses of what you will become.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to keep your own progression interesting, you will be awarded a bonus perk point at regular intervals when leveling up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, if you select Health or Magicka as your attribute when leveling you up, you will also receive a small amount of additional carry weight. In vanilla, your carry weight will only increase (by +5 points) if you select Stamina. This is still the case, but a smaller amount of extra carry weight can now also be gained when selecting Health or Magicka.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="legendary-skills">Legendary Skills&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The ability to reset skills to “Legendary” was added in vanilla Skyrim to prevent the player from “wasting” skill gain on skills they already brought to 100. This essentially removes the level cap (previously at 81) as you can simply reset and re-level any skill, and continue progressing toward another level-up. Unfortunately, making a skill “Legendary” would reset to skill level 15 which means losing access to all parks and having to start all over again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With Cheshyr’s Uncapper, you will be able to reset a skill from skill level 90 onward. This gives you the choice to skip the grind from skill level 90 to 100 and reset immediately at the cost of quick access to the “capstone perk” which becomes available at skill level 100. Thankfully, if you choose to reset the skill, you will be set back to skill level 40 instead of 15, meaning you can retake essential perks immediately.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The UI will not display it before level 100 is reached in a skill, but you can reset it to Legendary as soon as you are at level 90.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="perks">Perks&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The perk trees in TPF are from SimonMagus’ &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/30191">&lt;strong>Adamant - A Perk Overhaul&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> which Cheshyr’s Skyrim Uncapper preset was specifically made for. This allows for a good synergy between the two. Adamant also requires Simon’s &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/27839">&lt;strong>Mysticism - A Magic Overhaul&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> which similarly allows the two mods to play off each other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Some key features:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Spells and related perks finally scale and remain strong options in the late game which is not the case in vanilla.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Shouts will also scale in strength based on your Speech level and advance your Speech skill.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support for unarmed combat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Perks that activate when wearing a “full set” of heavy or light armor work with only three pieces worn (no need for a helmet).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Adamant perks are “vanilla plus”, meaning they feel very similar to the original perk trees, but with noticeably less filler character. Capstone perks (those unlocked at skill level 100) are powerful and worthy of the grind unlike many of the lackluster vanilla equivalents. For example, in vanilla the capstone perk for Archery gives you a 15% chance to paralyze your target. Adamant’s Archery capstone perk with guaranteed critical damage to enemies at full health is a great deal stronger and more rewarding in comparison.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Please refer to the mod page for up-to-date perk descriptions.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="respeccing">Respeccing&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you want are unhappy with how you spent your perk points, there are multiple ways to reset them:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Make a skill legendary:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Upon reaching skill level 90 in any skill, you can make it &amp;ldquo;Legendary&amp;rdquo;, resetting it to level 40 and refunding all perk points. See Legendary Skills section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Complete the Dragonborn DLC main quest:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of the main quest on Solstheim, you have the option to refund all perks from any of your perk trees at the cost of one Dragon Soul per tree.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Buy a Draught of Fate Unwound:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This potion was added by &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/1960">&lt;strong>Ish&amp;rsquo;s Respec Mod&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> and will automatically refund all your perks upon consuming it. Other than a relatively high price, there are no downsides associated with it. It was added primarily to allow users to refund perks before updating the perk overhaul, Adamant, as otherwise points spent on removed perks might be lost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can buy a Draught of Fate Unwound at &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Elgrim%27s_Elixirs">&lt;strong>Elgrim&amp;rsquo;s Elixirs&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> in Riften.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="combat--difficulty">Combat &amp;amp; Difficulty&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Combat in TPF is affected primarily by &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/34549">&lt;strong>Blade and Blunt - A Combat Overhaul&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> which adds complexity to the vanilla hack-and-slash system. It adds emphasis on Stamina management and movement. Please refer to the mod page for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The optional Timed Block module is not featured in TPF. A well-timed bash to interrupt an enemy&amp;rsquo;s attack will have a similar effect of opening them up for a counter-attack while presenting a higher risk if mistimed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="difficulty-modifiers">Difficulty Modifiers&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In vanilla Skyrim, there are multiple difficulty levels ranging from Novice to Legendary. They primarily increase incoming damage while decreasing outgoing damage which in practice means that enemies become &amp;ldquo;bullet sponges&amp;rdquo; (taking very little damage) while the player is progressively more vulnerable. You can checke the vanilla modifiers &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Damage#Difficulty_Level">&lt;strong>here&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Blade and Blunt adjusts the difficulty modifiers, slightly increasing incoming damage. With those changes, combat will feel noticably more difficult than vanilla to the point where you may be one-shot by certain enemy types. Facing mages without any magic resist enchantments or potions can be perilous.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In TPF 4.7, I elected to revert to the vanilla damage modifiers. &lt;strong>If you would like more difficult combat&lt;/strong>, rather than increasing the difficulty ingame, you should &lt;strong>uncheck the Blade and Blunt - Vanilla Difficulty Modifiers mod under COMBAT &amp;amp; ENCOUNTERS&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The reason why I reverted to the vanilla modifiers in TPF is because occasionally users complain about tough combat while absolutely refusing to lower the game difficulty out of a misplaced sense of pride. TPF combat with Blade and Blunt (and some other mods) is more challenging than vanilla, and you should never feel bad for lowering the difficulty in order to have fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="smithing">Smithing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Adamant’s smithing perk tree fixes inconsistencies with the vanilla one where perks were split into light and heavy. This makes sense for armors where that distinction is made but not for weapons. A heavy armor character may still want to upgrade their Orcish sword to Glass which requires a lower skill level than Ebony but it does require the other “light” perks which the heavy armor character likely didn’t take. It’s inconvenient to say the least.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adamant fixes this by splitting the smithing perk tree into a crafting and a tempering branch. Progressing the crafting branch will unlock recipes for stronger equipment tiers while the tempering branch will improve your ability to upgrade your equipment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Equipment can now be improved up to 10 times.&lt;/strong> Every time to you sharpen a weapon at the grindstone or improve an armor piece at the workbench, its damage or armor rating are increased by exactly one point. The name of the item is updated to reflect the tempering tier. For instance, an iron sword upgraded four times would display in the inventory as &amp;ldquo;Iron Sword +4&amp;rdquo;. Unlike with the vanilla tier names (Fine, Superior, Exquisite, etc), you can immediately tell how many times you already improved the item and how many times you can still do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="arcane-blacksmith">Arcane Blacksmith&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In vanilla, a fairly advanced perk is required to temper enchanted equipment: &lt;strong>Arcane Blacksmith&lt;/strong>. The perk is unlocked at skill level 60.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Adamant, this perk was removed from the perk tree and given to the player automatically. The idea is that being forced to decide between a weak but enchanted weapon or a strong but unenchanted item is not particularly fun. Instead you will now be able to temper your enchanted gear in order to make it useable at your level without having to level to Smithing 60 and invest in a perk.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="other-changes">Other Changes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Crafting recipes were adjusted for better consistency by &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/47115">&lt;strong>Simple Smithing Overhaul&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can now craft Lockpicks and Torches as well as most faction gear after completing the appropriate quests.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DLC-added recipes unlock after completing the intro quest to the respective DLC (no clutter at level 1).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dwemer scrap recipes do not appear in the smelter menu unless you have at least one piece of it in your inventory.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="horses">Horses&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While TPF does not feature a full horse overhaul, there are three mods that make horses a great deal more convenient. For one, they will no longer attack and instead flee upon entering combat. The five buyable horses as well as the unique Frost were also set to Essential so they will not die if they do get hit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrim/mods/91395">&lt;strong>Irondusk&amp;rsquo;s Saddlebags&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, you can store up to 500 weight units of items on your horse. Simply interact with your horse while sneaking and you will be prompted to open your saddle bags. The mod also adds a Horse Whistle power with which you can command your horse to wait or follow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you have a &lt;strong>follower&lt;/strong>, you will be able to buy a horse for them at any stable which they will then call and ride whenever you mount up on your own horse.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="shrines-and-divines">Shrines and Divines&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Upon interacting with a shrine, you will receive a blessing from the associated divine that lasts for 8 hours. You can only have one blessing at a time. These are vanilla features, but they were tweaked by &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/30191">&lt;strong>Adamant&amp;rsquo;s Shrines and Amulets&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> addon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The addon also tweaks the effects from amulets of the divines to match the updated shrine blessings. In vanilla, shrine and amulet effects were identical except for Julianos and Kynareth whose amulets increased Magicka and Stamina by 10 points respectively while the shrines awarded +25 points. Their amulets now also grant +25 points in the respective attribute.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Adamant, a perk from the Restoration tree also directly affects divine blessings. The first level of &lt;strong>Pilgrim&lt;/strong> (Restoration 30) increases the strength of divine blessings received to shrines while the second level (Restoration 60) adds an additional effect to each blessing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please check the section on &lt;strong>Shrines and Amulets&lt;/strong> at the bottom of the Adamant mod page for more information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Shrines no longer cure diseases&lt;/strong> upon interacting with them. You will need to buy, find, or craft a &lt;em>Cure Disease&lt;/em> potion.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="divine-agent">Divine Agent&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There are two unique effects as blessings granted by Mara and Dibella respectively upon completing quests in their honour. These quests are &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:The_Book_of_Love">&lt;strong>The Book of Love&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for Mara (which in TPF occurs only after completing &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Spread_the_Love">&lt;strong>Spread the Love&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>) and &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:The_Heart_of_Dibella">&lt;strong>The Heart of Dibella&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for (you guessed it) Dibella.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Agent of Mara:&lt;/strong> Magic Resistance is increased by 10% (Vanilla: 15%).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Agent of Dibella:&lt;/strong> Skills improve 10% faster (Vanilla: deal more damage to members of the opposite sex).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Tpf: Quests</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/documentation/quests/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/documentation/quests/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are no mods adding new quests in The Phoenix Flavour, but plenty mods that edit existing quests in various ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Many quests no longer start after hearing rumours. You need to pursue those rumours and speak directly with the source.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fewer quests will start automatically and you will be able to turn down more quests.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you refused a quest but change your mind later on, you will usually be able to return to the quest giver and accept it after all.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The level requirements for many quests were adjusted to prevent the player from being unable to complete an objective (due to enemies being due strong in the area).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="quest-requirements">Quest Requirements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With kryptopyr&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/25464">&lt;strong>Timing Is Everything&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, the vanilla level requirements for many quests were adjusted, in most cases they were increased to spread them out further and prevent your Journal from becoming too cluttered early on. All options in the TIE MCM can be adjusted so long as you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet started the respective quest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that the level requirements were adjusted with the slow leveling in mind that Cheshyr&amp;rsquo;s Uncapper preset introduces. EZ (encounter zone) levels for related areas were also taken into account.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some quest have additional conditions that must be met in addition to the specific level.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="dlc-quests">DLC Quests&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Dawnguard_(quest)">&lt;strong>Dawnguard DLC&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>25&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 10&lt;/em>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Build_Your_Own_Home">&lt;strong>Hearthfire DLC&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>20&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 9&lt;/em>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Dragonborn_(quest)">&lt;strong>Dragonborn DLC&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>30&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 25&lt;/em>). Skyrim main quest must be completed&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="daedric-quests">Daedric Quests&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:The_Cursed_Tribe">&lt;strong>The Cursed Tribe&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>24&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 9&lt;/em>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:The_Break_of_Dawn">&lt;strong>The Break of Dawn&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>29&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 12&lt;/em>). Will not start while the player is a vampire as Meridia despises the undead.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:The_Only_Cure">&lt;strong>The Only Cure&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>19&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 12&lt;/em>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:A_Night_To_Remember">&lt;strong>A Night to Remember&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>14&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 14&lt;/em>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Discerning_the_Transmundane">&lt;strong>Discerning the Transmundane&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>19&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 15&lt;/em>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:The_Whispering_Door">&lt;strong>The Whispering Door&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>27&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 20&lt;/em>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Pieces_of_the_Past">&lt;strong>Pieces of the Past&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>22&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 20&lt;/em>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Boethiah%27s_Calling">&lt;strong>Boethiah&amp;rsquo;s Calling&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>30&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 30&lt;/em>).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="miscellaneous-quests">Miscellaneous Quests&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:The_Wolf_Queen_Awakened">&lt;strong>The Wolf Queen Awakened&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>24&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 10&lt;/em>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Unfathomable_Depths">&lt;strong>Unfathomable Depths&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>19&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 14&lt;/em>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Grimsever%27s_Return">&lt;strong>Grimsever&amp;rsquo;s Return&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>19&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 14&lt;/em>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Kill_the_Giant_(Jarl)">&lt;strong>Kill the Giant&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>24&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 22&lt;/em>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Dungeon_Delving_(Jarl_-_Hagravens)">&lt;strong>Dungeon Delving&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>14&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 20&lt;/em>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Kill_the_Vampire">&lt;strong>Kill the Vampire&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>24&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 10&lt;/em>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Deathbrand_(quest)">&lt;strong>Deathbrand&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>34&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 36&lt;/em>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:The_Ebony_Warrior">&lt;strong>The Ebony Warrior&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Requires level &lt;strong>65&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>vanilla: 80&lt;/em>).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="radiant-requirements">Radiant Requirements&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Parapets&amp;rsquo; mod &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/45427">&lt;strong>Radiant Requirements&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> adds an MCM which allows you to tweak level requirements for various types of radiant quests. Without these requirements, you may for example receive a quest from the Companions in the early game tasking you to clear out a vampire lair. Unfortunately this may be impossible to complete for a low level Companion recruit as &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/33487">&lt;strong>Arena - An Encounter Zone Overhaul&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> increases the min levels for vampire lairs to &lt;strong>25&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Radiant Requirements, the required level for each encounter type was set one below their respective Arena encounter zone min level to avoid being underleveled for radiant quests:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dragon Lair:&lt;/strong> Requires level &lt;strong>24&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Draugr Crypt:&lt;/strong> Requires level &lt;strong>9&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Forsworn Camp:&lt;/strong> Requires level &lt;strong>14&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Hagraven Nest:&lt;/strong> Requires level &lt;strong>14&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Vampire Lair:&lt;/strong> Requires level &lt;strong>24&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Werewolf Lair:&lt;/strong> Requires level &lt;strong>24&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dragon Priest Lair:&lt;/strong> Requires level &lt;strong>29&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Falmer Hive:&lt;/strong> Requires level &lt;strong>19&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Giant Camp:&lt;/strong> Requires level &lt;strong>24&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Spriggan Grove:&lt;/strong> Requires level &lt;strong>9&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Warlock Lair&lt;/strong>: Requires level &lt;strong>14&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="faction-quests">Faction Quests&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To trigger the major faction quests, you now need to speak to the primary quest giver directly. Rumors or guard comments will no longer give you quest log entries.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Speak with &lt;strong>Aventus&lt;/strong> in Windhelm to start the &lt;strong>Dark Brotherhood&lt;/strong> quest line.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Speak with &lt;strong>Viarmo&lt;/strong> in Solitude to start the &lt;strong>Bard&amp;rsquo;s College&lt;/strong> quest line.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Speak with &lt;strong>Faralda&lt;/strong> in Winterhold to start the &lt;strong>College of Winterhold&lt;/strong> quest line.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Speak with &lt;strong>Kodlak&lt;/strong> in Whiterun to start the &lt;strong>Companions&lt;/strong> quest line.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Speak with &lt;strong>Brynjolf&lt;/strong> in Riften to start the &lt;strong>Thieves Guild&lt;/strong> quest line.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Speak with &lt;strong>Ulfric&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Galmar&lt;/strong> in Windhelm to start the &lt;strong>Stormcloak&lt;/strong> quest line.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Speak with &lt;strong>Tullius&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Rikke&lt;/strong> in Solitude to start the &lt;strong>Imperials&lt;/strong> quest line.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>You can check your current &lt;strong>rank&lt;/strong> in any given faction in the &lt;strong>Factions&lt;/strong> MCM (&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/17924">&lt;strong>Viewable Faction Ranks&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-companions">The Companions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Upon approaching Whiterun, you can observe a group of Companions fighting a giant out in the fields. The fight will last longer than in vanilla, to give you a better chance to join the fight. When speaking with Aela afterward, you will have a new, more polite response option. The quest &amp;ldquo;Join the Companions&amp;rdquo; will not be added to your journal. To join the Companions, go to Jorrvaskr in Whiterun and speak with Kodlak.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You need to complete 2 radiant quests (vanilla: 1) before the first big quest, &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Proving_Honor">&lt;strong>Proving Honor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, triggers. The potential radiant quests no longer include &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Hired_Muscle">&lt;strong>Hired Muscle&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> which would have sent you to beat up a random person. If you are given the &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Trouble_in_Skyrim">&lt;strong>Trouble in Skyrim&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> radiant quest, the type of enemy you are sent to kill will be determined by your level, ensuring that you will be able to complete the quest. For the Proving Honor quest itself, Aela may become your Shield-Sibling instead of Farkas in which case she will accompany you to Dustman&amp;rsquo;s Cairn.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After Proving Honor, you will have to complete 3 more radiant quests (vanilla: 2) before the next big quest &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:The_Silver_Hand">&lt;strong>The Silver Hand&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> fires. At the start of that quest, you will meet some members of the Circle who offer to turn you into a werewolf. If you refuse, they will return to their normal lives during the day and return to the Underforge at night. You may seek them out again if you changed your mind, or continue to do radiant quests without progressing through the main quest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you did choose to become a werewolf and completed The Silver Hand, you will have to do another 2 radiant quests (same amount as in vanilla) before &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Blood%27s_Honor">&lt;strong>Blood&amp;rsquo;s Honor&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> begins. The final three Companion quests after that occur back to back without requiring additional radiant quests to be completed and were not edited by mods in TPF.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="college-of-winterhold">College of Winterhold&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>TPF features almost the full suite of SomethingObscure&amp;rsquo;s College of Winterhold mods (except for the college overhaul itself) with Parapets&amp;rsquo; tweaks. The introduction at the gates and Faralda&amp;rsquo;s test were adjusted: For example, the Dragonborn may now pass after demonstrating the power of their voice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Check the mod pages for &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/22184">&lt;strong>Improved College Entry&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/22653">&lt;strong>Misc College of Winterhold Tweaks&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> for details on the many other adjustments that they made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of the quest line, the player will also be able to pass on the title of Arch-Mage to another college member thanks to the mod &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/30887">&lt;strong>Choose Your Own Arch-Mage&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="other-edited-quests">Other Edited Quests&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Thieves Guild Radiant Quests:&lt;/strong> In vanilla you have to complete a ridiculous 125 (!) radiant quests to unlock everything in the Thieves Guild hideout. &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/4382">&lt;strong>No Thieves Guild Grind&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> lowers the requirement to a much more sensible 12 radiant quests.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:The_Book_of_Love">&lt;strong>Book of Love&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: You need to complete &lt;a href="http://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Spread_the_Love">&lt;strong>Spread the Love&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> first (distributing pamphlets about Mara to various people) before you are sent out with the Book of Love quest. In vanilla, the quests are the other way around which doesn&amp;rsquo;t make a lot of sense.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:The_Forgemaster%27s_Fingers">&lt;strong>The Forgemaster&amp;rsquo;s Fingers&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>: Completing this quest is now the only possible way to attain &lt;a href="http://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Orc_Strongholds#Blood-Kin">&lt;strong>Blood-Kin&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> status as a non-Orc player and be allowed to enter the various Orc strongholds in Skyrim.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="paarthurnax">Paarthurnax&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Toward the end of the Skyrim main quest, there is an optional quest during which you will be given a choice by the two factions who helped you against the dragons, the Blades and the Greybeards: whether to kill Paarthurnax or let him live. Unfortunately, there will never be a satisfying conclusion to the quest if you decide against killing him. You will simply be shunned by the Blades and the quest will eventually vanish into the ether upon completing the main quest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are some mods editing this quest, however, they make it so you can have your cake and eat it, too. If you want Paarthurnax to live, the conflicts with &lt;em>both&lt;/em> factions can be simply resolved, completely removing the dilemma.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankfully, there is &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/43766">&lt;strong>The Paarthurnax Resolution&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> which very simply enables you to tell the Blades that no, you will not kill Paarthurnax, thus giving the quest and the decision you are asked to make some weight. They will not be pleased and you will permanently lose their support, but the quest will be marked as completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="lights-out">Lights Out!&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Lights_Out!">&lt;strong>Lights Out!&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> quest in Solitude involves wrecking a ship with very few options to steer (haha) the story in a different direction. With Parapets&amp;rsquo; mod &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/34681">&lt;strong>Save The Icerunner&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, you will have various ways to complete the quest that include sending Jaree-Ra to prison and thus saving the ship from its fate or alternatively following through with the plan but achieving a less depressing ending.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to turn Jaree-Ra in for his crimes, start by talking to Solitude&amp;rsquo;s headsman, Ahtar, and do his quest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information, check out Parapets&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/articles/1882">&lt;strong>detailed walkthrough&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="laid-to-rest">Laid to Rest&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Laid_to_Rest">&lt;strong>Laid to Rest&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> quest in Morthal has been fleshed out greatly by SomethingObscure in &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/28973">&lt;strong>Finding Helgi &amp;hellip; and Laelette - A Laid to Rest Overhaul&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>. It now featurs murder mystery elements, expanded dialogue options, and various flavour edits. These cover the first half of the quest, up until the point where you are sent to clear Morvarth&amp;rsquo;s Lair.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information, check out SomethingObscure&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/articles/1367">&lt;strong>detailed change list&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="stones-of-barenziah">Stones of Barenziah&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Collecting all Stones of Barenziah for the &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:No_Stone_Unturned">&lt;strong>No Stone Unturned&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> quest can be fairly annoying. To make things easier, you have the option to enable quest markers for each of the 24 stones in the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/22395">&lt;strong>Stackable Stones of Barenziah&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> MCM. The markers will only appear once the actual quest has been started which happens after bringing one of the stones to Vex in The Ragged Flaggon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The quest now also requires you to play the DLC as two stones from core Skyrim locations were moved to DLC locations. The stone in Proudspire Manor can now be found in Harkon&amp;rsquo;s room in Volkihar Keep while the stone in Whiterun&amp;rsquo;s Hall of the Dead was placed in Tel Mithryn on Solstheim.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tpf: New Stuff</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/documentation/new-stuff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/documentation/new-stuff/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="new-music">New Music&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While it is highly unusual for me to be adding new content like music tracks, there are some incredibly high quality music mods out there that I loved to play with. If you played a lot of Skyrim, you ARE going to notice the new tracks so they stick out in a sense but not negatively so. I found it rather refreshing to have a new track to listen to every once in a while and none of them stray too far from the atmosphere created by Jeremy Soule&amp;rsquo;s original soundtrack.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All included music mods contain tracks written specifically for Skyrim. I created a playlist which contains all new music tracks added to Skyrim by mods in TPF which you can find &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLj_QypS-aCNNyUBLpYsFAeCJk1Zq0xnmV">here&lt;/a>. Separate links can be found below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Northerner Diaries&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaking of Jeremy Soule, the composer was working on a project called &amp;ldquo;Northerner Symphony&amp;rdquo; shortly after the release of Skyrim which was &lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/499808045/from-the-composer-of-skyrim-soule-symphony-no-1/description">crowdfunded on Kickstarter&lt;/a> but never saw the light of day. However, several years after the original project was supposed to be completed Soule released the &amp;ldquo;Northerner Diaries&amp;rdquo; album containing &amp;ldquo;sketches&amp;rdquo; recorded with a virtual orchestra.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eight tracks from the &amp;ldquo;Northerner Diaries&amp;rdquo; album were added to Skyrim in the mod &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/28108">The Northerner Diaries - Immersive Edition&lt;/a> where author took great care to exclude tracks that didn&amp;rsquo;t fit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can find the full album on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XMAs_C_7Gp4">YouTube&lt;/a>. My personal favourite is the first track, Njól, with that beautiful piano melody.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Musical Lore by Nir Shor&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also included are three tracks by the composer Nir Shor (&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/3200">Musical Lore&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IDeXX8mCngc">Dawns with Fire&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XTHWeX285LU">Stonewall District&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Pe2zVegBT4">Restless Whispers&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>OrganicView&amp;rsquo;s Music&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And finally I am partial to the tracks composed by OrganicView which are split into four mods: one each for exploration, combat, towns, and taverns.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/19401">Still - Skyrim Inspired Music&lt;/a> - listen to all tracks on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/dgfz2ZGEU-E">YouTube&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/30014">Melodies of Civilisation - Skyrim Fan-Made Music&lt;/a> - listen to all tracks on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/OyZrAv14DiM">YouTube&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/16123">Hun Lovaas - Skyrim Fan-Made Combat Music&lt;/a> - listen to all tracks on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/x7Ge_c2Txdw">YouTube&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/36144">Around the Fire - Skyrim Fan-Made Music&lt;/a> - listen to all tracks on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/rBptKrAIOj4">YouTube&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>