<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Phoenix Flavour – Tool Setup</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/</link><description>Recent content in Tool Setup on The Phoenix Flavour</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bg: Tools Folder</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/tools-folder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/tools-folder/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers choosing a folder for modding tools.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> None&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="creating-a-tools-folder">Creating a Tools folder&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I recommend keeping all your modding tools in one &lt;strong>Tools&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When it comes to picking an installation directory for tools, there are two choices:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Inside the MO2 directory: &lt;code>\Mod Organizer 2\Tools\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Inside a new high-level folder: &lt;code>Drive:\Tools\&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The Tools folder must be &lt;u>on the same drive&lt;/u> as Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-success" role="alert">
Create a Tools folder in a location of your choice before going through other Tool Setup modules.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="inside-mo2">Inside MO2&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While tool authors often warn against running tools from within the MO2 directory, Wabbajack list authors have done just that for years with no issues that I am aware of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That being said, keeping tools within your MO2 instance is mostly useful if you want to include them in a Wabbajack list.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="outside-mo2">Outside MO2&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I recommend using a centralised, shared folder for every setup that is not supposed to become a Wabbajack list. Advantages include the ability to share tools between setups and even games (Skyrim SE and Fallout 4 share many tools) and easier updating.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="version-numbers">Version Numbers&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When adding to your Tools folder, I recommend including the version number in the name of the folder to better be able to keep track of which versions you installed. This does require you to update the folder name in the MO2 executable settings after updating a tool, but that becomes routine quickly enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Below, you can see my shared Tools folder:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/my-tools-folder.png" alt="My Tools Folder">&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="if-you-are-currently-working-through-the-core-module-continue-with-sseeditbgtool-setupsseedit">If you are currently working through the Core Module, continue with &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/sseedit/">SSEEdit&lt;/a>.&lt;/h4></description></item><item><title>Bg: Bethesda Archive Extractor</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/bae/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/bae/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers the installation of Bethesda Archive Extractor.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/tools-folder/">Tools Folder&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="about-bethesda-archive-extractor">About Bethesda Archive Extractor&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Bethesda Archive Extractor&lt;/strong> is a lovely tool for viewing and (selectively) extracting BSAs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/974?tab=files">Bethesda Archive Extractor&lt;/a> from its Nexus page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a folder called &lt;strong>Bethesda Archive Extractor&lt;/strong> in your &lt;strong>Modding Tools&lt;/strong> directory.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract the downloaded archive into the new folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="set-as-default">Set as default&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Setting BAE as the default app for opening BSAs will allow you to quickly peek inside archives the same way you can inside 7ZIP or RAR files. This can be immensely convenient for asset management.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To set it as the default app, we need a BSA.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Navigate to your &lt;strong>data folder&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click any BSA and select &lt;strong>Open with&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check the &lt;strong>Always use this app to open.bsa files&lt;/strong> option.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>More apps&lt;/strong>, scroll all the way to the bottom, and click &lt;strong>Look for another app on this PC&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>\Modding Tools\Bethesda Archive Extractor\&lt;/code> and double-click &lt;strong>BAE.exe&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This will immediately open whichever BSA you picked in BAE. As you can see, there is a filtering option and you have the ability to browse and unpack files. See &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/extracting-bsas/#via-bethesda-archive-extractor">Extracting BSAs&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;strong>Tip:&lt;/strong> Double-clicking a BSA in Mod Organizer 2 will open MO2&amp;rsquo;s own preview window which also has a filtering option and useful information about compression. However, if you right-click the BSA and select &lt;strong>Open&lt;/strong>, it will use the default app (BAE) instead.
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Bg: BethINI</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/bethini/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/bethini/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers the installation of BethINI.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/tools-folder/">Tools Folder&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="about-bethini">About BethINI&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>BethINI is a tool for modifying the vanilla INI files: Skyrim.ini, SkyrimPrefs.ini, and (optionally) SkyrimCustom.ini. Its optimised settings are based on extensive testing by DoubleYouC, a member of the STEP team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The tool can be used for Oblivion and Fallout (NV/3/4) in addition to Skyrim (LE/SE).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>BethINI is available on the Nexus. Do not try to run it through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/4875">BethINI&lt;/a> from its Nexus page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a folder called &lt;strong>BethINI&lt;/strong> in your &lt;strong>Modding Tools&lt;/strong> directory.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract the downloaded archive into the new folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Always remember to &lt;u>close&lt;/u> Mod Organizer 2 before running BethINI.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="configuration">Configuration&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Please consult the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/ini-config/">INI Files&lt;/a> page for more information and instructions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bg: Cathedral Assets Optimizer</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/cao/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/cao/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers the installation of Cathedral Assets Optimizer and setting up a profile to create BSAs.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/tools-folder/">Tools Folder&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="about-cathedral-assets-optimizer">About Cathedral Assets Optimizer&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Cathedral Assets Optimizer (CAO)&lt;/strong> is an all-in-one asset processing tool for Skyrim (SE/LE) and Fallout (NV/3/4). Among other things, it can create and unpack archives, optimise meshes, and perform some basic texture modifications like changing the resolution, creating mipmaps, or compressing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While CAO is meant to modify mods, it should target separate modding folders as opposed to being run on an entire setup. Do not try to launch it through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download the latest stable version from the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/23316?tab=files">Nexus page&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a folder called &lt;strong>Cathedral Assets Optimizer&lt;/strong> in your &lt;strong>Tools&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract the downloaded archive into the new folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For quick access, I recommend &lt;strong>pinning&lt;/strong> the executable to your taskbar.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="antivirus-exclusions">Antivirus Exclusions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The author of CAO recommends creating an exclusion in &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/add-an-exclusion-to-windows-security-811816c0-4dfd-af4a-47e4-c301afe13b26">Windows Defender&lt;/a> to prevent slowdowns (follow link for instructions).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Third-party antivirus software, if you have any installed, may also cause CAO to not work properly (or at all) and you may need to create an exclusion for them as well. You should be able to find instructions by googling for the name of the antivirus and &amp;ldquo;exclusion&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="create-bsa-profile">Create BSA Profile&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
This step is optional.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>As CAO has many different use cases for various games, it helps to create custom profiles for them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently, I use the tool largely for creating BSAs while resorting to Octagon and SSE NIF Optimizer for texture and mesh processing, respectively. In the following, I will show you how to set up a profile for creating BSAs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="create-new-profile">Create new profile&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open &lt;strong>Cathedral Assets Optimizer&lt;/strong> and make sure the &lt;strong>SSE&lt;/strong> profile is selected at the top.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check the option to &lt;strong>Show advanced settings&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/cao/cao-sse-profile.png" alt="CAO SSE Profile">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>New&lt;/strong> button to create a new profile and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to the infobox.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter &lt;strong>SSE - Create BSA&lt;/strong> as the name.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Confirm to use the &lt;strong>SSE&lt;/strong> profile as the basis.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>(When creating a new profile, I recommend using the premade profile for the same game as the base.)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="bsa-tab">BSA Tab&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>BSA&lt;/strong> tab, you will want to configure the options as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/cao/bsa-profile-bsa.png" alt="BSA Tab BSA">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Delete source files&lt;/strong> is an option I tend to keep disabled just in case I messed something up. If I did, it is easier to delete the BSA and run CAO again than having to first unpack the created archive(s). Of course, this means you will always have to manually delete the source files after BSA creation. Decide for yourself whether or not to disable this option.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Maximum Size:&lt;/strong> &lt;u>I recommend not changing this option.&lt;/u> BSA maximum sizes differ by game (see below) so if you use CAO for different games (i.e., Skyrim SE and Fallout 4), make sure to use separate Create BSA profiles for them.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
If memory serves, Skyrim LE BSAs were limited to 2GB while Fallout 4 BSAs can be up to 4GB in size. I am not sure about Skyrim SE BSAs but keeping them below 2GB in size seems like the safest option. None of the vanilla BSAs exceed 2GB.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="other-tabs">Other Tabs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I recommend leaving everything &lt;u>disabled&lt;/u> in the other three tabs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is because I find it to be generally easier to do one &lt;em>thing&lt;/em> at a time. Check through one mod at a time, run it through Octagon if you find that its textures are missing mipmaps, then run it through CAO to pack it into a BSA if necessary. Being very deliberate about how you modify files and going step-by-step can help avoid seemingly inexplicable issues down the line.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bg: Crash Log Tools</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/crash-log-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/crash-log-tools/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers the Mod Organizer 2 plugin Crash Log Tools.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/mo2/">Mod Organizer 2&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="about-crash-log-tools">About Crash Log Tools&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Crash Log Tools&lt;/strong> is a plugin for Mod Organizer 2 which adds the ability to view crash logs generated by &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/recommended-mods/utilities-frameworks/#crash-logger">Crash Logger&lt;/a> directly through the MO2 UI. This is far more convenient than navigating manually to where the logs are saved under &lt;code>\Documents\My Games\Skyrim Special Edition\SKSE\&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, the plugin will attempt to label known addresses in crash logs which may help with tracking down the cause of a crash.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Crash Log Tools is available on the Nexus.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download the latest version of &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/66743?tab=files">Crash Log Tools&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/mo2-plugins-folder-shortcut.png">shortcut&lt;/a> to open the MO2 Plugins folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Close Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract the downloaded archive into the &lt;strong>plugins&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Re-open Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>You should now be able to access &lt;strong>Crash Log Tools&lt;/strong> through the Toolbar:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/crash-log-tools/crash-log-tools-mo2.png" alt="Crash Log Tools">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bg: Creation Kit</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/creation-kit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/creation-kit/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers the installation of the Creation Kit.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/root-builder">Root Builder&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Creation Kit&lt;/strong> is Bethesda&amp;rsquo;s official modding tool which used to be available only from their proprietary launcher, but has since (mercifully) returned to Steam.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Search for the &lt;strong>Creation Kit&lt;/strong> in the Steam store.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure to select the &lt;strong>Skyrim Special Edition: Creation Kit&lt;/strong> and install it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>As the location, choose the same &lt;strong>Steam Library&lt;/strong> as for the game itself. The Creation Kit will be installed into the &lt;strong>root folder&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="downgrading">Downgrading&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Using the Creation Kit is a much better experience with &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/20061">SSE CreationKit Fixes&lt;/a>. Unfortunately, the original mod is not updated for the newest version of the Creation Kit (the same issues of version dependency affect it that also affect the base game and SKSE). An unofficial &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/71371">update&lt;/a> to the mod seems to have a few issues currently.*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=2>**I was warned about this by friends who use the Creation Kit far more than I ever have and I am deferring to their expertise on the matter.*&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To be on the safe side, I recommend rolling back to a previous version of the CK which is compatible with the original CK Fixes.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download halgari&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/67096?tab=files">Creation Kit Downgrade Patcher&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Save the executable into your &lt;strong>root folder&lt;/strong> and run it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Start Patching&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The process should only take a second. Close the window when it&amp;rsquo;s done and delete the patcher.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/ck/downgrade-ck.png" alt="Downgrade CK">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="mo2-integration">MO2 Integration&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="steam-appid">Steam AppID&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Close and re-open &lt;strong>Mod Organizer 2&lt;/strong>. It should automatically recognise the presence of the Creation Kit which should appear in the executables drop-down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you can run the CK through MO2, you need to manually add its Steam App ID in the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/creation-kit/mo2-executables-settings.png">executable settings&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/ck/ck-steam-appid.png" alt="CK MO2 Shortcut">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="mo2-shortcut">MO2 Shortcut&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I recommend selecting the Creation Kit from the drop-down and adding a shortcut to the &lt;strong>Toolbar&lt;/strong> for quick access.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/ck/ck-mo2-shortcut.png" alt="CK MO2 Shortcut">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="root-builder">Root Builder&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Currently, Root Builder&amp;rsquo;s cache does not include the CK files which means it will remove them from the root folder when an application is run through Mod Organizer 2. We need to rebuild the cache to solve this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>CreationKitPrefs.ini&lt;/strong> will be generated upon launching the Creation Kit and it may change if you change settings in the CK. To prevent Root Builder from tripping up over those changes, I recommend adding it to the list of excluded files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/ck/root-builder-clear-cache.png" alt="Root Builder Clear Cache">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ck-source-files">CK Source Files&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Upon launching the CK for the first time, we will get a message to unpack the &lt;strong>Scripts.zip&lt;/strong> in the data folder installed during the CK installation. The archive contains the source files (.psc) for all vanilla scripts (.pex) which are necessary for modifying and recompiling scripts. We can manage these source files using Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the process of moving the source files into a mod folder, we will also adjust the folder structure. As it happens, the folder structure for scripts and source files changed for some unfathomable reason: In &lt;strong>SLE&lt;/strong>, the file path was &lt;code>\Data\Scripts\Source\&lt;/code> whereas in &lt;strong>SSE&lt;/strong> it became &lt;code>\Data\Source\Scripts\&lt;/code>. Not only does the SLE file path make more sense (all vanilla and mod-added scripts are located under &lt;code>\Data\Scripts\&lt;/code>), but most source files packaged with mods also still use the old file path.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Tweaked Creation Kit INI&lt;/strong> that we are going to install soon will revert the file path for source files back to the SLE one. All that remains is manually fixing the folder structure for the source files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, we need to set up a new mod folder with the correct file path:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Create a new empty mod in MO2 and name it &lt;strong>Creation Kit - Source&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click the new mod and select &lt;strong>Open in Explorer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a new folder called &lt;strong>Scripts&lt;/strong> and open it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a new folder called &lt;strong>Source&lt;/strong> and open it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>(These are, in fact, data folder files, so no root folder file path is necessary.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next, we need to extract the source files:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>\Steam\steamapps\common\Skyrim Special Edition\Data\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the &lt;strong>Scripts.zip&lt;/strong> in the data folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>\Source\Scripts\&lt;/code> within the archive.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select all &lt;strong>.psc&lt;/strong> files (CTRL + A) and extract them into the new folder structure:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>\Mod Organizer 2\mods\Creation Kit - Source\Scripts\Source\&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Back in Mod Organizer 2, refresh the interface (F5) and move the new mod right below the Creation Kit separator.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="dialogueviews">DialogueViews&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For the &lt;strong>DialogueViews&lt;/strong> folder, we can take an easier route.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Create a new empty mod in MO2 and name it &lt;strong>Creation Kit - DialogueViews&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click the new mod and select &lt;strong>Open in Explorer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to the top level within the &lt;strong>Scripts.zip&lt;/strong> archive.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract the &lt;strong>DialogueViews&lt;/strong> folder into the new mod folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Back in Mod Organizer 2, refresh the interface (F5) and move the new mod below &lt;strong>Creation Kit - Source&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click it and select &lt;strong>Ignore missing data&lt;/strong> (the XMLs are not recognised as mod files).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Finally, delete the &lt;strong>Scripts.zip&lt;/strong> from your data folder. Otherwise, the CK will keep bugging you about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
You can leave the two new &amp;ldquo;mods&amp;rdquo; disabled in MO2 until you specifically need them.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="improving-the-ck">Improving the CK&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are multiple additional improvements we can install for the Creation Kit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, create a new separator in Mod Organizer 2 called &lt;strong>Creation Kit&lt;/strong>. I recommend placing it between the base game files (official master files and creations) and your other mods.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="tweaked-custom-ini">Tweaked Custom INI&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Like the base game, the Creation Kit comes with a set of two INI files, &lt;strong>CreationKit.ini&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>CreationKitPrefs.ini&lt;/strong>, that can be modified directly or overwritten using a &lt;strong>CreationKitCustom.ini&lt;/strong>. We will go with the latter option and grab a preconfigured custom INI from the Nexus.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download and install &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/19817?tab=files">Tweaked Creation Kit INI&lt;/a> (click &lt;strong>Mod Manager Download&lt;/strong>).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Mod Organizer 2 will not complain about installing the file as a mod because it recognises the INI as a valid format.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, the custom INI, like all other CK files, needs to go into the root folder. We need to adjust the folder structure for &lt;strong>Root Builder&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Right-click the new mod and select &lt;strong>Open in Explorer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a new folder and name it &lt;strong>Root&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drag the &lt;strong>CreationKitCustom.ini&lt;/strong> into the &lt;strong>Root&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Refresh MO2 with F5 and right-click the mod &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Ignore missing data&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move the mod below &lt;strong>Creation Kit - DialogueViews&lt;/strong> and activate it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="creation-kit-fixes">Creation Kit Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We previously downgraded the Creation Kit to a previous version to be able to use this mod.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/20061?tab=files">SSE CreationKit Fixes&lt;/a>.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Grab the &lt;strong>CK64Fixes Release 3.2&lt;/strong> main file and save it to your usual directory.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Install the mod through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Once again, we need to adjust the folder structure for &lt;strong>Root Builder&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Right-click the mod and select &lt;strong>Open in Explorer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a new folder and name it &lt;strong>Root&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drag all files &lt;u>except&lt;/u> for the &lt;strong>meta.ini&lt;/strong> into the new folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Refresh MO2 with F5, right-click the mod, and select &lt;strong>Ignore missing data&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move the mod below &lt;strong>Tweaked Creation Kit INI&lt;/strong> and activate it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
If the wrong version number bothers you like it bothers me, you can double-click the mod and change it to &lt;strong>3.2&lt;/strong> in the &lt;strong>Nexus&lt;/strong> tab.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="separate-ck-exe">Separate CK EXE&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
This step is optional. It is intended for Wabbajack curators of lists that require the CK.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Having a downgraded version of the Creation Kit executable in your root folder should not be an issue for 99% of users. It is, however, an issue for me because I am a Wabbajack list curator and users of my lists would be required to downgrade the CK as a prerequisite for several of my lists if I left the exe there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To prevent this, I am moving it into Mod Organizer 2 and verify files to restore the current version in the root folder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/ck/separate-ck-exe.png" alt="Separate EXE">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="test-run">Test Run&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With everything installed, give the &lt;strong>Creation Kit&lt;/strong> a test run. Launch it through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to CK Fixes, starting up the CK should only take a few seconds. If it loads up the main window and if the &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> is empty after quitting again, everything was set up correctly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bg: Mod Organizer 2</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/mo2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/mo2/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers the installation and basic configuration of Mod Organizer 2.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/clean-install/">Clean Install&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Mod Organizer 2 has two prerequisites.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While you may already have them install, I recommend (re)installing them to be sure:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download &lt;a href="https://dotnet.microsoft.com/download/dotnet-framework/thank-you/net48-web-installer">.NET Framework 4.8&lt;/a> and follow the instructions in the installer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Download the &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/vs/16/release/vc_redist.x64.exe">Microsoft Visual C++ Redistributable&lt;/a> and follow the instructions in the installer.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>To finalise the installation you may be required to restart your PC.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="downloading-mo2">Downloading MO2&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Mod Organizer 2 is hosted on the Nexus and on Github.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/6194">Mod Organizer 2&lt;/a> Nexus page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Switch to the &lt;strong>Files&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>Manual Download&lt;/strong> button for &lt;strong>Mod Organizer 2&lt;/strong> under &lt;strong>Main Files&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you do not have &lt;strong>Nexus Premium&lt;/strong>, you will need to click &lt;strong>Download&lt;/strong> again on the next page after a brief countdown.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/mo2/download-mo2.png" alt="Download MO2">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="installing-mo2">Installing MO2&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Save the downloaded executable to a convenient location and double-click it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If there is a Windows warning, click &lt;strong>More Info&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Run anyway&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
Worried about catching a virus? Read about the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/knowledge-base/nexus-virus-check/">Nexus Virus Check&lt;/a>.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="installer-configuration">Installer Configuration&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the MO2 installer, accept the license agreement and proceed to the next page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will be asked where to install Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Once again, &lt;strong>selecting an SSD or NVME is highly recommended&lt;/strong> as it will improve load times and in-game performance.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>The MO2 folder will contain all your mods&lt;/strong> which may add up to &lt;strong>100GB&lt;/strong> and more.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For now, make sure you have &lt;u>at least 50GB of free space&lt;/u> on whichever hard drive you choose. That will be sufficient to get started.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/mo2/mo2-installation-directory.png" alt="MO2 Installation Directory">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the rest of the installer, you can simply keep clicking &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong> to install the tool with all components into your chosen directory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click &lt;strong>Finish&lt;/strong> once all files have been extracted. Mod Organizer 2 will be launched automatically so you can proceed with the next step.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="instance-setup">Instance Setup&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After the initial installation process, the &lt;strong>Instance Manager&lt;/strong> will open where we will create a new &lt;strong>portable instance&lt;/strong>. These are self-contained and allow you to run as many copies of Mod Organizer 2 as you like, for various games or different setups.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(I personally run five or more instances at any given time, for both Skyrim SE and Fallout 4, none of which interfere with each other.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click the &lt;strong>Create new instance&lt;/strong> button to proceed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/mo2/mo2-new-instance.png" alt="MO2 New Instance">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong> in the configuration window.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select &lt;strong>Create a portable instance&lt;/strong> on the next page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>On the next page in the configuration wizard, select &lt;strong>Skyrim Special Edition&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong> again on the following page to confirm using your MO2 installation folder for all sub directories.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Connect to Nexus&lt;/strong>* and switch to the browser to authorise MO2 to connect your account.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In the MO2 installer, you should see: &lt;strong>Linked with Nexus successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Proceed to the next step and click &lt;strong>Finish&lt;/strong> to finalise your new MO2 instance.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;font size="2">**If you are not prompted to connect MO2 to the Nexus, you have likely already done this for a previous MO2 installation.*&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="first-launch">First Launch&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Mod Organizer 2 should launch automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong> when asked to see the tutorial.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We will go over the various parts of MO2 in this guide.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If asked whether MO2 should handle NXM links, click &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This allows automatic downloads from the Nexus through MO2.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Before we do anything else, let&amp;rsquo;s disable the log at the bottom. We are not going to need it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/mo2/disable-mo2-log.png" alt="disable mo2 log">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also recommend right-clicking the MO2 icon on your taskbar and &lt;strong>pinning&lt;/strong> it for quick access.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="mo2-settings">MO2 Settings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Open the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> by clicking the first icon on the right in the toolbar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/mo2/mo2-open-settings.png" alt="MO2 Open Settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="settings-general">Settings: General&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Under &lt;strong>Download List&lt;/strong>, I highly recommend checking &lt;strong>Show meta information&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Compact list&lt;/strong>. This will affect the Downloads tab in the right pane of MO2 where all downloaded files will appear. As the list grows, a more compact view with information about the file version and type will become invaluable.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Check out the &lt;a href="https://i.imgur.com/BW4F4tD.png">default settings&lt;/a> versus the &lt;a href="https://i.imgur.com/eNnzd6p.png">compact settings&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I personally do not use the &lt;strong>Hide downloads after installation&lt;/strong> option. Of course, the list of downloads in my MO2 setups is hundreds of files long, and yes, hiding files after installing them would keep the downloads tab clean. All hidden mods can quickly be made visible again by ticking the &lt;strong>Hidden files&lt;/strong> box at the bottom of the &lt;strong>Downloads&lt;/strong> tab, and individual files can be hidden and unhidden at will. Personally, I prefer the simplicity of simply leaving everything visible and using the search bar to find what I am looking for. Once you start installing mods, you should make your own choice.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="settings-themes">Settings: Themes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While I personally prefer light mode in the majority of my apps and programs, I realise that my opinion is rather unpopular. Under &lt;strong>Style&lt;/strong>, you can try out various other themes. If you are looking for a simple dark theme, I recommend the &lt;strong>1809 Dark Mode&lt;/strong> option for now. It is similar to the default light theme and will make following along with my screenshots easier.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Make sure to restart MO2 after changing the theme.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Colors&lt;/strong> section below affects the colors in which mods and separators will light up when highlighting them. I strongly suggest not tampering with them until you have a proper understanding of mod order and asset conflicts.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="settings-paths">Settings: Paths&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Since we set up MO2 as a portable instance, all file paths to the various directories are currently within the MO2 installation itself: &lt;code>/%BASE_DIR%/&lt;/code>, the base directory. We already discussed the potential size of the mods folder, which can easily exceed 50GB, but should nevertheless be located on a fast drive, ideally an SSD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, &lt;strong>the downloaded archives from which the mods are installed do NOT need to be on an SSD&lt;/strong>. They are only required for the initial installation and merely serve as backups afterwards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keeping the archives is nevertheless recommended as you may want to reinstall a mod later on to choose different options if they come with an installer, or simply to restore it to the vanilla state if you modified it. Hence, I recommend changing the &lt;strong>Downloads&lt;/strong> directory to a different drive. Pick the hard drive with the most amount of space; any HDD will do.*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;font size="2">**It should be noted that keeping downloaded archives on a faster drive may speed up mod installation, including for Wabbajack list. Nevertheless, SSD / NVME space is precious and I personally prefer to use it for more mods or other games.*&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
This is a recommendation, not a requirement. Manage your disk space as you see fit.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/mo2/mo2-downloads-folder.png" alt="Downloads Folder">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bsa-extractor-2">BSA Extractor 2&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Some of MO2&amp;rsquo;s extra functionality is implemented via pre-installed plugins. Unfortunately, the default BSA extraction plugin may currently corrupt textures when used to extract BSAs, so I recommend installing a fixed version.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Close Mod Organizer 2 (always do this before installing plugins).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Download &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/92044?tab=files">BSA Extractor 2&lt;/a> from the Nexus page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract the &lt;strong>plugins&lt;/strong> folder to &lt;code>\Mod Organizer 2\&lt;/code> (the MO2 root folder).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Confirm to merge with existing &lt;strong>plugins&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="configuration">Configuration&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>By default, BSA Extractor 2 will ask about unpacking the archive every time you install a mod that contains a BSA. This can be disabled (and I recommend doing so).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Restart Mod Organizer 2 and go into the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/mo2/mo2-open-settings.png">settings&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Switch to the &lt;strong>Plugins&lt;/strong> tab and select &lt;strong>BSA Extractor 2&lt;/strong> near the bottom of the list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Double-click &lt;strong>enable_install_dialogue&lt;/strong> and set it to &lt;strong>False&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/mo2/configure-bsa-extractor-2.png" alt="Settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="new-profile">New Profile&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of MO2&amp;rsquo;s many lovely features is the ability to create an indefinite amount of self-contained &lt;strong>profiles&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every profile has its own:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Load order&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mod Order&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Saves (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>INI Files (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="create-new-profile">Create New Profile&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Open the MO2 profiles settings by clicking the ID card icon in the &lt;strong>Toolbar&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/mo2/mo2-profiles-settings.png" alt="MO2 Profiles Settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click the &lt;strong>Create&lt;/strong> button and enter a name for your profile.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I recommend naming your profile after the central mod or theme of the modlist you intend to build, like &lt;strong>Legacy of the Dragonborn&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>SimonRim&lt;/strong>, or &lt;strong>Survival&lt;/strong>. There is also nothing stopping you from simply calling it &lt;strong>Modded&lt;/strong> as opposed to the unmodded &lt;strong>Default&lt;/strong> profile.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
If you are following the &lt;strong>Core Module&lt;/strong>, you can name it that.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Whether you check the &lt;strong>Default Game INI Settings&lt;/strong> is really up to you. I recommend leaving the option enabled and running BethINI later on to modify your INIs.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to create your new profile.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I recommend enabling the &lt;strong>Use profile-specific Save Games&lt;/strong> option at the bottom (while having your new profile selected).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Select&lt;/strong> to quickly switch to your new profile.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="interface-adjustments">Interface Adjustments&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Below are my personal adjustments to the Mod Organizer 2 interface. Take them as suggestions (or ignore them).&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
If you are following the &lt;strong>Core Module&lt;/strong> please do copy at least my changes to the categories displayed in the left pane.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="the-right-pane">The Right Pane&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>right pane&lt;/em> of Mod Organizer 2 features a number of tabs, none of which require much space to properly display. I typically reduce it take up about a fourth of the entire interface, dragging around the columns in the &lt;strong>Plugins&lt;/strong> tab so that all options are comfortably displayed without wasting too much space on the &lt;strong>Mod Index&lt;/strong> column.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-left-pane">The Left Pane&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>left pane&lt;/em> of Mod Organizer 2 displays the &lt;strong>mod order&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clicking on the sorting columns above the mod order, you will see a number of options.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/mo2/adjust-mo2-columns.png" alt="MO Columns">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>✔️&lt;strong>Conflicts:&lt;/strong> Displays little icons to show overwrites.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>✔️&lt;strong>Flags:&lt;/strong> Not necessary, but recommended. Shows if notes are appended to a mod.*&lt;/li>
&lt;li>✔️&lt;strong>Content:&lt;/strong> Very helpful because it shows you which types of assets are contained in a mod.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>❌&lt;strong>Category:&lt;/strong> Uses Nexus categories by default. Separators are better for sorting.**&lt;/li>
&lt;li>❌&lt;strong>Nexus ID:&lt;/strong> The ID of the respective mod (which is the combination of numbers at the end of its URL).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>✔️&lt;strong>Source Game:&lt;/strong> Useful when mixing Skyrim LE and Skyrim SE mods which is not very common anymore.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>✔️&lt;strong>Version:&lt;/strong> Helpful for tracking updates.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>❌&lt;strong>Installation:&lt;/strong> Displays the date of installation. Not sure what you would need this for.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>✔️&lt;strong>Priority:&lt;/strong> Shows the position in the mod order. Does not hurt to leave on.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>✔️&lt;strong>Notes:&lt;/strong> See short notes at a glance. (AKA my favourite thing about MO2.)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=2>**There are also flags to remind you of endorsing mods and to show the tracking status. The tracking feature never worked properly for me and the only mods I have not endorsed are my own, so I typically disable both &lt;strong>Endorsement Integration&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Tracking Integration&lt;/strong> in the MO2 settings (Nexus tab). Disable these features or leave them active, it is up to you.*&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=2>***You can also create a set of custom categories (instructions forthcoming).*&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="my-mo2-layout">My MO2 Layout&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After some re-arranging of columns and ratios, this is what my MO2 instance (on a 1080p monitor) looks like:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/mo2/mo2-my-layout.png">Click here to view the picture in full size.&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/mo2/mo2-my-layout.png" alt="My Layout">&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="if-you-are-currently-working-through-the-core-module-return-to-step-1bgcore-modulestep1ui-overview">If you are currently working through the Core Module, return to &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/core-module/step1/#ui-overview">Step 1&lt;/a>.&lt;/h4></description></item><item><title>Bg: SSE NIF Optimizer</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/sse-nif-optimizer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/sse-nif-optimizer/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers the installation of SSE NIF Optimizer.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/tools-folder/">Tools Folder&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="about-sse-nif-optimizer">About SSE NIF Optimizer&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SSE NIF Optimizer&lt;/strong> is a mesh optimisation tool that is especially useful for porting mods.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download the latest stable version from the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/4089/?tab=files">Nexus page&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a folder called &lt;strong>SSE NIF Optimizer&lt;/strong> in your &lt;strong>Modding Tools&lt;/strong> directory.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract the downloaded archive into the new folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Bg: SSEEdit</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/sseedit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/sseedit/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers the installation of SSEEdit for Mod Organizer 2.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/mo2/">Mod Organizer 2&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/tools-folder/">Tools Folder&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="about-sseedit">About SSEEdit&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>xEdit is a tool for viewing and modifying Bethesda plugins.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Versions of it exist for most Bethesda games, not only Skyrim SE, and its name changes depending on the game: For example, xEdit for Skyrim SE is known as &lt;strong>SSEEdit&lt;/strong> while xEdit for Skyrim LE was called &lt;strong>TES5Edit&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>FO4Edit&lt;/strong> is used in Fallout 4 modding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you have installed the programme, you can use it for any game that is supported by either changing the name of the executable, or starting it with a specific argument such as &lt;code>-sse&lt;/code> for Skyrim SE.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
You will see the tool referred to as SSEEdit or xEdit interchangeably. Both mean the same thing.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SSEEdit is hosted on the Nexus:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download the latest version of &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/164">SSEEdit&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a folder called &lt;strong>SSEEdit&lt;/strong> in your &lt;strong>Tools&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract the downloaded archive into the new folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="mo2-integration">MO2 Integration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Plugins are data folder files which means &lt;strong>SSEEdit&lt;/strong> must be run through Mod Organizer 2 in order to access its virtual data folder.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In Mod Organizer 2, click the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/mo2-executables-settings.png">gears icon&lt;/a> in the Toolbar to open the &lt;strong>Executables&lt;/strong> settings.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the small blue plus icon and select &lt;strong>Add from file&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>\Tools\SSEEdit\&lt;/code> and double-click &lt;strong>SSEEdit.exe&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to add the executable to Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/add-sseedit-to-mo2.png" alt="Add xEdit">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="toolbar">Toolbar&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>SSEEdit should be automatically selected in the executables drop-down (if not, select it).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For maximum convenience, I recommend clicking the &lt;strong>Shortcut&lt;/strong> drop-down below the &lt;strong>Run&lt;/strong> button and selecting &lt;strong>Toolbar and Menu&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Click the SSEEdit icon in the Toolbar has the same effect as selecting it from the executables drop-down and clicking &lt;strong>Run&lt;/strong>, except it is obviously faster. I recommend doing this for every tool.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/mo2-xedit-shortcut.png" alt="Shortcut">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="sseedit-ref-cache">SSEEdit Ref Cache&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When loading up your plugins in SSEEdit, the tool will spend a considerable amount of time processing all records. To cut down on the loading time, SSEEdit creates a &lt;strong>ref cache&lt;/strong> (caching reference records for each plugin) which reduces the startup time from several minutes to twenty seconds or less.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I recommend saving the cache files into the &lt;strong>SSEEdit&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In Mod Organizer 2, click the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/mo2-executables-settings.png">gears icon&lt;/a> in the Toolbar to open the &lt;strong>Executables&lt;/strong> settings.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select &lt;strong>SSEEdit&lt;/strong> in the list of executables.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Arguments&lt;/strong> add the &lt;code>-c:&amp;quot;filepath&amp;quot;&lt;/code> argument along with the file path.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Your file path will, of course, depend on where you installed SSEEdit. It must end in a &lt;code>\cache\&lt;/code> folder. This folder does not have to exist, it will be created by SSEEdit upon generating the first cache files. &lt;u>The file path must end on a trailing backslash.&lt;/u>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For me, the argument looks like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>-c:&amp;quot;G:\Modding Tools\SSEEdit\cache\&amp;quot;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/sseedit-refcache-argument.png" alt="xEdit Refcache">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="generating-ref-cache">Generating Ref Cache&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Launch SSEEdit through Mod Organizer 2 and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> in the &lt;strong>Plugin Selection Window&lt;/strong> to load all your currently installed plugins. This will take a moment as SSEEdit builds the cache files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can quit once the log at the bottom returns &lt;code>Background loader: finished&lt;/code> or once you are prompted to activate ModGroups.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Check your &lt;code>\Tools\SSEEdit\cache\&lt;/code> folder to make sure the files were saved to the correct location.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="disable-warning">Disable Warning&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Please skip this if you are currently following the Core Module.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>To prevent the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/core-module/sseedit-warning-window.png">warning window&lt;/a> from appearing when trying to modify a record, add the following argument to the executables settings in Mod Organizer 2:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>-IKnowWhatImDoing
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/sseedit/disable-warning-window.png" alt="Disable Warning Window">&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="if-you-are-currently-working-through-the-core-module-return-to-step-3bgcore-modulestep3the-unwanted-effects-book">If you are currently working through the Core Module, return to &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/core-module/step3/#the-unwanted-effects-book">Step 3&lt;/a>.&lt;/h4></description></item><item><title>Bg: Synthesis</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/synthesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/synthesis/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers the installation of Synthesis.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/mo2/">Mod Organizer 2&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/tools-folder/">Tools Folder&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="about-synthesis">About Synthesis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Synthesis&lt;/strong> is an automated patching tool that is capable of processing a large amount of plugins in a short period of time and apply changes from one or more pre-made patchers. More and more mods are coming to rely on Synthesis-generated patches to ensure easy compatibility and integration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Synthesis can be downloaded from Github.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download the &lt;strong>Synthesis.zip&lt;/strong> from the latest version on &lt;a href="https://github.com/Mutagen-Modding/Synthesis/releases">Github&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a folder called &lt;strong>Synthesis&lt;/strong> in your &lt;strong>Modding Tools&lt;/strong> directory.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract the downloaded archive into the new folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Remember that you can add the version number to the folder name.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="mo2-integration">MO2 Integration&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Synthesis requires access to the data folder and must therefore be launched through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/mo2-executables-settings.png">executable settings&lt;/a> in Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the small blue plus icon and select &lt;strong>Add from file&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to your &lt;strong>Synthesis&lt;/strong> folder and double-click &lt;strong>Synthesis.exe&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to add the executable to Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I recommend selecting the tool from the drop-down and adding a shortcut to the Toolbar for quick access.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/synthesis/synthesis-shortcut.png" alt="Synthesis Shortcut">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="synthesis-profile">Synthesis Profile&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Upon launching Synthesis for the first time you will be able to configure it for your version of Skyrim.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Select &lt;strong>Skyrim&lt;/strong> and then &lt;strong>Skyrim Special Edition&lt;/strong> (Steam) or &lt;strong>Skyrim Special Edition GOG&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>It is possible to create multiple profiles for different games, all using the same instance of Synthesis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tool-setup/synthesis/synthesis-configuration.png" alt="Synthesis Shortcut">&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>