<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Phoenix Flavour – New Game</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/</link><description>Recent content in New Game on The Phoenix Flavour</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Skyrim-Se: Final Adjustments</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/final-adjustments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/final-adjustments/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="timing">Timing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before starting a new playthrough, there are some considerations to make:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Has there been a Skyrim update recently? If so, SKSE64, the mods depending on it as well as the guide may receive an update very soon, and it may be worth it to wait a week or two for everything to catch up before diving into the game.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Also keep an eye on our Discord server in case a major update for the guide or a mod is imminent.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="mo2-notifications">MO2 Notifications&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before jumping into the game, go through one final checkup. In Mod Organizer 2, go to &lt;strong>View&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Notifications&lt;/strong>. If this is greyed out, you are good to go! If not there are multiple different warnings you might encounter:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Missing Masters:&lt;/strong> One of your plugins is missing a master file. It is marked with an exclamation mark in your load order. This is most likely due to skipping a mod that was not optional or selecting the wrong option in a FOMOD installer. Go back to the mod’s instructions in the guide and double-check everything.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Form 43 Plugin:&lt;/strong> You forgot to re-save one or several plugins in the Creation Kit. Re-save them now.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Outdated SKSE Plugin:&lt;/strong> Check the plugin&amp;rsquo;s mod page to see if there is a new version.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Files in your overwrite:&lt;/strong> This one is not particularly problematic and you can probably ignore it for the time being.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="new-profile">New Profile&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In Mod Organizer 2, open the &lt;strong>Profiles&lt;/strong> window (Tools &amp;gt; Profiles or CTRL + P).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select your &lt;strong>The Phoenix Flavour&lt;/strong> and click &lt;strong>Copy&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter a name for the new profile. Here are some suggestions:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>The Phoenix Flavour - {name of the character for the playthrough}&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>The Phoenix Flavour - {name of the build or playstyle for the playthrough}&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>The Phoenix Flavour - Playthrough 1&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> and select your new profile in the list. Make sure both options at the bottom are checked:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use profile-specific Save Games&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use profile-specific Game INI Files&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Close the &lt;strong>Profiles&lt;/strong> window.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Switch to your new profile in Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="new-game">New Game&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run &lt;strong>SKSE&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select &lt;strong>NEW&lt;/strong> in the Skyrim main menu to start your playthrough.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Skyrim-Se: Mod Configuration</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/mod-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/mod-configuration/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="initialisation">Initialisation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After starting a new game, you will be dropped in the &lt;strong>Alternate Start - Live Another Life&lt;/strong> cell where you can customise your character, then configure your mods before you actually start playing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stand still and wait until all messages have run through in the upper left corner (check the screenshot below). Then hit &lt;strong>ESCAPE&lt;/strong> and create a manual save before you continue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to SkyUI, it is possible to configure most mods directly through their Mod Configuration Menu – or MCM for short – which you can access through the main menu. Hit &lt;strong>ESCAPE&lt;/strong> and select &lt;strong>MCM&lt;/strong>. See recommended changes for most of the guide’s MCMs below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/initialisation-complete.jpg" alt="Initialisation complete">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-matter-of-time">A Matter of Time&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can either:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Configure the clock widget to your liking.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Untick &lt;strong>Show&lt;/strong> for each module in the &lt;strong>General&lt;/strong> tab to hide it until you are ready to customise it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you installed my personal AMOT preset, go to &lt;strong>Presets&lt;/strong> and click &lt;strong>Load user settings&lt;/strong> (see screenshot).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/load-amot-preset.jpg" alt="Load AMOT Preset">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="all-geared-up-derivative">All Geared Up Derivative&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In the &lt;strong>NPC&lt;/strong> tab, check &lt;strong>Enable Weapons&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/allgud-mcm.jpg" alt="AllGUD MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cathedral-weathers">Cathedral Weathers&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Uncheck &lt;strong>Configuration Spell&lt;/strong> (redundant when you can access the MCM).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/cw-mcm.jpg" alt="Cathedral Weathers MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="follower-framework">Follower Framework&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="npc-behaviour-optional">NPC Behaviour (optional)&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Turn on the following options under &lt;strong>Activity&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Sandboxing&lt;/strong>:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ignore Special Furniture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stop During Player Dialogue&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Only Sandbox In Town&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>My preferences. Optional.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="horse-whistle-optional">Horse Whistle (optional)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>NFF features a bindable horse whistle hotkey which you can press to call the last ridden mount to your location.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Activity&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Player Horse&lt;/strong>, bind a &lt;strong>Call Player Horse Hotkey&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="regard-system-optional">Regard System (optional)&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Disable the Regard system under &lt;strong>Gameplay&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Regard&lt;/strong>:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow Regard: Off&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is completely optional. The feature works perfectly fine, I just don&amp;rsquo;t like it personally.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="additional-powers-optional">Additional Powers (optional)&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Disable the &lt;strong>Command Followers&lt;/strong> ability under &lt;strong>System&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Casted Abilities&lt;/strong> to further de-clutter your Powers menu.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can define a hotkey for it above.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="consoleutil-support">ConsoleUtil Support&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>System&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Core&lt;/strong>, check the &lt;strong>Enable ConsoleUtil&lt;/strong> option.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="genuinely-intelligent-soul-traps">Genuinely Intelligent Soul Traps&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This mod - while focusing on bug fixes and soul gem multithreading - comes with some very nifty level requirement options. If you like, you can set level requirements for each of its special features as well as the for capturing of each tier of souls. Toggle and adjust this system in the &lt;strong>Leveling&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="growl---werebeasts-of-skyrim">Growl - Werebeasts of Skyrim&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Toggle on &lt;strong>Invulnerable During Transformation&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="immersive-hud">Immersive HUD&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="toggle-settings-optional">Toggle Settings (optional)&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can change the hotkey to display the HUD here.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I recommend turning on the &lt;strong>Key Press Toggles&lt;/strong> option but that is a personal preference.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="link-widgets-optional">Link Widgets (optional)&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Check &lt;strong>Link ALL SkyUI Widgets&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you installed A Matter of Time, this will link the clock widget to the HUD so that it gets toggled alongside the other components (such as the compass).&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/ihud-link-widgets.jpg" alt="iHUD link widgets">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="morehud">moreHUD&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In the &lt;strong>Enemy&amp;rsquo;s Level&lt;/strong> tab, uncheck the following options:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Show Magicka Meter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Show Stamina Meter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>These only clutter up the interface in my opinion. You can also disable Health numbers if you like.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/morehud-mcm.jpg" alt="moreHUD MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="realistic-water-two">Realistic Water Two&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Mod Options&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Blacksmith Forge Water&lt;/strong>, toggle the following options:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Kynesgrove&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rorikstead&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/rwt-mcm.jpg" alt="Realistic Water 2 MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="storm-lightning">Storm Lightning&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By default, the lightning storms with this mod are pretty intense. I&amp;rsquo;d suggest changing to a different preset (above &amp;ldquo;default&amp;rdquo;) to tone them down a little.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Presets&lt;/strong>, select any one on one of the options.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/storm-lightning-mcm.jpg" alt="Storm Lightning MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="timing-is-everything">Timing Is Everything&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Another large MCM, and one you should configure now, at the start of the game as it affects many quests that start very early on in Vanilla. You can either leave the settings on default, tweak them, or apply my preset that we installed earlier. You can also apply my preset and &lt;em>then&lt;/em> tweak whatever you dislike about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To apply the custom preset, do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Go to the &lt;strong>Extra Options&lt;/strong> tab in the Timing Is Everything MCM.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Load Preset&lt;/strong> and confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You will be asked not the leave the MCM before the process is complete. Confirm again.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All values will be updated. Click &lt;strong>Okay&lt;/strong> to close the final message box.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/tie-mcm.jpg" alt="TIE MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="trade--barter">Trade &amp;amp; Barter&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Barter Rates&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong>, check the &lt;strong>Modify Barter Settings&lt;/strong> box.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/trade-barter-mcm.jpg" alt="Trade and Barter MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="wonders-of-weather">Wonders of Weather&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is optional and personal preference.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Rainsplashes&lt;/strong>, set &lt;strong>Level&lt;/strong> to &lt;strong>Disabled&lt;/strong> to turn the effect off.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/wow-mcm.jpg" alt="Wonders of Weather MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="starting-the-game">Starting the game&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once you’re done configuring everything, save the game manually. Then talk to the Statue of Mara, select one of the options and interact with the bed in the corner to truly start your playthrough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As for the options, going with the &lt;code>vanilla start&lt;/code> is entirely possible but you can also choose the &lt;code>I am camping in the woods&lt;/code> option for a faster alternative that drops you in the same region but skips the cart ride and execution sequence. It is NOT recommended that you choose the &lt;code>vampire lair&lt;/code> option as that has been known to cause issues with vampire mods.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For the best experience &lt;strong>I recommend the vanilla start&lt;/strong> as it is impossible to balance all the various options that AS LAL offers.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Good luck and have fun!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/select-game-start.jpg" alt="Select game start">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skyrim-Se: ENB Tweaks</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/enb-tweaks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/enb-tweaks/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Open the ENB GUI by pressing Shift+Enter. You can tweak the presets there and most changes will be visible instantly. Click &lt;strong>SAVE CONFIGURATION&lt;/strong> after changing anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This page currently only includes instructions for Serio&amp;rsquo;s ENB. If you are using another preset (such as the default Rudy ENB), you can still tweak anything you like through the UI, but there are no instructions / recommendations at this time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="serios-enb">Serio&amp;rsquo;s ENB&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="detailed-shadows">Detailed Shadows&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I personally find grass to be better looking when the Detailed Shadows effect is disabled. You can do so by going to &lt;strong>EFFECT&lt;/strong> and unchecking &lt;strong>EnableDetailedShadows&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim/new-game/serios-disable-detailed-shadows.png" alt="Serios Disable Detailed Shadows">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="interior-brightness">Interior Brightness&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Serio&amp;rsquo;s was tuned for the ELE lighting overhaul and will be too bright for Luminosity. Go into an interior and tweak the following values:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>[ENVIRONMENT]
AmbientLightingIntensityInteriorDay=0.85
AmbientLightingIntensityInteriorNight=0.75
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The exact values are merely suggestions. Feel free to tweak the brightness as you see fit.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim/new-game/serios-tweak-interior-lighting.png" alt="Serios Interior Brightness">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="luts">LUTs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>LUTs are different color grading tables that change the overall tone of the image. Serio&amp;rsquo;s features eleven different LUTs that you can enable and switch between at will.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open the &lt;strong>ENBEFFECTPOSTPASS.FX&lt;/strong> section in the right pane.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check the &lt;strong>Enable LUT&lt;/strong> option and cycle through the available LUTs under &lt;strong>Gradient Tint Type&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>By customising the &lt;strong>Gradient Tint Amount&lt;/strong>, you can tweak how strong the color adjustment should be.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In the PostPassFX section you can also toggle other effects such as Film Grain, Vignette, and Letterbox.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim/new-game/serios-switch-lut.png" alt="Serios LUT">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skyrim-Se: Gameplay Guide</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/gameplay-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/gameplay-guide/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="perks--leveling">Perks &amp;amp; Leveling&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/2783">Mysticism - A Magic Overhaul&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/30191">Adamant - A Perk Overhaul&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/35366">Skyrim Uncapper - Adamant Arena&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="vanilla-vs-tpf">Vanilla vs TPF&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In vanilla Skyrim, you gain levels by increasing your proficiency in various skills. Proficiency is gained by using said skills. For example, if you sneak a lot around enemies, your sneak skill will eventually increase which will also give you progress toward the next level up. Leveling up, you will then be given a choice between the three main attributes (Health, Stamina, Magicka) as well as a perk point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In TPF, there are some differences you ought to be aware of. The rate at which you gain skill progression, level-ups, perk points, and attributes is controlled by Cheshyr’s Skyrim Uncapper preset for Adamant and Arena, our perk and encounter zone overhaul respectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, the preset rebalances crafting skill gains so that they don’t contribute as much to your overall progression toward the next level. Otherwise, due to the abundance of crafting material, you would be able to quickly grind out a few levels with crafting alone. If skill gain for crafting professions was simply slowed down, increasing your skill level for access to higher level perks would become a frustrating grind.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="leveling-up">Leveling Up&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The speed at which you level up (which is determined by how quickly you gain skill proficiency and how much the gained skill proficiency progresses you toward the next level-up) is adjusted for different periods in your playthrough. Leveling slows down after level 10 and picks up again after level 30, meaning you will spend a good deal more time between level 10 and 30 than in vanilla.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This makes sense in multiple ways: The leveled loot and encounter system of vanilla Skyrim will progress you very quickly through loot tiers and enemy variants until it spits you out north of level 35, having seen the vast majority of what the game has to offer. By slowing down progression before that happens, you spend more time in that part of the game where leveling up constantly unlocks new enemy types and gear variants as you play. This part of the game is also where many of the unique quests unlock, Daedric quests among them. You’ll be collecting your first artifacts and catch glimpses of what you will become.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to keep your own progression interesting, you will be awarded a bonus perk point at regular intervals when leveling up.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="legendary-skills">Legendary Skills&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Legendary Skills
The ability to reset skills to “Legendary” was added in vanilla Skyrim to prevent the player from “wasting” skill gain on skills they already brought to 100. This essentially removes any level cap (like the previous 81) as you can simply reset and re-level any skill, and continue progressing toward another level-up. Unfortunately, making a skill “Legendary” would reset to skill level 15 which means you have to start all over again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With Cheshyr’s Uncapper, you will be able to reset a skill from skill level 90 onward. This gives you the choice to skip the grind from skill level 90 to 100 and reset immediately at the cost of quicker access to the “capstone perk” which becomes available at skill level 100. Thankfully, if you choose to reset the skill, you will be set back to skill level 40 instead of 15, meaning you can retake essential perks immediately.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="perks">Perks&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The perk trees in TPF are from SimonMagus’ overhaul Adamant for which Cheshyr’s Skyrim Uncapper preset was made specifically. This allows for some neat synergy between the two. Adamant also requires Simon’s magic overhaul Mysticism which similarly allows the two mods to play off each other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Some key features:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Spells and related perks finally scale and remain strong options in the late game which is not the case in vanilla.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Shouts will also scale in strength based on your Speech level and advance your Speech skill.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support for unarmed combat (see Combat Styles section).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Perks that activate when wearing a “full set” of heavy or light armor work with only three pieces worn (no need for a helmet).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Adamant perks are “vanilla plus”, meaning they feel very similar to the original perk trees but with noticeably less filler character. Capstone perks (those unlocked at skill level 100) are powerful and worthy of the grind unlike many of the lackluster vanilla equivalents. For example, in vanilla the capstone perk for Archery gives you a 15% chance to paralyze your target. Adamant’s Archery capstone perk with guaranteed critical damage to enemies at full health is a great deal stronger and more rewarding in comparison.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Not-quite-removed perks:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Several vanilla perks were removed from their perk trees but added to the player automatically. These are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Dual casting for all mage schools.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zooming in with ranged bow and crossbow (Eagle Eye).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ability to improve enchanted equipment (Arcane Blacksmith).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ability to press and hold the attack key while blocking to perform a Power Bash.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>25% greater magnitude for mixed potions (Benefactor).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ability to press the sprint button while sneaking to perform a Silent Roll.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ability to perform a power attack while sprinting with one-handed weapons for additional damage (Critical Charge).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ability to perform a power attack while sprinting with two-handed weapons for additional damage (Greater Critical Charge).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Increased range for summoning and conjuration spells (Summoner).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Increased range for placing rune spells (Rune Master).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="respeccing">Respeccing&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you want are unhappy with how you spent your perk points, there are multiple ways to reset them:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Make a skill legendary:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Upon reaching skill level 90 in any skill, you can make it &amp;ldquo;Legendary&amp;rdquo;, resetting it to level 40 and refunding all perk points. See Legendary Skills section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Complete the Dragonborn DLC main quest:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of the main quest on Solstheim, you have the option to refund all perks from any of your perk trees at the cost of one Dragon Soul per tree.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Buy a Draught of Fate Unwound:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This potion was added by &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/1960?tab=files">Ish&amp;rsquo;s Respec Mod&lt;/a> and will automatically refund all your perks upon consuming it. Other than a relatively high price, there are no downsides associated with it. It was added primarily to allow users to refund perks before updating the perk overhaul, Adamant, as otherwise points spent on removed perks might be lost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can buy a Draught of Fate Unwound at &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Elgrim%27s_Elixirs">Elgrim&amp;rsquo;s Elixirs&lt;/a> in Riften.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="smithing">Smithing&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/30191">Adamant - A Perk Overhaul&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/18994">Weapon Armor Clothing and Clutter Fixes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/43441">Lightweight Smithing Tweaks&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/5013">Craftable Torches&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/3385">Craftable Lockpicks&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="perk-tree">Perk Tree&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Adamant’s smithing perk tree fixes inconsistencies with the vanilla one where perks were split into light and heavy. This makes sense for armors where that distinction is made but not for weapons. A heavy armor character may still want to upgrade their Orcish sword to Glass which requires a lower skill level than Ebony but it does require the other “light” perks which the heavy armor character likely didn’t take. It’s inconvenient to say the least.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adamant fixes this by splitting the smithing perk tree into a crafting and a tempering branch. Progressing the crafting branch will unlock recipes for stronger equipment tiers while the tempering branch will improve your ability to upgrade your equipment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Crafting Perks:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Basic Styles (20):&lt;/strong> Steel, Leather&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Journeyman Styles (40):&lt;/strong> Dwarven, Scaled, Steel Plate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Rare Styles (50):&lt;/strong> Elven, Chitin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Intermediate Styles (60):&lt;/strong> Nordic, Orcish&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Exotic Styles (70):&lt;/strong> Glass, Stalhrim&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Advanced Styles (80):&lt;/strong> Ebony&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mythic Styles (100):&lt;/strong> Daedric, Dragon&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Temper Perks:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Blacksmith (10/50):&lt;/strong> You can temper all items by one/two additional tiers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Armorsmith (30):&lt;/strong> You can temper armor and shields by one additional tier.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Weaponsmith (60):&lt;/strong> You can temper weapons by one additional tier.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Forgemaster (90):&lt;/strong> You can temper all items by one additional tier.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="arcane-blacksmith">Arcane Blacksmith&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In vanilla, a fairly advanced perk is required to temper enchanted equipment: Arcane Blacksmith. The perk is unlocked at skill level 60. In Adamant, this perk was removed from the perk tree and given to the player automatically. The idea is that being forced to decide between a weak but enchanted weapon or a strong unenchanted item is not particularly fun. Instead you will now be able to temper your enchanted gear in order to make it useable at your level without having to level to Smithing 60 and spend a perk.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="silver-and-gold-smithing">Silver and Gold Smithing&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In Lightweight Smithing Tweaks, I added level 30 and 60 as requirements for Silver and Gold smithing respectively. This change was inspired by kryptopyr’s Complete Crafting Overhaul Redone and is supposed to prevent the player from gaining large amounts of money and skill gain early on from smashing together some gems and ingots. In vanilla you can do this as soon as you have the materials, even if you have the smithing skills of a five-year-old.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For consistency, crafting the Gilded Elven Cuirass also requires Smithing 60 as well as one Gold Ingot.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="minor-changes">Minor Changes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can now craft Lockpicks and Torches.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DLC-added recipes unlock after completing the intro quest to the respective DLC.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dwemer scrap recipes don’t appear in the smelter menu unless you have at least one piece of it in your inventory.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="combat-styles">Combat Styles&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/2783">Mysticism - A Magic Overhaul&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/30191">Adamant - A Perk Overhaul&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="sneak-archer">Sneak Archer&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One of the strongest and most beloved vanilla builds remains viable and powerful in TPF. Rejoice, sneak archers!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="unarmed-combat">Unarmed Combat&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>With Adamant, there is finally support for an unarmed playthrough. Three perks in the Light Armor perk boost your unarmed damage specifically. Additionally, unarmed damage scales with your Light Armor skill and you gain Light Armor experience from unarmed fighting.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="companions">Companions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/18076">Nether&amp;rsquo;s Follower Framework&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrim/mods/91395">Irondusk&amp;rsquo;s Saddlebags&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/38348">Misc Tweaks - Better Horses&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="horses">Horses&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While TPF does not feature a full horse overhaul, there are three mods that make horses a great deal more convenient. For one, they will no longer attack and instead flee upon entering combat. The five buyable horses as well as the unique Frost were also set to Essential so they will not die if they do get hit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Saddlebags:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With Irondusk&amp;rsquo;s mod Saddlebags, you will be able to store up to 500 weight units of items on your horse. Simply interact with your horse while crouching and you will be prompted to open your saddle bags.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Horse Whistle:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nether&amp;rsquo;s Follower Framework includes a hotkey for calling your horse which you can define in the NFF MCM.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="shrines-and-divines">Shrines and Divines&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/30191">Adamantine Addons - Shrines and Amulets&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/38348">Misc Tweaks - Shrines Don&amp;rsquo;t Cure Diseases&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="blessings">Blessings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Upon interacting with a shrine, you will receive a blessing from the associated divine that lasts for 8 hours. You can only have one blessing at a time. These blessings were tweaked by Adamant&amp;rsquo;s Shrines and Amulets in TPF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Addon also tweaks the effects from amulets of the divines to match the updated shrine blessings. In vanilla they were identical except for Julianos and Kynareth whose amulets increased Magicka and Stamina by 10 points respectively while the shrines awarded +25 points. Their amulets now also grant +25 points in the respective attribute.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Effects of blessings received at shrines and granted by amulets:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Akatosh:&lt;/strong> Magicka regenerates 25% faster (Vanilla: 10%).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Arkay:&lt;/strong> Health is increased by 25pts (same as vanilla).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dibella:&lt;/strong> Skills improve 10% faster (Vanilla: +10 Persuasion).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Julianos:&lt;/strong> Magicka is increased by 25pts (Shrines same as vanilla, Vanilla Amulets: +10pts).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Kynareth:&lt;/strong> Stamina is increased by 25pts (Shrines same as vanilla, Vanilla Amulets: +10pts).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mara:&lt;/strong> Restoration spells cost 10% less Magicka (Vanilla: +10 Restoration).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Stendarr:&lt;/strong> Stamina regenerates 25% faster (Vanilla: +10 Blocking).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Talos:&lt;/strong> Shout cooldown is reduced by 10% (Vanilla: 20%).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Zenithar:&lt;/strong> Carry weight is increased by 25pts (Vanilla: +10 Barter).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Shrines no longer cure diseases upon interacting with them. You will need to buy, find, or craft a Cure Disease potion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="pilgrim-perk">Pilgrim Perk&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In Adamant, a perk from the Restoration tree directly affects divine blessings. The first level of &lt;strong>Pilgrim&lt;/strong> (Restoration 30) increases the strength of divine blessings received to shrines while the second level (Restoration 60) adds an additional effect to each blessing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Additional effects gained with Pilgrim 2:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Jaws of Akatosh:&lt;/strong> You move 10% faster.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Breath of Arkay:&lt;/strong> You restore 2 health per second.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Beauty of Dibella:&lt;/strong> You deal 10% more damage to humans, elves, and beast races.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Law of Julianos:&lt;/strong> All spells cost 10% less.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Way of Kynareth:&lt;/strong> You spent 25% less Stamina when power attacking or drawing a bow.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Benevolence of Mara:&lt;/strong> Healing spells are 10% stronger.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mercy of Stendarr:&lt;/strong> You deal 10% more damage to the undead.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fist of Talos:&lt;/strong> Your Shouts deal 25% more damage.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Scales of Zenithar:&lt;/strong> Buying and selling prices are 25% better.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="divine-agent">Divine Agent&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There are two unique effects in Skyrim as blessings granted by Mara and Dibella respectively upon completing quests in their honor. These quests are &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:The_Book_of_Love">The Book of Love&lt;/a> for Mara (which in TPF occurs only after completing &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Spread_the_Love">Spread the Love&lt;/a>) and &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:The_Heart_of_Dibella">The Heart of Dibella&lt;/a> for (you guessed it) Dibella.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Agent of Mara:&lt;/strong> Magic Resistance is increased by 10% (Vanilla: 15%).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Agent of Dibella:&lt;/strong> Skills improve 10% faster (Vanilla: deal more damage to members of the opposite sex).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>