<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Phoenix Flavour – New Game</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/</link><description>Recent content in New Game on The Phoenix Flavour</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Skyrim-Se: Final Adjustments</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/final-adjustments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/final-adjustments/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="timing">Timing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before starting a new playthrough, there are some considerations to make:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Has there been a Skyrim update recently? If so, SKSE64, the mods depending on it as well as the guide may receive an update very soon, and it may be worth it to wait a week or two for everything to catch up before diving into the game.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Also keep an eye on our Discord server in case a major update for the guide or a mod is imminent.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="mo2-notifications">MO2 Notifications&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before jumping into the game, go through one final checkup. In Mod Organizer 2, go to &lt;strong>View&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Notifications&lt;/strong>. If this is greyed out, you are good to go! If not there are multiple different warnings you might encounter:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Missing Masters:&lt;/strong> One of your plugins is missing a master file. It is marked with an exclamation mark in your load order. This is most likely due to skipping a mod that was not optional or selecting the wrong option in a FOMOD installer. Go back to the mod’s instructions in the guide and double-check everything.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Form 43 Plugin:&lt;/strong> You forgot to re-save one or several plugins in the Creation Kit. Re-save them now.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Outdated SKSE Plugin:&lt;/strong> Check the plugin&amp;rsquo;s mod page to see if there is a new version.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Files in your overwrite:&lt;/strong> This one is not particularly problematic and you can probably ignore it for the time being.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="new-profile">New Profile&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In Mod Organizer 2, open the &lt;strong>Profiles&lt;/strong> window (Tools &amp;gt; Profiles or CTRL + P).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select your &lt;strong>The Phoenix Flavour&lt;/strong> and click &lt;strong>Copy&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter a name for the new profile. Here are some suggestions:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>The Phoenix Flavour - {name of the character for the playthrough}&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>The Phoenix Flavour - {name of the build or playstyle for the playthrough}&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>The Phoenix Flavour - Playthrough 1&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> and select your new profile in the list. Make sure both options at the bottom are checked:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use profile-specific Save Games&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use profile-specific Game INI Files&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Close the &lt;strong>Profiles&lt;/strong> window.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Switch to your new profile in Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="new-game">New Game&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run &lt;strong>SKSE&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select &lt;strong>NEW&lt;/strong> in the Skyrim main menu to start your playthrough.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Skyrim-Se: Mod Configuration</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/mod-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/mod-configuration/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="initialisation">Initialisation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After starting a new game, you will be dropped in the &lt;strong>Alternate Start - Live Another Life&lt;/strong> cell where you can customise your character, then configure your mods before you actually start playing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stand still and wait until all messages have run through in the upper left corner (check the screenshot below). Then hit &lt;strong>ESCAPE&lt;/strong> and create a manual save before you continue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to SkyUI, it is possible to configure most mods directly through their Mod Configuration Menu – or MCM for short – which you can access through the main menu. Hit &lt;strong>ESCAPE&lt;/strong> and select &lt;strong>MCM&lt;/strong>. See recommended changes for most of the guide’s MCMs below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/initialisation-complete.jpg" alt="Initialisation complete">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-matter-of-time">A Matter of Time&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can either:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Configure the clock widget to your liking.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Untick &lt;strong>Show&lt;/strong> for each module in the &lt;strong>General&lt;/strong> tab to hide it until you are ready to customise it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you installed my personal AMOT preset, go to &lt;strong>Presets&lt;/strong> and click &lt;strong>Load user settings&lt;/strong> (see screenshot).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/load-amot-preset.jpg" alt="Load AMOT Preset">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="all-geared-up-derivative">All Geared Up Derivative&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In the &lt;strong>NPC&lt;/strong> tab, check &lt;strong>Enable Weapons&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/allgud-mcm.jpg" alt="AllGUD MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cathedral-weathers">Cathedral Weathers&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Uncheck &lt;strong>Configuration Spell&lt;/strong> (redundant when you can access the MCM).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/cw-mcm.jpg" alt="Cathedral Weathers MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="diverse-dragons-collection">Diverse Dragons Collection&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open the MCM once, then exit it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>By doing so, the mod will recognise that you have SKSE and SkyUI installed and automatically removes its configuration tool from your Powers menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="follower-framework">Follower Framework&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="npc-behaviour-optional">NPC Behaviour (optional)&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Turn on the following options under &lt;strong>Activity&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Sandboxing&lt;/strong>:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ignore Special Furniture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stop During Player Dialogue&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Only Sandbox In Town&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>My preferences. Optional.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="horse-whistle-optional">Horse Whistle (optional)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>NFF features a bindable horse whistle hotkey which you can press to call the last ridden mount to your location.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Activity&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Player Horse&lt;/strong>, bind a &lt;strong>Call Player Horse Hotkey&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="regard-system-optional">Regard System (optional)&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Disable the Regard system under &lt;strong>Gameplay&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Regard&lt;/strong>:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow Regard: Off&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is completely optional. The feature works perfectly fine, I just don&amp;rsquo;t like it personally.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="additional-powers-optional">Additional Powers (optional)&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Disable the &lt;strong>Command Followers&lt;/strong> ability under &lt;strong>System&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Casted Abilities&lt;/strong> to further de-clutter your Powers menu.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can define a hotkey for it above.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="consoleutil-support">ConsoleUtil Support&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>System&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Core&lt;/strong>, check the &lt;strong>Enable ConsoleUtil&lt;/strong> option.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="genuinely-intelligent-soul-traps">Genuinely Intelligent Soul Traps&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This mod - while focusing on bug fixes and soul gem multithreading - comes with some very nifty level requirement options. If you like, you can set level requirements for each of its special features as well as the for capturing of each tier of souls. Toggle and adjust this system in the &lt;strong>Leveling&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="growl---werebeasts-of-skyrim">Growl - Werebeasts of Skyrim&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Toggle on &lt;strong>Invulnerable During Transformation&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="immersive-hud">Immersive HUD&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="toggle-settings-optional">Toggle Settings (optional)&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can change the hotkey to display the HUD here.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I recommend turning on the &lt;strong>Key Press Toggles&lt;/strong> option but that is a personal preference.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="link-widgets-optional">Link Widgets (optional)&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Check &lt;strong>Link ALL SkyUI Widgets&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you installed A Matter of Time, this will link the clock widget to the HUD so that it gets toggled alongside the other components (such as the compass).&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/ihud-link-widgets.jpg" alt="iHUD link widgets">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="morehud">moreHUD&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In the &lt;strong>Enemy&amp;rsquo;s Level&lt;/strong> tab, uncheck the following options:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Show Magicka Meter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Show Stamina Meter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>These only clutter up the interface in my opinion. You can also disable Health numbers if you like.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/morehud-mcm.jpg" alt="moreHUD MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="realistic-water-two">Realistic Water Two&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Mod Options&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Blacksmith Forge Water&lt;/strong>, toggle the following options:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Kynesgrove&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rorikstead&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/rwt-mcm.jpg" alt="Realistic Water 2 MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="storm-lightning">Storm Lightning&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By default, the lightning storms with this mod are pretty intense. I&amp;rsquo;d suggest changing to a different preset (above &amp;ldquo;default&amp;rdquo;) to tone them down a little.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Presets&lt;/strong>, select any one on one of the options.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/storm-lightning-mcm.jpg" alt="Storm Lightning MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="timing-is-everything">Timing Is Everything&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Another large MCM, and one you should configure now, at the start of the game as it affects many quests that start very early on in Vanilla. You can either leave the settings on default, tweak them, or apply my preset that we installed earlier. You can also apply my preset and &lt;em>then&lt;/em> tweak whatever you dislike about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To apply the custom preset, do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Go to the &lt;strong>Extra Options&lt;/strong> tab in the Timing Is Everything MCM.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Load Preset&lt;/strong> and confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You will be asked not the leave the MCM before the process is complete. Confirm again.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All values will be updated. Click &lt;strong>Okay&lt;/strong> to close the final message box.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/tie-mcm.jpg" alt="TIE MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="trade--barter">Trade &amp;amp; Barter&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Barter Rates&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong>, check the &lt;strong>Modify Barter Settings&lt;/strong> box.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/trade-barter-mcm.jpg" alt="Trade and Barter MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="wonders-of-weather">Wonders of Weather&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is optional and personal preference.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Rainsplashes&lt;/strong>, set &lt;strong>Level&lt;/strong> to &lt;strong>Disabled&lt;/strong> to turn the effect off.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/wow-mcm.jpg" alt="Wonders of Weather MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="starting-the-game">Starting the game&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once you’re done configuring everything, save the game manually. Then talk to the Statue of Mara, select one of the options and interact with the bed in the corner to truly start your playthrough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As for the options, going with the &lt;code>vanilla start&lt;/code> is entirely possible but you can also choose the &lt;code>I am camping in the woods&lt;/code> option for a faster alternative that drops you in the same region but skips the cart ride and execution sequence. It is NOT recommended that you choose the &lt;code>vampire lair&lt;/code> option as that has been known to cause issues with vampire mods.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For the best experience &lt;strong>I recommend the vanilla start&lt;/strong> as it is impossible to balance all the various options that AS LAL offers.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Good luck and have fun!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim-se/new-game/select-game-start.jpg" alt="Select game start">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skyrim-Se: ENB Tweaks</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/enb-tweaks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/new-game/enb-tweaks/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Open the ENB GUI by pressing Shift+Enter. You can tweak the presets there and most changes will be visible instantly. Click &lt;strong>SAVE CONFIGURATION&lt;/strong> after changing anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This page currently only includes instructions for Serio&amp;rsquo;s ENB. If you are using another preset (such as the default Rudy ENB), you can still tweak anything you like through the UI, but there are no instructions / recommendations at this time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="serios-enb">Serio&amp;rsquo;s ENB&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="detailed-shadows">Detailed Shadows&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I personally find grass to be better looking when the Detailed Shadows effect is disabled. You can do so by going to &lt;strong>EFFECT&lt;/strong> and unchecking &lt;strong>EnableDetailedShadows&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim/new-game/serios-disable-detailed-shadows.png" alt="Serios Disable Detailed Shadows">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="interior-brightness">Interior Brightness&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Serio&amp;rsquo;s was tuned for the ELE lighting overhaul and will be too bright for Luminosity. Go into an interior and tweak the following values:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>[ENVIRONMENT]
AmbientLightingIntensityInteriorDay=0.85
AmbientLightingIntensityInteriorNight=0.75
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The exact values are merely suggestions. Feel free to tweak the brightness as you see fit.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim/new-game/serios-tweak-interior-lighting.png" alt="Serios Interior Brightness">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="luts">LUTs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>LUTs are different color grading tables that change the overall tone of the image. Serio&amp;rsquo;s features eleven different LUTs that you can enable and switch between at will.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open the &lt;strong>ENBEFFECTPOSTPASS.FX&lt;/strong> section in the right pane.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check the &lt;strong>Enable LUT&lt;/strong> option and cycle through the available LUTs under &lt;strong>Gradient Tint Type&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>By customising the &lt;strong>Gradient Tint Amount&lt;/strong>, you can tweak how strong the color adjustment should be.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In the PostPassFX section you can also toggle other effects such as Film Grain, Vignette, and Letterbox.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/skyrim/new-game/serios-switch-lut.png" alt="Serios LUT">&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>