<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Phoenix Flavour – Welcome to Paradise</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome to Paradise on The Phoenix Flavour</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fo4: Introduction</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/introduction/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Welcome to Paradise&lt;/strong> (WTP) is a lightweight Wabbajack mod list for Fallout 4. Mods were selected to improve existing parts of the game rather than outright replacing them, although some aspects were edited more heavily than others. The setup was built with gameplay-friendly performance in mind and can run at a stable 60FPS @1440p on reasonably modern hardware.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WTP comes with an extensive documentation (of which you are reading the Introduction right now) and you are expected to read all pages in the &lt;strong>Installation&lt;/strong> section as well as the &lt;strong>Mod Config&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Join us on the official &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/xCPxJFbCTS">Discord server&lt;/a> for support, feedback, and modding discussions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can find a list of all included mods on the &lt;a href="https://loadorderlibrary.com/lists/welcome-to-paradise">Load Order Library&lt;/a> page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support me on &lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/thephoenixflavour">Patreon&lt;/a> or donate via &lt;a href="https://www.paypal.com/paypalme/ThePhoenixFlavour?locale.x=de_DE">PayPal&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Check out DroppedIceCream&amp;rsquo;s amazing showcase for LOTF:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fzO7F6JlIDI" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;h3 id="state-of-the-list">State of the List&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As of the release of &lt;strong>WTP 2.0&lt;/strong> in December 2021, the list is back in active developement.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="about-the-name">About the name&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Up until release 1.3, the list was simply called &amp;ldquo;The Phoenix Flavour for Fallout 4&amp;rdquo; or occasionally just &amp;ldquo;Phoenix Fallout&amp;rdquo;. This was primarily because yours truly lacked the creativity to come up with a proper name in time for the public release. But a little over a month later I figured one out after all:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Olli9bETzXk">Welcome to Paradise&lt;/a> is a beautiful song by &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCioNNjH3S7X8byCjPDEqZkA">Aviators&lt;/a>, an American indie musician whose work I&amp;rsquo;ve loved for many years. The song was written specifically for Fallout 4. He wrote two more Fallout songs, &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/fX5SBZoBiMM">Apocalypse State of Mind&lt;/a> and my personal favourite &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/aZ1pCyFK_kY">Remains&lt;/a> which has enjoyed a permanent spot in many of my playlists for years (unfortunately it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have made for a fancy list name). All three of his Fallout songs are on the album &lt;a href="https://soundoftheaviators.bandcamp.com/album/stargazers">Stargazer&lt;/a> which you can get on Bandcamp!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="wtp-features">WTP Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Moderately improved visuals while retaining a high frame rate with &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/57680">Lightweight Lighting&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/58028">Spectrum ENB&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thanks to the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/46403">Previsibines Repair Pack&lt;/a>, performance exceeds vanilla in some areas, especially when the ENB is disabled.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Custom texture packs made up of handpicked retextures and packaged into BA2s for better performance.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adventure &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/13459">with Dogmeat and one other companion&lt;/a> as originally intended by Bethesda.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Customise your pip-boy with &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/47858">new paint jobs&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/57891">upgrade your vault suit&lt;/a> as you progress through the main quest.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Many custom file edits and patches for a coherent experience.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/3877">VIS-based&lt;/a> sorting overhaul with a custom keywords resource.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Modern interface with (almost) the full &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/48758">FallUI&lt;/a> suite.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Simple implementation of &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/44691">crafting stations&lt;/a> with support for included mods.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Faster workshop system with better object placement and new stuff to build.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Power armors are more rare. Paint and material mods were split.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Custom, high-quality terrain and object LOD generated with xLODGen.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Detailed instructions for the initial setup as well as ingame configuration.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support for one (1) creation: fadingsignal&amp;rsquo;s Modern Military Backpack.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Detailed instructions for enabling ultrawide (21:9) compatibility.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="not-included">Not Included&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you are looking for any of the following features, &lt;strong>Welcome to Paradise&lt;/strong> may not be the mod list for you:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Significant visual changes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Silent protagonist.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>More difficult combat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Survival mode.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nudity or spicy NSFW content.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New quest mods.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mods that vastly differ from the vanilla experience.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Full Creation Club support.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-wabbajack">What is Wabbajack?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Due to the lack of sharing permissions for the vast majority of mods, traditional mod packs do not exist for Bethesda games. With Wabbajack it is possible to recreate one user&amp;rsquo;s mod list on another&amp;rsquo;s computer without redistributing any of the mod files. For more information, please check out the &lt;a href="https://www.wabbajack.org/">Wabbajack website&lt;/a> or join the official &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/wabbajack">Discord server&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Using Wabbajack is much easier than following a manual installation guide but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t absolve you from reading.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="recommended-hardware">Recommended Hardware&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While WTP was made for regular gameplay, a &lt;em>somewhat&lt;/em> modern PC is required to run the setup comfortably. This is due to the bad optimisation of the vanilla game as much as the included mods. Keep in mind that the game will perform much better on 1080p than on 1440p or higher resolutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can see the details of my old setup below, sufficient for playing at 1440p with stable 60FPS. Note that having 6GB VRAM or more is highly recommended for good performance.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Specs&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>CPU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Intel i5 7600K @4.2GHz, hybrid-cooled&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>GPU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EVGA GTX 1070 Founder&amp;rsquo;s Edition (8192MB VRAM)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>RAM&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Corsair Vengeance 16GB DDR4-3200 Memory&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>SSD 1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Samsung EVO 850 Series 256GB SSD (OS)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>SSD 2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Samsung EVO 860 Series 1000GB SSD (Games)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Monitor&lt;/td>
&lt;td>LG 27GL850-B UltraGear 1440p @144Hz&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I have since upgraded to an i7 10700k and a RTX 3080 which are certainly NOT required to play WTP at a stable frame rate.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="get-started-with-the-installationfo4wtpinstallation-now">Get started with the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/installation/">Installation&lt;/a> now.&lt;/h4></description></item><item><title>Fo4: Installation</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/installation/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="requirements">Requirements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While Wabbajack takes care of 99% of the work, there are still some steps that need to be completed by the user. The &lt;strong>Installation&lt;/strong> section will take you through the process from start to finish and you are expected to follow it to the letter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Welcome to Paradise requires:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A copy of &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/sub/199943/">Fallout 4&lt;/a> with all official DLC (Game of the Year Edition) on Steam.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4">Nexus Mods&lt;/a> account, preferably with a Premium subscription.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Around 35.5GB for WTP, 25GB for the downloaded mods, and 34.5GB for the base game.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Grab a glass of Nuka Cola and let&amp;rsquo;s get started.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="mo2-prerequisites">MO2 Prerequisites&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Mod Organizer 2 requires the Microsoft Visual C++ Redistributable and .NET Framework 4.8, two basic packages. Chances are you already have them installed, but please grab the two installers linked below and run them. If the packages are already present on your system, the installers should notify you.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download and install &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/vs/16/release/vc_redist.x64.exe">Visual C++ 2019&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Download and install &lt;a href="https://dotnet.microsoft.com/download/dotnet-framework/thank-you/net48-web-installer">.NET Framework 4.8&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If either of them were missing on your system, they will be installed now. Afterwards, you may be required to restart your PC.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="uninstallation">Uninstallation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In order to ensure that your Fallout 4 installation is pristine and vanilla, we are going to completely re-install the game. This is especially important if you have modded the game previously as left-over files might interfere with your WTP installation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>If you never modded Fallout 4 and/or never installed other Wabbajack lists, you may skip this step.&lt;/strong> However, I still recommend you verify the game files through Steam in that case.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Uninstall &lt;strong>Fallout 4&lt;/strong> through Steam&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to your Steam directory: &lt;code>C:\Program File x86\Steam\steamapps\common\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If there is still a &lt;strong>Fallout 4&lt;/strong> folder, delete it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When uninstalling a game through Steam, only vanilla files are removed. Mod-added files must be deleted manually.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="ini-folder">INI Folder&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>More Fallout-related files are located inside the so-called &lt;strong>INI Folder&lt;/strong> which needs to be cleaned out as well. It contains your savegames as well as the game&amp;rsquo;s INI files and, if you modded Fallout 4 before, F4SE plugin logs.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Navigate to the &lt;strong>INI Folder:&lt;/strong> &lt;code>C:\Users\{Your User Name}\Documents\My Games\Fallout4&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you have an ongoing vanilla playthrough, back up the &lt;strong>Saves&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Delete everything inside the &lt;strong>Fallout4&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="reinstallation">Reinstallation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The reinstallation also serves the purpose of relocating the game files to a better directory. Using UAC protected folders (such as &lt;code>C:\Program Files&lt;/code> or &lt;code>C:\Program Files x86&lt;/code>) for the game or any modding tools has a risk of causing issues down the line. It is best to avoid those folders to begin with. Most Wabbajack list authors, myself included, will not provide support for people that disregard this warning and use UAC protected folders anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that this does not include the Steam client. Most people will have it installed under &lt;code>C:\Program Files x86\Steam&lt;/code> which is completely fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, Fallout 4 and Mod Organizer 2 should be installed on the same hard drive. Ideally that hard drive would be an SSD to reduce loading times and eliminate stuttering.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="steam-library">Steam Library&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In order to prevent some confusion, I will refer to the Library in Steam as the &lt;strong>Game Library&lt;/strong>. It is the second of four items in the top menu in the Steam client and contains a list of all your games.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Steam Library&lt;/strong> on the other hand is a folder on your hard drive into which Steam games are installed. By default, this would be &lt;code>C:\Program Files x86\Steam\steamapps\common\&lt;/code>. Since we do not want to have files inside a UAC protected folder like &lt;code>Program Files x86&lt;/code>, we should not install Fallout 4 in the default directory. A new &lt;strong>Steam Library&lt;/strong> is required.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Unfortunately Steam allows only one Steam Library per hard drive. You can find a workaround &lt;a href="https://github.com/LostDragonist/steam-library-setup-tool/wiki/Usage-Guide">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>If you already have a separate Steam Library outside the UAC protected folders on the drive you want to install Fallout 4 and Mod Organizer 2 on, skip ahead to the next step.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Otherwise follow the instructions below to create a new Steam Library:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open &lt;strong>Steam&lt;/strong> and go into the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the Downloads tab, select &lt;strong>Steam Library Folders&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Add Library Folder&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Point it to a location somewhere outside the UAC protected folders, e.g. &lt;code>G:\Steam Library\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Close all windows when you’re done.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="setting-the-language-to-english">Setting the language to English&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Non-English installations of Fallout 4 are not supported.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Right-click &lt;strong>Fallout 4&lt;/strong> in your Steam games library.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select &lt;strong>Properties&lt;/strong> and switch to the &lt;strong>Langauge&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ensure that the language is set to &lt;strong>English&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/installation/fallout-english.png" alt="Fallout English">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="reinstalling-the-game">Reinstalling the game&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open Steam and go into your &lt;strong>Game Library&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find &lt;strong>Fallout 4&lt;/strong> in the list and click &lt;strong>Install&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>As location, select a &lt;strong>Steam Library&lt;/strong> in a non-UAC protected folder and click &lt;strong>Next&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Wait for Fallout 4 to be downloaded before you proceed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="regenerating-ini-files">Regenerating INI Files&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After re-installing the game, it is important to launch it at least once through Steam so that the registry keys are set up. Otherwise, certain modding tools may not recognise the game. Upon launching the game, the default set of INI files will also be regenerated.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Find &lt;strong>Fallout 4&lt;/strong> in your &lt;strong>Games Library&lt;/strong> and hit &lt;strong>Play&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You will be prompted with a notification that Fallout 4 is configuring your video options, click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> again to the next window and hit &lt;strong>Exit&lt;/strong> to close the launcher.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The preset that is selected now will be irrelevant. WTP uses its own set of INI files.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/installation/regenerate-inis.png" alt="Regenerate INIs">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="future-updates">Future Updates&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The most important mod for most Bethesda games is the &lt;strong>Script Extender&lt;/strong>, a resource that is in turn required for many key mods. The &lt;strong>Fallout 4 Script Extender&lt;/strong> (F4SE) is &lt;em>version dependent&lt;/em>. It requires a specific version of Fallout 4. For instance, F4SE &lt;code>0.6.21&lt;/code> &lt;em>requires&lt;/em> Fallout 4 &lt;code>1.10.163&lt;/code>, and will not work with any other version of the game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately any update for the Creation Club requires the game executables to be updated which breaks F4SE every time. When that happens, the Script Extender team usually updates F4SE within a few days. Any F4SE plugins will have to be updated by their respective authors as well which can take several weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to prevent Creation Club updates from interrupting your playthrough and breaking your game, we are going to disable automatic updates in Steam. We are also going to backup the current version&amp;rsquo;s executables so you can restore them at any time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="disable-auto-updates">Disable Auto Updates&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open Steam and find &lt;strong>Fallout 4&lt;/strong> in your &lt;strong>Game Library&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click it and select &lt;strong>Properties&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the &lt;strong>Updates&lt;/strong> tab, change &lt;strong>Automatic updates&lt;/strong> to &lt;strong>Only update this game when I launch it&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Close the &lt;strong>Properties&lt;/strong> window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/installation/steam-disable-auto-updates.png" alt="Steam Disable Auto Updates">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="official-high-resolution-texture-pack">Official High Resolution Texture Pack&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Bethesda published a free 55GB texture pack with upscaled 4K textures that are nowhere near worth the hard drive space, especially not when compared to the higher quality textures from various mods that are featured in WTP. If you had the HD DLC installed previously, you need to disable it in Steam.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open &lt;strong>Steam&lt;/strong> and go into your &lt;strong>Game Library&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go to the &lt;strong>Fallout 4&lt;/strong> page and click &lt;strong>Manage my 8 DLC&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Uncheck &lt;strong>Fallout 4 - High Resolution Texture Pack&lt;/strong> in the list and click &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/installation/disable-hd-dlc.png" alt="Disable HD DLC">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="creation-club-content">Creation Club Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you bought any &amp;ldquo;creations&amp;rdquo; from the Creation Club (or grabbed some while they were available for free), they may still be present in your Data folder. Some select &amp;ldquo;creations&amp;rdquo; are supported in WTP as of version 1.6 but I recommend you install them as separate mods later on.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>steamapps\common\Fallout4\Data&lt;/code> and cut (CTRL + X) all files starting with &lt;strong>cc&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Paste (CTRL + V) all files to &lt;code>Fallout 4 Modding\Backups\Creation Club&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="wabbajack-installation">Wabbajack Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download the &lt;a href="https://www.wabbajack.org/#/">Wabbajack&lt;/a> executable from the official website.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move the downloaded file to &lt;code>Fallout 4 Modding\Wabbajack&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Double-click &lt;strong>Wabbajack.exe&lt;/strong>. It will automatically download and install the latest version.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="downloading-wtp">Downloading WTP&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Once Wabbajack is installed and open, click on &lt;strong>Browse Modlists&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find &lt;strong>Welcome to Paradise&lt;/strong> in the list and click the arrow to download.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the dots next to &lt;strong>Installation Location&lt;/strong> and choose a path.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Choose an empty, high-level folder, e.g. &lt;code>G:\Welcome to Paradise&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Welcome to Paradise&lt;/strong> installation folder:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SHOULD&lt;/strong> be on your SSD or otherwise fastest hard drive.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>CANNOT&lt;/strong> be inside the Wabbajack installation folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>CANNOT&lt;/strong> be inside the Fallout 4 installation folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>CANNOT&lt;/strong> be inside &lt;code>C:\Program Files&lt;/code> or &lt;code>C:\Program Files x86&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="download-location">Download Location&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The MO2 downloads folder within your &lt;strong>Welcome to Paradise&lt;/strong> folder will automatically be chosen as the download location. However, this is mostly a waste of space as the downloaded mod archives are only required for the initial installation and subsequent updates but not for gameplay.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I strongly recommend changing the &lt;strong>Download Location&lt;/strong> to a folder on a hard drive with plenty of free storage.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You can reuse the download folders from different Wabbajack lists for the same game.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="wtp-installation">WTP Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>After filling in the installation and download directories, click the Start button on the left.&lt;/strong> If you have Nexus Premium, you can lean back while Wabbajack downloads the required mod files and installs the setup. Otherwise, you will have to click through the mod pages and download manually (Wabbajack will guide you).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Should anything go wrong during the installation process, please find the &lt;strong>Wabbajack.current.log&lt;/strong> file inside &lt;code>\Wabbajack\&amp;lt;version number&amp;gt;\logs\&lt;/code>. Upload it (drag and drop) into the &lt;code>#wtp-support&lt;/code> channel on our &lt;a href="https://discord.com/invite/BpwXX5f">Discord server&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once the download and installation process has finished successfully, Wabbajack will inform you about it and you can proceed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="mod-organizer-2">Mod Organizer 2&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>All mods are installed in Mod Organizer 2 which is required to play the setup. You must always launch F4SE through MO2.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Navigate to your &lt;strong>Welcome to Paradise&lt;/strong> installation directory.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Double-click &lt;strong>ModOrganizer.exe&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I recommend adding ModOrganizer.exe to your taskbar or creating a shortcut on your Desktop for easy access.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="performance-inis">Performance INIs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you are playing on a lower-end PC and are worried about performance, you can install the performance-optimised set of INI files included with WTP:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>\Welcome to Paradise\mods\WTP INIs - Performance\&lt;/code> and copy the &lt;strong>Fallout4.ini&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Fallout4Prefs.ini&lt;/strong> inside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Paste them to &lt;code>\Welcome to Paradise\profiles\Welcome to Paradise\&lt;/code> and overwrite the existing ones.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Repeat the process with the INI files from &lt;strong>WTP INIs - Default&lt;/strong> to revert to the default settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="resolution">Resolution&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Unlike the default INIs, Wabbajack will not be able to automatically adjust the resolution in the INI files and you will have to do this manually.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Skip this if you are on an ultrawide monitor (there are instructions further down on this page).&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To change the monitor resolution, open the &lt;strong>INI Editor&lt;/strong> in Mod Organizer 2 (see picture below).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go to the &lt;strong>Fallout4Prefs.ini&lt;/strong> tab and scroll to the &lt;code>[Display]&lt;/code> section.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change the following two lines to match your monitor resolution:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>iSize H=
iSize W=
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button at the bottom before you close the window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/installation/change-resolution.png" alt="Change Resolution">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="controller-fix">Controller Fix&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The resolution of the Pip-Boy interface was increased in the &lt;code>fallout4prefs.ini&lt;/code> file. Unfortunately this will cause the map cursor to lock in the upper left corner when playing with a controller.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you play with a controller, follow these instructions to revert the INI tweak:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click the puzzle icon in MO2 and select &lt;strong>INI Editor&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/installation/mo2-ini-editor.png" alt="Open INI Editor">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Switch to the &lt;strong>fallout4prefs.ini&lt;/strong> tab and scroll down to the &lt;strong>[Display]&lt;/strong> section.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Revert the following lines to the values shown below:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>uPipboyTargetHeight=700
uPipboyTargetWidth=876
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Close the window and click &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> to save your changes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/installation/controller-fix.png" alt="Controller Fix">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="frame-rate-and-vsync">Frame Rate and VSYNC&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the Creation Engine&amp;rsquo;s drawbacks is the physics engine which is tied to the frame rate. Simply put, the game breaks if it runs at more than 60FPS. However, there is a mod that allows you to unlock the frame rate by dynamically adjusting havok settings at runtime, aptly called &lt;strong>High FPS Physics Fix&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>FPS&lt;/strong> or frames per second are how the amount of still images shown every second are measured. The higher your FPS, the more fluid the game appears. The amount of frames per second that can be rendered depends on your hardware, primarily your CPU and GPU. In my opinion, a stable 60FPS is perfect for most games, including Fallout 4. Most systems should be able to achieve a consistent 60FPS in WTP.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>VSYNC&lt;/strong> is a technique that syncs a game&amp;rsquo;s framerate to your monitor&amp;rsquo;s refresh rate (hence the name). It prevents &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Screen_tearing">screentearing&lt;/a> at the cost of latency and is always recommended.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Welcome to Paradise caps the framerate at 60 and forces VSYNC through High FPS Physics Fix.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="adjusting-the-fps-cap">Adjusting the FPS Cap&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you are unhappy with the default cap at 60FPS, you can change it. To do so, follow these instructions:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In Mod Organizer 2, double-click the &lt;strong>ESSENTIALS&lt;/strong> separator at the top to expand it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Doubl-click &lt;strong>High FPS Physics Fix - WTP Settings&lt;/strong> which contains a custom INI for High FPS Physics Fix.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Switch to the &lt;strong>INI Files&lt;/strong> tab and select the &lt;strong>HighFPSPhysicsFix_Custom.ini&lt;/strong> file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In &lt;strong>Line 2&lt;/strong>, change the value for &lt;code>InGameFPS=&lt;/code> to your desired FPS cap. Set to &lt;strong>0.0&lt;/strong> to uncap the frame rate.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Press &lt;strong>CTRL + S&lt;/strong> to save and close the window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/installation/change-fps-cap.png" alt="Change FPS Cap">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ultrawide-support">Ultrawide Support&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Skip this step if you have a 16:9 monitor.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Since release 2.2, WTP officially supports ultrawide monitors with a &lt;strong>21:9 ratio&lt;/strong>, i.e. resolutions of &lt;strong>2560x1080&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>3440x1440&lt;/strong>. This requires a few minor changes in Mod Organizer 2 that you should go through before starting your playthrough.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="ini-changes">INI Changes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Upon installing WTP, Wabbajack should automatically detect your monitor&amp;rsquo;s default resolution and configure Fallout4Prefs.ini accordingly. However, if you wish you can check this and make sure the correct resolution is set. To do so, open the &lt;strong>INI Editor&lt;/strong> in MO2, go to the &lt;strong>Fallout4Prefs.ini&lt;/strong> tab and scroll to the &lt;strong>[Display]&lt;/strong> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the resolution is not correct, change it and click the &lt;strong>SAVE&lt;/strong> button at the bottom before closing the window.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/installation/change-resolution.png" alt="Change Resolution">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="additional-mods">Additional Mods&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In Mod Organizer 2, find the &lt;strong>ULTRAWIDE SUPPORT (21-9)&lt;/strong> separator in the left pane and double-click to expand it. There are three mods below it. Activate all three by checking the boxes. This will add an additional plugin to the load order which you do not need to adjust because it is empty and only exists to load an INI file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/installation/ultrawide-mods.png" alt="Ultrawide Mods">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="creation-club">Creation Club&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The only Creation supported by WTP is fadingsignal&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://fallout.fandom.com/wiki/Modular_military_backpack">Modular Military Backpack&lt;/a> which is the perfect companion to the K-9 Harness (also by fadingsignal). I removed the levelled list distribution so there is only a single backpack in the world which you will come across very early on in the game in Vault 111.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you own the Modular Military Backpack CC, you can install it for WTP by following these steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Navigate to the mods folder within your Mod Organizer 2 instance: &lt;code>\Welcome To Paradise\mods\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a new folder named &amp;ldquo;Creation Club - Modular Military Backpack&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Retrieve the plugin and archives for the Creation from your CC backups folder:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>ccfsvfo4001-ModularMilitaryBackpack.esl
ccFSVFO4001-ModularMilitaryBackpack - Main.ba2
ccFSVFO4001-ModularMilitaryBackpack - Textures.ba2
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Copy all three files into the new &amp;ldquo;Creation Club - Modular Military Backpack&amp;rdquo; folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Back in Mod Organizer 2, press &lt;strong>F5&lt;/strong> to refresh.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The new mod will appear at the bottom of your mod order (left pane).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drag it up below the &lt;strong>NEW CONTENT&lt;/strong> separator and activate it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Also activate the patches for the Creation under the same separator.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/installation/install-backpack-creation.png" alt="Install Backpack Creation">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="launching-the-game">Launching the game&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In order to play TPF Fallout 4, you must launch &lt;strong>f4se_loader.exe&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2. Otherwise your mods will not work. When you open Mod Organizer 2, F4SE (renamed to &lt;strong>Welcome to Paradise&lt;/strong> for your convenience) should be selected automatically in the executables drop-down and you can start the game by clicking &lt;strong>Run&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/installation/run-f4se.png" alt="Start Game">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="starting-a-new-save">Starting a new save&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In the main menu, click &lt;strong>NEW&lt;/strong> to start a your playthrough.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Press &lt;strong>F10&lt;/strong> to temporarily toggle off ENB. It may look strange during the intro video and prologue.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Shortly after the character creation, you will get a prompt which is added by the mod &lt;strong>Start Me Up&lt;/strong>. You will be asked whether you want to &amp;ldquo;relive the memory&amp;rdquo;, giving you the option to skip the prologue. &lt;strong>Do not select this option if you never played Fallout 4 before&lt;/strong>, you are going to miss some important things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to play the regular Fallout 4 intro (highly recommended), click &amp;ldquo;This is a memory. Let&amp;rsquo;s stay here a while&amp;rdquo; and the prologue will play out as usual. Proceed to the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/mod-config/">Mod Configuration&lt;/a> page after exiting the vault.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="start-me-up">Start Me Up&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Intro spoilers ahead.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>If you do choose to skip the prologue because you have played it a hundred times already, select the second option: &amp;ldquo;This is a memory. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to relive this.&amp;quot;. After a fade-to-black, you will find yourself waking up inside the cryo pod shortly after a certain someone shot your spouse. Note that the door to the hall is &lt;strong>locked&lt;/strong> until you interact with the terminal (left of the door), configure your SPECIAL stats and enter a name.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="interact-with-the-terminal">&lt;strong>Interact with the terminal:&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/installation/smu-terminal.jpg" alt="SMU Terminal">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="select-your-special-stats-and-enter-your-name">&lt;strong>Select your SPECIAL stats and enter your name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/installation/special-stats.jpg" alt="SPECIAL stats">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="open-main-door-through-the-terminal">&lt;strong>Open main door through the terminal:&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/installation/open-door.jpg" alt="Open Door">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="play-through-the-intro-as-usual-and-continue-with-the-mod-configurationfo4wtpmod-config-page-after-exiting-the-vault">Play through the intro as usual and continue with the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/mod-config/">Mod Configuration&lt;/a> page after exiting the vault.&lt;/h4></description></item><item><title>Fo4: Mod Config</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/mod-config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/mod-config/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="mcm-settings">MCM Settings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Thanks to the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/21497">Mod Configuration Menu&lt;/a>, many mods can now be tweaked through the MCM which can be accessed through the pause menu. For Welcome to Paradise, most settings were already adjusted and can be applied using &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/56195">MCM Settings Manager&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in what kind of changes the preset includes, check the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/mcm-settings/">MCM Settings&lt;/a> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="load-mcm-preset">Load MCM Preset&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Please wait until after you woke up in Vault 111 before you load the WTP MCM settings.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Press ESCAPE to go into the Pause menu and open the &lt;strong>Mod Config&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the &lt;strong>-=MCM Settings Manager=-&lt;/strong> at the top.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> when asked to save your current (default) settings, then &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> again to confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Choose the appropriate profile and click &lt;strong>Apply&lt;/strong>:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>WTP - MCM Settings&lt;/strong> if you are on a 16:9 monitor.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>WTP - MCM Settings (21:9)&lt;/strong> if you are on a 21:9 monitor.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> twice to confirm, then click &lt;strong>Reload MCM&lt;/strong> on the left.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>All MCM settings are now properly loaded up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/mod-config/apply-wtp-mcm-preset.jpg" alt="Apply WTP MCM Preset">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="holotime">HoloTime&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>HoloTime adds a clock widget to the interface. By default, the mod is disabled, but it can be enabled in its MCM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please note that the &lt;strong>Widget position&lt;/strong> setting in HoloHUD cannot currently be saved and applied by MCM Settings Manager. I recommend downsizing it to 0.7 and relocating it to the upper right corner so it does not interfere with the notification boxes on the right.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, you will not be able to move the clock out of the 16:9 window if you are playing on a 21:9 resolution.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/mod-config/adjust-holotime-widget-position.jpg" alt="Adjust HoloTime Widget Position">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="immersive-hud">Immersive HUD&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Immersive HUD is a great option to reduce the interface clutter when it is not needed. Like HoloTime, it is disabled by default, but can be turned on in its MCM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/mod-config/enable-ihud.jpg" alt="Enable iHUD">&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>After applying the WTP MCM settings and optionally changing the FallUI HUD preset, please save and restart the game.&lt;/strong> This will ensure that all changes properly apply.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="other-mod-settings">Other Mod Settings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, not all mods include MCMs so we&amp;rsquo;ll have to use holotapes the old fashioned way. Settings holotapes obviously require the Pip-Boy so they can only be used after leaving Vault 111.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="restore-power-armor-frames">Restore Power Armor Frames&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For this mod (which allows you to take the power armor frames off of dead enemies), I recommend adding a perk requirement. The holotape in question should have been added to your inventory at the start of the game.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Find the &lt;strong>Restore Power Armor Frames Settings&lt;/strong> holotape in your Pip-Boy under &lt;strong>Misc&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Settings Holotapes&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the &lt;strong>Perk Requirements&lt;/strong> section. I recommend setting &lt;strong>Scrapper rank 2&lt;/strong> as the required perk.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/mod-config/restore-pa-frames-config.jpg" alt="Restore PA Frames Config">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="visible-idle-markers">Visible Idle Markers&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The config holotape for Visible Idle Markers is not added automatically so you need to find a Crafting Station (which is what Chem Stations are called in WTP). There is one in Sanctuary behind one of the houses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/mod-config/sanctuary-crafting-station.jpg" alt="Sanctuary Crafting Station">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Visible Idle Markers Settings&lt;/strong> holotape can be found in the &lt;strong>MOD CONFIG&lt;/strong> category at the very bottom of the list and crafted for free.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Find the &lt;strong>Visible Idle Markers Settings&lt;/strong> holotape in your Pip-Boy under &lt;strong>Misc&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Settings Holotapes&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the &lt;strong>Disable Hammering&lt;/strong> option so that your Sanctuary settlers will stop trying to hammer the walls into shape.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/mod-config/visible-idle-markers-config.jpg" alt="Visible Idle Markers Config">&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Before diving into the game, I highly recommend checking out the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/documentation/">WTP Documentation&lt;/a> or at least the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/documentation/#keybinds">keybinds&lt;/a> section.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="enjoy-your-playthrough">Enjoy your playthrough!&lt;/h4></description></item><item><title>Fo4: Documentation</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/documentation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/documentation/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="ini-settings">INI Settings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As usual, I have used &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/67">BethINI&lt;/a> to generate the INI files before adding some manual tweaks. The default INI set is based on the &lt;strong>High&lt;/strong> preset while the performance INI set uses the &lt;strong>Medium&lt;/strong> one.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>VSYNC&lt;/strong> is always turned off, it is forced through High FPS Physics Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ambient occlusion&lt;/strong> is always turned off, we are using ENB AO instead&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>TAA&lt;/strong> is used for anti aliasing (as opposed to FXAA)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Godrays&lt;/strong> are disabled in the performance INIs&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="fallout4ini">Fallout4.ini&lt;/h3>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>[Display]
fPipboyScreenEmitIntensityPA=1.25
fPipboyScreenDiffuseIntensityPA=0.15
[Pipboy]
bPipboyDisableFX=1
bPipboyEffectColorOnLight=0
fPAEffectColorB=0.392
fPAEffectColorG=0.722
fPAEffectColorR=0.376
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;h3 id="fallout4prefsini">Fallout4Prefs.ini&lt;/h3>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>[Display]
uPipboyTargetHeight=1400
uPipboyTargetWidth=1752
[Interface]
iHUDColorB=100
iHUDColorG=184
iHUDColorR=96
[Pipboy]
fPipboyEffectColorB=0.3920
fPipboyEffectColorG=0.7220
fPipboyEffectColorR=0.3760
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;h2 id="visual-changes">Visual Changes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Fallout 4 was never a particularly beautiful game, but it has solid graphics. Compared to older Fallout titles, it is a great deal more colourful and &amp;ldquo;cartoonish&amp;rdquo;, no green filter like in Fallout 3 and no distinct dusty hue like in Fallout New Vegas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my changes for WTP, I have decided to stay faithful to the vanilla colours and style, opting to focus largely on improving texture quality. Any more profound changes such as a tree overhaul would have susbstantially increased the list&amp;rsquo;s complexity due to FO4&amp;rsquo;s precombine system which is the only thing that keeps performance from turning into a slide show.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="weather--lighting">Weather &amp;amp; Lighting&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Welcome to Paradise includes &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/57680">Lightweight Lighting - A Weather and Interior Lighting Overhaul&lt;/a> which subtly improves lighting while retaining the original colour palette. Combined with the lightweight &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/58028">Spectrum ENB&lt;/a> preset, it constitutes a solid upgrade over vanilla without changing the original style.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/wtp-day.jpg" alt="WTP Day">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/wtp-dusk.jpg" alt="WTP Dusk">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/wtp-night.jpg" alt="WTP Night">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="landscape">Landscape&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In keeping with the pledge to stick with the vanilla style, I added &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/9292">Lush Landscapes&lt;/a> (the &amp;ldquo;Dried&amp;rdquo; edition) as the grass overhaul which does a good job at improving vanilla&amp;rsquo;s sparse vegetation. Water was greatly improved by &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/20775">Water Enhancement Textures&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/41568">Wave Animation Vanilla Enhanced&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/wtp-landscape.jpg" alt="WTP Landscape">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="texture-packs">Texture Packs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In Fallout 4, loose assets can actually have a significant impact on performance and load time over BA2 packed assets, far more so than in Skyrim SE. This is why most mod authors pack up their assets in archives and it is why I have been religiously packing up most loose assets in WTP. On this page I am listing the mods that the individual textures and meshes in the custom WTP texture packs are from.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that the assets were &lt;em>not&lt;/em> repackaged and redistributed. Each of the individual mods will be downloaded for you from their original mod pages by Wabbajack, then packed up into archives to match my own setup.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="texture-pack---clutter">Texture Pack - Clutter&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/28204">Grey Tortoise Cigarettes Redux&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/1500">Bottles Label Overhaul&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/32224">Sweet Roll 5000&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/59380">Drinkable Water Retexture&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/45675">Gold Bars - FNV Dead Money Inspired Replacer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/8087">Better Ammo Boxes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/8879">Duffle Bag Retexture 2K&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/16841">Retextured First Aid Kids - Ephla&amp;rsquo;s Unique First Aid&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/12062">PatrickJr&amp;rsquo;s Redone Bobbleheads&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/49999">Classic Wasteland Survival Guide - Magazine Retexture&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/53012">U.S. Covert Operations Manual Revised - Magazine Retexture&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/50253">Total Hack - Magazine Retexture&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/52206">Library and Subway Tokens HD Remastered&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/34246">Globes 2K&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/34014?tab=files">Wall Worldmap&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/37762">ADs 2X Rez&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="texture-pack---apparel">Texture Pack - Apparel&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/40633">Pipboy UHD 2K&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/40952">Vault Suit UHD 4K&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/524">Combat Armor No Star Decal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/12187">Robot Armor Retextured&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/13053">Mechanist Armor Retextured&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/14340">Marine Helmet with Tactical Hood&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/14010">Piper&amp;rsquo;s Coat HR&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/36704">Better House Dress Shoes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/5021">Eyewear and Mask Retexture&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/19272">Shorter Gas Masks&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="texture-pack---power-armors">Texture Pack - Power Armors&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/27917">Power Armors Redone&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/28033">Power Armors Redone Extended - CPAO Textures&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/28033">Power Armors Redone Extended - Minutemen Paint Job Textures&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/30796">Power Armor Jetpack 2K HD&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/4092">Matching White Brotherhood Rank Insignia&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="texture-pack---weapons">Texture Pack - Weapons&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/33107">10mm HD&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/24398">The Fantastic Forty Four&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/49185">The Hunting Rifle Set&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/49369">The Ballistic Series&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/2211">Scratch Made - New Double Barrel Shotgun Textures&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/48567">The Laser Series&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/37723">CC&amp;rsquo;s FUHD Institute Laser Weapons&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/48321">The Plasma Project&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/24506">The Meritable Minigun&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/33381">Missile Launcher HD&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/24460">The Fancy Fatman&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/41107">Gauss Rifle UHD&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/51479">The Flamer Project&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/31564">Cryolator HD&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/31611">Broadsider HD&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/51557">Leafblower Junk Jet&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/24813">The Delightful Deliverer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/24606">The Radical Ripper&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/38644">Grognak&amp;rsquo;s Axe&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/6960">Kremvh&amp;rsquo;s Tooth Replacer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/37749">M26 Fragmentation Grenade Replacer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="texture-pack---creatures">Texture Pack - Creatures&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/14726">Delightful Dead Fish&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/53516">CC&amp;rsquo;s UHD Bloatflies - Reimagined&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/36533">CC&amp;rsquo;s UHD Radscorpions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/36434">CC&amp;rsquo;s Enhanced Vanilla Mirelurks&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/15038">Protectron HD&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/36045">Assaultron HD&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/37680">CC&amp;rsquo;s FUHD Sentry Bots&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/53619">CC&amp;rsquo;s Liberty Prime&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/36857">CC&amp;rsquo;s UHD Fog Crawlers&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/36460">CC&amp;rsquo;s UHD Aliens&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="gameplay-changes">Gameplay Changes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>WTP features a good amount of quality of life improvements. These include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/62843">Perk Up - Lightweight Perk Overhaul&lt;/a>: Reworks vanilla perks to be less annoying or pointless.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/18946">Start Me Up&lt;/a>: The Basic version of this mod included in WTP allows you to skip the pre-war part of the Prologue.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/45072">Consume Without Pickup&lt;/a>: Immediately use a Stimpak or eat that Radstag stew without having to pick it up first.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/52723">Baka Wait Anywhere&lt;/a>: Allows you to wait anywhere without having to sit down (but with a few conditions).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/20093">Automatically Lowered Weapons&lt;/a>: The player automatically lowers their weapon when not in combat.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="quest-adjustments">Quest Adjustments&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/users/2652197?tab=user+files">No Quest Autostart series&lt;/a>: The DLC quests will no longer start automatically upon reaching the required level. You will need to either listen to the associated radio broadcast or actively go to the related location. Note that the level requirements was not removed, but the quests will no longer be automatically added to your quest log.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/25934">Keep Radiants in the Commonwealth&lt;/a>: Any radiant quests received in the Commonwealth will now always send you to locations within the Commonwealth (as opposed to DLC areas which they previously could).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/24940">Preston Garvey No Radiant Settlement Quests&lt;/a>: After taking the Castle for the Minutemen, Preston Garvey will no longer give you radiant quests with the exception of those that you cannot get through the Radio Freedom broadcasts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/51979">Whose Quest Is It Anyway&lt;/a>: Upon attempting to remove a quest item from your inventory, you will now be notified which quest the item is locked by.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="simple-crafting-station">Simple Crafting Station&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>All vanilla Chem Stations were renamed to &amp;ldquo;Crafting Stations&amp;rdquo; to account for the fact that you can craft pretty much anything at them. Their models were changed accordingly by &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/44691">this excellent mod&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Holotapes to configure a few mods were moved to a unique category at Crafting Stations called MOD CONFIG. They can now be crafted for free.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/config-holotape-crafting.jpg" alt="Config Holotape Crafting">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="photo-mode">Photo Mode&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>WTP includes the amazing &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/49997">Photo Mode&lt;/a> by reg2k. It&amp;rsquo;s the perfect tool for screenarchers, pause the game and find the perfect angle for a great picture. You can access it through ESCAPE menu or define a hotkey in the associated MCM.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="power-armor">Power Armor&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While WTP touches little on the gameplay side of things, I did change how power armors were distributed and how their paint jobs work to be quite different from vanilla.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="distribution">Distribution&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Quick summary of the changes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You will find fewer full power armors sets and more separate pieces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>T-45 and Raider power armor pieces will be more commonly found.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>T-51 power armor pieces will be more commonly found.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>T-60 power armor pieces can be found exclusively on Brotherhood troops.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>X-01 power armor pieces are rare. There are only two full sets in the Commonwealth.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In vanilla, one may be forgiven to think that before the bombs dropped every citizen of Boston had a set of power armor stored in their backyard. There are just so bloody many of them! In order to cut down the amount of armors you find, I added &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/12050">Some Assembly Required&lt;/a> for its hand-placed power armor pieces (and removed everything else it did). In most locations where before there was a power armor frame often with a full set, you will now find separate pieces or other rare loot. Additionally, pieces of Raider, T-45, or (rarely) T-51 power armor were hand-placed in various locations around the Commonwealth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since this change means there will be far fewer frames found in the world, I added &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/20890">Restore Power Armor Frames&lt;/a> which will allow you to extract the frames from dead NPCs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to lore, &lt;strong>T-60 power armor&lt;/strong> had not yet replaced the T-51 in the standard army loadout before the bombs dropped and did not enter mass-production until the Brotherhood of Steel procured the means to do so much later on. As such it makes no sense for T-60 sets to be significantly more common than T-51 in the Commonwealth. In WTP, T-60 sets are given exclusively to Brotherhood troops. Atom Cats now wear T-45 power armor sets instead of T-60. The only T-60 set you can find outside of the Brotherhood is the &lt;a href="https://fallout.fandom.com/wiki/Tesla_T-60_armor">Tesla&lt;/a> variant from the Automatron DLC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is one full set of T-51 power armor including frame and fusion core in a heavily fortified location. See the SPOILER SECTION at the bottom if you want to know where to find it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the levelled lists, T-60 pieces were replaced by T-45 pieces and X-01 pieces were replaced by T-51 pieces.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As for &lt;strong>X-01 power armor&lt;/strong>, there are only two full sets to be found: One of them is the &lt;a href="https://fallout.fandom.com/wiki/Quantum_X-01_power_armor">Quantum X-01&lt;/a> from the Nuka World DLC. The second consists of regular X-01 pieces you will have to gather from various locations around the Commonwealth. Scroll to the bottom of this page to the SPOILER SECTION to find out where exactly those six pieces can be found.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="paint-jobs">Paint Jobs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In vanilla, many paint jobs also have non-cosmetic effects such as stat increases. The mod &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/4619">Power Armor Materials AND Paints&lt;/a> separates these two so you can control the paint job and &amp;ldquo;material&amp;rdquo; (the non-cosmetic buffs) separately. This required some integration patching with other power armor mods added in WTP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Paint jobs now all cost 2 oil and 2 steel to apply (matching the Creation Club paint jobs). They no longer increase weight or value of the armor piece and will not yield a loose mod upon swapping to a different one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, paint jobs were made available for a greater variety of power armor pieces by &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/11234">Consistent Power Armor Overhaul&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/28029">Minutemen Paint Job&lt;/a>. Both of those mods are supported by the amazing &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/28033">Power Armors Redone Extended&lt;/a> so the new paint job variants are of the same style and quality as the vanilla power armors retextured by &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/27917">Power Armors Redone&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Paint Jobs&lt;/th>
&lt;th>T-45&lt;/th>
&lt;th>T-51&lt;/th>
&lt;th>T-60&lt;/th>
&lt;th>X-01&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Factory&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Winterized (white)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Military (olive)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Brotherhood of Steel&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Minutemen&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Vault-Tec&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Railroad&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Institute&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Atom Cats&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Hot Rod Flames&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Hot Rod Shark&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Hot Rod Hot Pink&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Vim!&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Vim! Refresh&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Sugar Bombs&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Abraxo&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;td>x&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Brotherhood of Steel paint job has multiple variants for any PA Left Arm pieces to display your rank insignia (Knight, Sentinel, Paragon). For all other pieces, there is only a single &amp;ldquo;Brotherhood of Steel&amp;rdquo; paint job as there are no rank-specific decals for them.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Abraxo&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Sugar Bombs&lt;/strong> paint jobs for the T-51 (added by the Contraptions DLC) will no longer be available by default. You need to find special promotional holotapes for each to unlock the paint jobs. Their locations are listed in the SPOILER SECTION at the bottom of this page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Vault-Tec&lt;/strong> paint job for the T-45, T-51, T-60, and X-01 power armors is similarly disabled at the start of the game and can be unlocked by a holotape. You can find it in the Overseer&amp;rsquo;s office of any vault.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="other-changes">Other Changes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/4408">Power Armor Animation Changes&lt;/a> makes entering and exiting your power armor out of combat much faster. Upon exiting your power armor frame, your fusion core will immediately be placed in your inventory thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/14773">Take Your Cores&lt;/a>. This saves you from having to grab them manually. If you leave the cores in, NPCs like your settlers may decide to take your power armor for a walk and they don&amp;rsquo;t always return it either. &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/33080">No PA Battery Pathing&lt;/a> removes the dreaded struggle of getting behind your power armor and slotting in the fusion core which in vanilla, if you get stuck, lasts up to 16 seconds.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="settlement-building">Settlement Building&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The building system was generally improved by the following mods:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/9424">Place Everywhere&lt;/a> removes the dreaded red outlines. You can now build anywhere and have much finer movement controls.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/16939">New Infinite Settlement Budget Plugin&lt;/a> significantly increases the building budget (so be careful).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/46453">Visible Idle Markers&lt;/a> helps prevent building objects on idle markers which NPCs would clip through to reach the marker.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Building objects in settlements no longer grants XP.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The more objects you place in a settlement (or technically the higher the overall polycount of all object gets), the more performance will degrade. With the expanded building budget it is now up to the player to decorate carefully and mind the framerate.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="scrapping-machine">Scrapping Machine&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The mod &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/35793">Scrapping Machine&lt;/a> adds some very useful &lt;del>washing&lt;/del> scrapping machines that you can build in your workshop. Any junk items placed inside will be broken down into their base scrap. This is extremely useful because junk broken down for components when crafting or building may cause unused base scrap to be lost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/wtp-scrap-1.jpg" alt="WTP Scrap 1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/wtp-scrap-2.jpg" alt="WTP Scrap 2">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/wtp-scrap-3.jpg" alt="WTP Scrap 3">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="keybinds">Keybinds&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>WTP comes with a bunch of custom hotkeys, all of which can be configured in MCMs or INI files.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="enbseries">ENBSeries&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Hotkeys for ENB can be adjusted in the &lt;code>enblocal.ini&lt;/code> (located in the root folder). &lt;a href="https://keycode.info/">Here&lt;/a> is a great website to quickly figure out the keycode for any key by simply pressing it.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>F8&lt;/strong> Toggle FPS Counter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>F10&lt;/strong> Toggle ENB Effect&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>F11&lt;/strong> Open ENB GUI&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="workshop">Workshop&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Y&lt;/strong> Open the Workshop (Faster Workshop)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>F1&lt;/strong> Toggle Place Everywhere (can build objects anywhere)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>F2&lt;/strong> Toggle Snapping (requires Place Everywhere mode to be on)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="hud">HUD&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>V&lt;/strong> Toggle HUD (if Immersive HUD is enabled)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>H&lt;/strong> Toggle clock widget (if HoloTime is enabled)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="other">Other&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>P&lt;/strong> Open Photo Mode&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>CTRL + B&lt;/strong> Toggle Radio&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>CTRL + G&lt;/strong> Use Stimpak&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="new-content">New Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="additional-music">Additional Music&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>WTP both adds new tracks to the background music as well as to the Diamond City radio. The new additions were carefully selected to match the vanilla atmosphere so as not pull you out of the game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following mods expand the game&amp;rsquo;s soundtrack:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/14531">Musical Lore - Wasteland Edition&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/15870">Fallout Suite - Soundtrack Extension for Fallout 4&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/9663">Bleak Beauty - A Fallout 4 Fan Made OST&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The music mods&amp;rsquo; individual plugins were replaced by a patched and merged one.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/56898">Diamond City Radio Extended&lt;/a> adds over 140 new songs to the radio&amp;rsquo;s catalogue.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="pip-boy-color-variations">Pip-Boy Color Variations&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/47858">Pip Boy Retextured&lt;/a> adds eight new colour variations (paint jobs) for the Pip Boy like the Creation ones but for free. You can change your Pip Boy&amp;rsquo;s paint job whenever you like at any Armor Workbench.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="k-9-harness">K-9 Harness&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of fadingsignal&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/17686">K-9 Harness&lt;/a> for Dogmeat so I had to add it to WTP. Instead of it being craftable, I have placed one harness in a location that fits thematically. Either trust that you will find it naturally on your travels or check the SPOILER SECTION at the bottom of this page if you want to know where it is.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="cc-modular-military-backpack">CC Modular Military Backpack&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Also by fadingsignal is the &lt;a href="https://fallout.fandom.com/wiki/Modular_military_backpack">Modular Military Backpack&lt;/a> which matches the K-9 Harness beautifully. It is a Creation so you will need to buy it from the Creation Club. There are instructions for installing the Creation in WTP on the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/installation/#creation-club">Installation&lt;/a> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that the backpack will no longer be given to you upon leaving Vault 111 and it will not be distributed either. You can find a single one within Vault 111 that you can pick up at the start of the game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/cc-backpack.jpg" alt="CC Backpack">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="spoiler-section">SPOILER SECTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PLEASE DO NOT KEEP SCROLLING IF YOU DON&amp;rsquo;T WANT TO KNOW WHERE VARIOUS RARE ITEMS ARE FOUND.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="x-01-power-armor">X-01 Power Armor&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can find X-01 power armor pieces in the following locations:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://fallout.fandom.com/wiki/The_Prydwen">The Prydwen&lt;/a>: X-01 Helmet (vanilla)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://fallout.fandom.com/wiki/Old_Gullet_sinkhole">Old Gullet Sinkhole&lt;/a>: X-01 Left Arm&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://fallout.fandom.com/wiki/Boxing_gym">Boxing Gym&lt;/a>: X-01 Right Armor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://fallout.fandom.com/wiki/Museum_of_Witchcraft">Museum of Witchcraft&lt;/a>: X-01 Torso&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://fallout.fandom.com/wiki/Greenetech_Genetics">Greenetech Genetics&lt;/a>: X-01 Left Leg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://fallout.fandom.com/wiki/O%27Neill_Family_Manufacturing">O&amp;rsquo;Neill Family Manufacturing&lt;/a>: X-01 Right Leg&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="full-t-51-set">Full T-51 Set&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There is a full suit of T-51 on the rooftop of the &lt;a href="https://fallout.fandom.com/wiki/35_Court">35 Court&lt;/a> in the Financial District, downtown Boston.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="pa-paint-jobs">PA Paint Jobs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can find holotapes to unlock certain power armor paint jobs in the following locations:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://fallout.fandom.com/wiki/Super_Duper_Mart_(Fallout_4)">Super-Duper Mart&lt;/a>: Sugar Bombs paint job (T-51)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://fallout.fandom.com/wiki/Charlestown_laundry">Charlestown Laundry&lt;/a>: Abraxo paint job (T-51)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="k-9-harness-1">K-9 Harness&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Can be found at the &lt;a href="https://fallout.fandom.com/wiki/Malden_police_station">Malden police station&lt;/a>, upstairs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fo4: MCM Settings</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/mcm-settings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/mcm-settings/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The MCM settings below are applied by the WTP MCM preset.&lt;/strong> They are documented here purely for my benefit and for curious users. YOU DO NOT HAVE TO APPLY THEM MANUALLY.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="baka-wait-anywhere">Baka Wait Anywhere&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>While Being Irradiated: &lt;strong>ON&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait Hotkey: &lt;strong>CTRL + T&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I did not use just T as the hotkey as that would bring up the Wait menu while renaming weapons, etc, at workbenches.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/baka-wait-anywhere-mcm.jpg" alt="Baka Wait Anywhere MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="configurable-hotkeys">Configurable Hotkeys&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use Stimpak: &lt;strong>CTRL + G&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Toggle Radio: &lt;strong>CTRL + B&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Please note that any hotkeys bound through this mod are not blacklisted in menus and will fire when renaming a weapon in the workbench for instance. Thus, it is necessary to use keys that are not letters or combinations of multiple keys. Also be aware that Toggle Workshop and Show Wait Menu are not bound because hotkeys for them are covered by other mods.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/configurable-hotkeys-mcm.jpg" alt="Configurable Hotkeys MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fallui-inventory">FallUI Inventory&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Dual colors was set to &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> (with white as the primary color)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Secondary color was set to &lt;strong>Green light&lt;/strong> for all menus&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/fallui-inventory-mcm-1.jpg" alt="FallUI Inventory MCM 1">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Go back by Pipboy/cancel key (for submenus) was set to &lt;strong>ON&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/fallui-inventory-mcm-2.jpg" alt="FallUI Inventory MCM 2">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fallui-confirm-boxes">FallUI Confirm Boxes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>All boxes were set to &lt;strong>96, 184, 100&lt;/strong> (same as FallUI Inventory green light color)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All boxes except for the Create Robot one were set to the standard design&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/fallui-confirm-boxes-mcm.jpg" alt="FallUI Confirm Boxes MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fallui-hud">FallUI HUD&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Max visible messages: &lt;strong>5&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hide &amp;ldquo;Hold [V] to open the Workshop menu&amp;rdquo;: &lt;strong>ON&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/fallui-hud-mcm.jpg" alt="FallUI HUD MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fallui-map">FallUI Map&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Local map color &lt;strong>Green light&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Max zoom out &lt;strong>0.3&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Map marker scale &lt;strong>130&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/fallui-map-mcm.jpg" alt="FallUI Map MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fallui-workbench">FallUI Workbench&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Auto-craft items without cost: &lt;strong>OFF&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Brightness unavailable item: &lt;strong>25&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/fallui-workbench-mcm.jpg" alt="FallUI HUD MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="faster-workshop">Faster Workshop&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This mod is only included for its hotkey feature as Buffout already improves the workshop loading speed.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Start Workshop Mode: &lt;strong>Y&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/faster-workshop-mcm.jpg" alt="Faster Workshop MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="holotime">HoloTime&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>HoloTime is &lt;em>disabled&lt;/em> by default and needs to be turned on first.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Downscaled to size .7 and relocated to the top right where it won&amp;rsquo;t clash with notifications boxes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Toggle HoloTime Display to &lt;strong>H&lt;/strong> (HUD needs to be enabled)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/holotime-mcm.jpg" alt="HoloTime MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="immersive-hud">Immersive HUD&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Immersive HUD is &lt;em>disabled&lt;/em> by default and needs to be turned on first.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Main Settings: &lt;strong>Immersive HUD Enabled&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Settings Holotape &lt;strong>OFF&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>AID Toggle Items &lt;strong>OFF&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hotkey to Toggle HUD: &lt;strong>V&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Crosshair - Hit Marker: &lt;strong>Always&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Compass - Combat: &lt;strong>ON&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Compass - Aiming: &lt;strong>OFF&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Power Armor HUD: &lt;strong>Always On&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stealth Indicator: &lt;strong>Always On&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enemy Health: &lt;strong>Always On&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/immersive-hud-mcm.jpg" alt="Immersive HUD MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="photo-mode">Photo Mode&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Photo Mode Menu Position: &lt;strong>4&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Start Photo Mode: &lt;strong>P&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/photo-mode-mcm.jpg" alt="Photo Mode MCM">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="workshop-framework">Workshop Framework&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As the hint in the MCM suggests, the vanilla Shelter mechanic (where settlers&amp;rsquo; happiness is reduced if the game cannot detect a roof over their bed) is buggy. I prefer disabling it altogether:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Shelter Mechanic: &lt;strong>OFF&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Just build your settlers&amp;rsquo; beds somewhere below a roof to protect your immersion and ignore this buggy mechanic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/workshop-framework-mcm-1.jpg" alt="Workshop Framework MCM 1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Workshop Framework has a neat feature that automatically closes doors after a few seconds. Settlers are unfortunately able to open them, but will never close them again so you usually have all doors in your settlement standing wide open. Having them close automatically finally fixes that.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Door Management: &lt;strong>ON&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Auto-Close Delay: &lt;strong>10&lt;/strong> (seconds)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/workshop-framework-mcm-2.jpg" alt="Workshop Framework MCM 2">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, I highly recommend disabling the Manage Workbench prompt:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Manage Workbench &lt;strong>OFF&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The Manage menu accessible at workbenches is only for scrapping stuff placed by the player and the WF layouts feature. Since TPF Fallout 4 doesn&amp;rsquo;t currently include additional layouts, I would rather people disabled this entirely to prevent confusion. If you are interested in WF layouts, re-enable the Manage Workbench option and watch kinggath&amp;rsquo;s tutorials on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N3MGiari9xc&amp;amp;feature=emb_logo">importing&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9OVzgFzjnRw&amp;amp;feature=emb_logo">exporting&lt;/a> them. Obviously, downloading and installing layouts counts as adding mods and voids your right to get support for WTP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/documentation/workshop-framework-mcm-3.jpg" alt="Workshop Framework MCM 3">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fo4: Known Issues</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/known-issues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/known-issues/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="performance-issues">Performance Issues&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>WTP is a performance friendly setup and should run well for most users. In fact, thanks to the &lt;strong>Previsibines Repair Pack&lt;/strong>, it should run better than vanilla in some places. While WTP includes some 4K retextures, the Fallout 4 engine is actually capable of loading lower resolution versions of these when running out of VRAM. Almost all loose assets are packed into BA2 archives for better performance. I also took care not to include mods with long levelled lists containing new face presets as these can significant performance issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That being said, Fallout 4 is prone to performance issues, especially stuttering. For performance in general please keep in mind that resolutions above 1080p can incur a sizeable frame loss. 4K does not scale well. Having the game and/or MO2 installed on an HDD instead of an SSD may similarly cause frame drops or some stuttering.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are struggling with frame drops I would first recommend swapping to the &lt;strong>Performance INIs&lt;/strong>. You can find instructions &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/installation/#performance-inis">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are still unhappy about your framerate, you can disable the &lt;strong>ENB Binaries&lt;/strong> found under the &lt;strong>ROOT FOLDER&lt;/strong> separator in Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="nate-and-nora-have-brown-faces-in-the-character-creation">Nate and Nora have brown faces in the character creation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If Nate and Nora have brown faces in the character creation, you missed &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fallout-4/wtp/installation/#official-high-resolution-texture-pack">this step&lt;/a> instructing you NOT to install the Official High Resolution Texture Pack. Go back to the linked section, remove the HD DLC, and the issue will be gone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/brown-faces-issue.png" alt="Brown Faces">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="natenora-is-invisible-in-the-cryo-pod">Nate/Nora is invisible in the cryo pod&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;del>When skipping the pre war prologue, you may find your spouse&amp;rsquo;s body is invisible in their cryo pod. You can still interact with them to get their wedding ring. The problem is caused by Start Me Up and Previs Repair Pack and unfortunately I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet figured out how to fix it. Either the way, it&amp;rsquo;s a minor issue and definitely not gamebreaking.&lt;/del>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Should be fixed in more recent versions of PRP.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/appendix/invisible-spouse.jpg" alt="Invisible Spouse">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-stuck-when-interacting-with-a-terminal">Getting stuck when interacting with a terminal&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>This is not a WTP-specific issue.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Occasionally you may get stuck when attempting to access a terminal. This can be fixed by opening the console (tilde key, right above TAB on your keyboard) and typing in &lt;code>tcl&lt;/code>. Upon closing the console (hitting tilde again), you should be able to use the terminal. Remember to open the console and type in &lt;code>tcl&lt;/code> again to re-enable collision.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/appendix/stuck-terminal.jpg" alt="Stuck Terminal">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="subtitles-get-stuck-during-first-minutemen-quest">Subtitles get stuck during first Minutemen quest&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>This is not a WTP-specific issue.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When talking to Preston and Sturges in the Museum of Freedom, the subtitles usually get stuck for a time during the conversation. This happens in vanilla too and cannot be fixed as far as I know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/appendix/subtitles-stuck.jpg" alt="Subtitles Stuck">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="issues-with-the-pip-boy-map-when-playing-with-a-controller">Issues with the Pip-Boy map when playing with a controller&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By default, the Pip-boy UI is of a &lt;a href="https://staticdelivery.nexusmods.com/mods/1151/images/48758/48758-1609598190-107962601.jpeg">pitifully low resolution&lt;/a>. Unfortunately, increasing it will cause a bug when playing with a controller that restrict the cursor to the upper left corner on the Pip-boy map.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can work around this by turning off your controlling, opening your map, then turning it back on again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The alternative is to revert the high resolution tweak in the INI files. To do so, follow these instructions:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open the &lt;strong>INI Editor&lt;/strong> in Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>fallout4prefs.ini&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scroll down to the &lt;code>[Display]&lt;/code> section.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Revert the values for the Pip-boy height and width to the default (see below).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>uPipboyTargetHeight=700
uPipboyTargetWidth=876
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button at the bottom and close the window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/appendix/map-gamepad.jpg" alt="Map Cursor Stuck">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="flickering-puddles">Flickering puddles&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;del>This is a persistent issue with cubemaps. We have a fix for it, &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/46787">Fixed flickering puddles&lt;/a>, &lt;del>but the bug still occurs and I&amp;rsquo;m honestly clueless.&lt;/del> I fixed the fix in WTP 1.6 and it should be fine now although the flickering does still seem to happen during rain storms for whatever reason.&lt;/del>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;del>Puddles were removed altogether by &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/31991">Clarity - A Visual Overhaul&lt;/a> which was added in WTP 2.0 and should eliminate the issue for good.&lt;/del>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>As of WTP 2.5, puddles were re-enabled and should no longer flicker!&lt;/strong> This is possible thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/62207?">fadingsignal&amp;rsquo;s fix&lt;/a> and an ENB update.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="load-screens-appear-frozen">Load screens appear frozen&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In loading screens, there is no spinning object and the loading symbol is not animated. This is actually not a bug, but a feature. Disabling animations in loading screens apparently increases load times. It was done in the High FPS Physics Fix custom INI file.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="empty-crafting-bench-category">Empty crafting bench category&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Currently (since WTP 2.6?) there is an emtpy category in the Crafting (chem) Bench. If you click on it, you CANNOT back out again so please don&amp;rsquo;t click on. I hope to be able to fix this soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/empty-chem-bench-category.jpg" alt="Emtpy Chem Bench Category">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fo4: Changelog</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/changelog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/changelog/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="release-264">Release 2.6.4&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>09/09/2022&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added This Settlement Does Not Need Your Help - BS Defence Redone&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Missing Nukalurk Recipe Book&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Missing Nukalurk Recipe Book - Sorting Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Ketaros Missing Magazines&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Ketaros Missing Magazines - Sorting Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Ketaros Missing Magazines - WTP Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Shadow Boost FO4 to 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.2.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Far Object LOD Improvement Project to 2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Previsibines Repair Pack to 0.59.11&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Fall UI - No 3D in Barter Menu&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed wrong load order for Phoenix - Simple Crafting Stations.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed missing sorting tag for the Yellow Slicker Hat&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Changed sorting tag for Blood Packs from [Raw] to (Aid)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated terrain and object LOD&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-263">Release 2.6.3&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>23/08/2022&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Welcome to Paradise now has its own &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/63530">Nexus Page&lt;/a> as well as a beautiful &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fzO7F6JlIDI">video showcase&lt;/a> by DroppedIceCream!&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-1">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added LOOT Config Loader (MO2 Plugin)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Shadow Boost&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Ownership Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Better Weapon Diversity for CHW&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Better Weapon Diversity for CHW - WTP Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Perennial Power Armor - Lightweight Power Armor Rebalance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Perennial Power Armor - WTP Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Keep Radiants in the Commonwealth - UFO4P Version&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Blue&amp;rsquo;s Minutemen Flag Pack (Standalone)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Fixed Gobo Effects to 2.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Keep Radiants in the Commonwealth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cleaned out some redundant records from the Conflict Resolution Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-262">Release 2.6.2&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>18/08/2022&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>DoubleYou updated their LOD resources, so here&amp;rsquo;s new terrain and object LODs for you guys. Also reverted LOST Audio Tweaks&amp;rsquo; change to the low health heart beat sfx, as requested.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-2">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Optimized Vanilla Tree LODs to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Far Harbor 3D Tree LODs to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated terrain and object LOD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reverted low health heart beat sound fx behaviour to vanilla&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-261">Release 2.6.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>16/08/2022&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>All I wanted to do was fix WJ installations failing due to the xLODGen archives, but then DoubleYou went and published more LOD improvements, so I had to regenerate terrain and object LODs, and things kind of escalated from there. Anyway, this is a semi-minor update that is of course safe save and makes (distant) trees look better, especially on Far Harbor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>KNOWN ISSUE:&lt;/strong> Currently there is an empty category in the Crafting (chem) Bench. If you click it YOU CAN&amp;rsquo;T BACK OUT so, uhh, don&amp;rsquo;t click it. I have no idea what is causing it but I&amp;rsquo;ll investigate further.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-3">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added BSArchPro (irrelevant for users)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fall UI No 3D in Barter Menu&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Better Landscape Grass&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added NukaWorld HiRez FakeRocks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Drinkable Water Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Wasteland Workshop Snappable Posters&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Five Wall Corners&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Optimised Vanilla Tree LODs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Far Harbor 3D Tree LODs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Re-added Fixed Gobo Effects&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.2.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Fixed Alpha Maps to 6.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Targeted Textures to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Perk Up to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Retextured Water - By Ben Ephla&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed xLODGen archives that was causing installs to fail (sorry)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repacked the Texture Pack - Clutter BA2s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slightly modified the Upgradable Vault Suit crafting station category for consistency&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated terrain and object LOD&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Documentation:&lt;/strong> Minor updates for newly added mods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Known Issues:&lt;/strong> Added empty Crafting Bench category issue&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-26">Release 2.6&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>12/08/2022&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This update requires a new save.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WTP now features &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/62843">Perk Up - Lightweight Perk Overhaul&lt;/a>, one of a collection of mods by SpringHeelJon for his new Wabbajack list, &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/62880">FUSION&lt;/a>, which you should definitely check out!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also added &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/31720">Kezyma&amp;rsquo;s Root Builder&lt;/a> which means moving the Game Folder Files is no longer required. Instead, all files that need to be inside the root folder will be moved there by the plugin when you launch the game, and removed again when you close it. Existing WTP users should clear out existing GFF files from their root folder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also I finally got around to generating custom terrain and object LOD for this update.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-4">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added FO4LODGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Kezyma&amp;rsquo;s Root Builder (MO2 plugin)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Kezyma&amp;rsquo;s Profile Sync (MO2 plugin)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Targeted Textures - Vanilla Textures Upscaled Fixed and Sized&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Perk Up - Lightweight Perk Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added No Empty Med Cabinets (custom plugin)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Perk Up - Restore Power Armor Frames Patch (custom plugin)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FO4LODGen Resources&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added HD LOD Textures&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Modern House LOD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Far Object LOD Improvement Project&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added custom terrain and object LOD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Fixed Alpha Maps to 6.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lightweight Lighting to 2.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Upgradeable Vault Suit to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Previsibines Repair Pack to 0.59.10&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed deorder&amp;rsquo;s plugins&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Starlight Drive In LOD Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Nuka-World - Transit Center LOD Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Fixed Gobo Textures (included with Targeted Textures)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Far Harbor Pine Branches 4K (included with Targeted Textures)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Fix for Forsythia (included with Targeted Textures)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Easy Lockpicking and Hacking (replaced by Perk Up)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Fortune Finder 4 Fix (included in Perk Up)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Neura LOD (replaced by custom LODs)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="modifications">Modifications&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Forwarded various UFO4P edits&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added the [Raw] sorting tag to the Nukalurk Egg added by the UFO4P&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added new {Neck} tag with appropriate icon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed missing tags on Yao-guai Finger Necklace and Pack Feather Necklace&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Renamed some custom plugins&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ESL-flagged Some Assembly Required - WTP Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-1">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Installation:&lt;/strong> Removed Game Folder Files instructions (no longer necessary with Root Builder)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Installation:&lt;/strong> Removed Easy Lockpicking and Hacking section (mod removed in favour of Perk Up)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Documentation:&lt;/strong> Removed Game Folder Files section (no longer necessary with Root Builder)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Known Issues:&lt;/strong> Updated instructions on how to disable ENB in case of performance issues&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-25">Release 2.5&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>30/07/2022&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This update is coming with some site restructuring: The entire WTP documentation was moved to the new Fallout 4 Lists section and as a result, all links are broken. I fixed those I could find, let me know if you find any that are still leading into the void. I also took the opportunity to restructure the pages somewhat, particularly the Documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also removed the mod Facials for Everyone because of persistent performance issues. Fallout 4 has an issue where long levelled lists for NPC templates considerably degrade performance, so Facials offered a &amp;ldquo;lite&amp;rdquo; version with a shorter LList for that reason and WTP was using that. But I still got plenty of reports for stutters that were fixed by disabling facials and decided to boot the mod.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also puddles were re-enable and should no longer flicker. Yay!&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-5">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Simple Puddle Reflection Flicker Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Gloomy Glass - All Transparent Materials Revised&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Blasted Billboards - A Weathered Billboard Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Peeling Posters - Weathered Paper Based Signs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Frame Job - A Power Armor Frame Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Eyes of Beauty - SHJ Edit&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Dog Furniture Pack&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Previsibines Repair Pack - Hotfix 0.59.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated the Fallout 4 Script Extender to 0.6.23&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Spectrum ENB to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated the Unofficial Fallout 4 Patch to 2.1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated High FPS Physics Fix to 0.8.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Wetness Shader Fix to 3.6.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lightweight Lighting to 2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Ultimate Window Overhaul Redone to 4.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Curated Companions to Final&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Classic Holstered Weapons System to 1.06b&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Whisper&amp;rsquo;s Extra Pieces and Snaps to 2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Useful Posts to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated LOST Audio Tweaks to 3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Overboss Colter Fix (now obsolete)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Clarity - A Visual Overhaul - Material Edits&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed ADs 2X Rez HDTP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Power Armor Frame 4K UHD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed The Eyes of Beauty&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Facials for Everyone - Less Than Fresh Faces&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed WTP - Curated Companions Patch (no longer necessary)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repacked Texture Pack - Power Armor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed load order for SyringerAmmoSimplerIngredientsAlternate.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Re-enabled puddles which should now be flicker-free at last&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-2">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Installation:&lt;/strong> Moved Requirements here and added MO2 Prerequisites sub section&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Installation:&lt;/strong> Instructions for the CC Modular Military Backpack were rewritten and moved here&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Documentation:&lt;/strong> Merged several separate sites together into one longer documentation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Known Issues:&lt;/strong> Added &amp;ldquo;brown faces&amp;rdquo; problem and solution&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-24">Release 2.4&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>17/06/2022&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It was recently brought to my attention that some DLC weapons have completely broken names which turned out to have been due to a very silly oversight on my part. This update fixes that, but unfortunately it will not work retroactively. If you already went to Far Harbor and / or Nuka World, any weapons that already generated will have the incorrect names. Sorry about that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In other news, I added a few recent releases, mostly adding new snap points to meshes to make settlement building a smoother experience. Syringer ammo is now easier to craft (requiring base ingredients rather than Antifreeze Bottles etc) and will be sorted in their own roll-up (sub) menu in the Aid tab. You can quit accidentally poisoning yourself now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you don&amp;rsquo;t want to start a new game for this, you need to manually restart the quest for Diamond City Radio Extended ingame. Open the console and run the following two commands:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>stopquest radiodiamondcity
startquest radiodiamondcity
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-6">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Atom Cats Drag Race Start Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added CC&amp;rsquo;s UHD APC 4K (packed into a BA2)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Companion Thoughts Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Syringer Ammo Simpler Ingredients&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Proctor Teagan Sells BOS Clothing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Garden Plot Snap&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Useful Posts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Warehouse Corner Wall Snap&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Warehouse to Wall Snap&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Snappy Half Walls&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated BethINI to 3.6.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Cathedral Assets Optimizer to 5.3.13&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout 4 to 1.26.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Wetness Shader Fix to 3.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.2.1a&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated MCM Settings Manager to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Phoenix - Sorting Overhaul (see below)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated FallUI - Interface to 2.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated FallUI - HUD to 1.6b&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated FallUI - Confirm Boxes to 2.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated FallUI - Workbench to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Diamond City Radio Extended to 3.0.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated LOST Audio Tweaks - DCRE RAO Patch to 3.0.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated WTP MCM Presets (both regular and 21:9 versions)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated both sets of INI files with the new version of BethINI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed tbbmalloc.dll from Game Folder Files&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The tbbmalloc.dll is no longer required for Buffout. You can delete it from your root folder.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="sorting-overhaul">Sorting Overhaul&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added some Nuka World melee weapon paint job options missing in the main INNR record&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed broken names on Far Harbor / Nuka World weapons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed some insanely difficult to see errors in the scrap tags for three different Lit Cigar records&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-3">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/documentation/mcm-settings/">MCM Settings&lt;/a>: Updated for the new changes (specifically in the FallUI mod MCMs)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-233">Release 2.3.3&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>30/04/2022&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Small update. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s save-safe.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-7">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added DiamondTheWall Retexture (packed into a BA2)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added CC&amp;rsquo;s UHD UFO 4K (packed into a BA2)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Cathedral Asset Optimizer (irrelevant for users)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Cola Cars Overboss Fix to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Laser Weapons 1st Person Reposition to 1.5.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Wetness Shader Fix to 3.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Fallout 4 Ultimate Window Overhaul to 3.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Configurable Hotkeys to 6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Previsibines Repair Pack to 0.59.5&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-232">Release 2.3.2&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>03/04/2022&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Another minor update, mostly to address performance concerns and to fix ambient occlusion being enabled in the INIs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-8">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Overboss Colter Fix (used to be part or PRP)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.0.22&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Previsibines Repair Pack to 0.57.4.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Disabled ambient occlusion in the default INIs (it was accidentally left enabled in the previous update, sorry about that)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added a set of performance INIs that should yield a better framerate on lower end PCs&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-4">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Introduction:&lt;/strong> Moved the requirements here from the Installation page&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Installation:&lt;/strong> Added the Performance INI section&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>INI Files:&lt;/strong> Moved notes on INI settings to their own page&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Known Issues:&lt;/strong> Added &amp;ldquo;Performance Issues&amp;rdquo; section&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-231">Release 2.3.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>28/03/2022&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is a quick maintenance update for WTP because I&amp;rsquo;m a dummy and deleted the enbseries zip from the CDN. I did take the opportunity to add a new, high-res map retexture which required me to adjust the MCM settings for FallUI Map a bit. While I was at it, I changed the Wait hotkey to CTRL + T so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t accidentally trigger while renaming a weapon. Finally, I also regenerated INIs with the new version of BethINI, hope I didn&amp;rsquo;t forget about any custom tweaks. I may add performance INIs in the future if people find this set to be too demanding.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-9">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Glass Roofs Stop Rain and Snow - Vanilla Green House Roof&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Collection Improved Maps&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added NPC Accuracy Revised&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated WTP - MCM Settings Preset&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.0.21&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Natural Landscapes to 0.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Tune The Radios to 2.1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Previsibines Repair Pack to 1.57.4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated BethINI to 3.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed enbseries link which took down 2.3 (very sorry about that)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated INI files&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-5">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>GFF &amp;amp; INI Settings:&lt;/strong> Now documenting my INI tweaks on this page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>MCM Settings:&lt;/strong> Updated Baka Wait Anywhere settings and added FallUI Map settings.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-23">Release 2.3&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>27/02/2022&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>New save required.&lt;/strong> Please also overwrite the Game Folder Files!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This update adds a few cool new mods as well as some relevant updates.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The assorted radio mods were replaced with the combined &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/56898">Diamond City Radio Extended&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Visuals are now largely affected by &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/58028">Spectrum ENB&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/57680">Lightweight Lighting&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can now &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/57891">upgrade your vault suit&lt;/a> as you progress through the main quest!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/37180">Facials for Everyone&lt;/a> expands the face preset lists without affecting performance.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Please note that I have not tested this update extensively. That being said, I do not anticipate any major issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-10">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Spectrum ENB&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Lightweight Lighting - A Weather and Interior Lighting Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Imposing Gunner Skulls&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Facials For Everyone - Less Than Fresh Faces&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Curated Companions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added WTP - Curated Companions Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Upgradable Vault Suit&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added WTP - Upgradable Vault Suit Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Diamond City Radio Extended&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Radio AT - DCE RAO Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ENB Series to 0.468&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.0.20&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated What&amp;rsquo;s Your Name to 1.13.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Previsibines Repair Pack to 0.57.2/0.57.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed FallOpt ENB&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Flicker Fixer (incorporated in PRP)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Improved Map with Visible Roads&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed SeriouslySarcastic&amp;rsquo;s Immersive Companions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Better Settlers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed BS Defence&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed More Where That Came From - Diamond City Radio Edition&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed LOST Audio Tweaks - MWTCF DC Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Elvani&amp;rsquo;s Track Pack - Diamond City Radio&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Previs Repair Pack - Clarity Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heavily edited Clarity.esp, it now only removes puddles and iron sight DOF&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Disabled InputSwitch in Buffout (could cause some issues)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Easy Lockpicking and Hacking is now disabled by default&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place Everywhere mode is now on by default&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-6">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>With this update, I gave the website a much-needed once over. Most improvements are relatively minor and were not documented.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Introduction:&lt;/strong> Slightly restructured the page and updated the feature list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Installation:&lt;/strong> Consolidated all sub-pages to a single long one. Attempted to shorten it a little and fixed a few broken links.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Installation:&lt;/strong> Added instructions on how to enable Easy Lockpicking and Hacking.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mod Config:&lt;/strong> Removed step about applying FallUI HUD preset. Turns out the MCM preset already does it!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>WTP Visuals:&lt;/strong> Slightly updated the documentation. The screenshots are a tad outdated and will be replaced asap.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>WTP Gameplay:&lt;/strong> Slightly updated the documentation.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-22">Release 2.2&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>13/01/2022&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>With this update I am removing This Is Trash, WTP&amp;rsquo;s scrapping mod which should some performance issues and flickering. Neither This Is Trash nor Previs Repair Pack are causing this issue, but using both at the same time would require me to regenerate previs/precombines for places where they overlap if I wanted to avoid issues. To tell you the truth, the whole process is time-consuming and annoying, and I do not care enough about Fallout 4 modding to dive any deeper into this. Hence, the removal of This Is Trash.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In other news, I re-added Ultrawide (21:9) support. Folks with 2560x1080 or 3440x1440 monitor resolutions will now be able to play with a properly adjusted UI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This update is NOT save-safe.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remember to copy over Game Folder Files again to update the ENB preset.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-11">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added ENB Helper for Fallout 4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added MCM Booster&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added TruBy9 UltraWide Fallout 4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Welcome to Paradise - MCM Settings (21-9)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Minimalistic Main Menu&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mod Organizer to 2.4.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated FallOpt ENB to 2.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Natural Rocks to 0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Another Sanctuary Bridge (can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to redo precombines)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed This Is Trash (can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to redo precombines)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed Place Everywhere INI (keybinds were F2, F3 instead of F1, F2 - thanks, Dargor!)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Minor edits to the Conflict Resolution Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-7">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/installation/finalisation/">Finalisation&lt;/a>: Added section with instructions for ultrawide compatibility.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/mod-config/">Mod Config&lt;/a>: Updated the MCM preset instructions to account for the new 21:9 preset.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/wtp/installation/widescreen-main-menu.jpg" alt="Widescreen Main Menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="release-21">Release 2.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>25/12/2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is a small maintenance update, largely to bring you the recent FallOpt ENB improvements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This update is &lt;strong>save-safe&lt;/strong>. Please copy over game folder files once again as the ENB files updated.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-12">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.0.18a&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated MCM Settings Manager to 1.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated LOST - Audio Tweaks to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Previsibines Repair Pack to 0.53.12012021&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated FallOpt ENB to 2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Hush Dogmeat (integrated in LOST - Audio Tweaks)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enabled HBAO in fallout4prefs.ini (ambient occlusion)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Changed MO2 separator colours again&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New Wabbajack cover image&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-20">Release 2.0&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>01/12/2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A new save is required.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Welcome to Paradise 2.0 goes back to the roots. The list was refocused to vanilla improvements with a great deal of sorely needed back-end changes, including a full rebuild with detailed documentation of all edits in Mod Organizer 2. Lingering issues and annoyances from previous versions (that I know of) were eliminated with the result being an overall more consistent, polished experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>New lighting and ENB combination for more consistent visuals as well as brighter nights and interiors.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Better shadow INI settings to reduce pop-in and blurry shadows (thanks SpringHeelJon!).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Replaced Boston FPS Fix with Previs Pack to eliminate some crashes and improve performance in even more areas.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Replaced Workshop Re-arranged with smaller, more managable workshop additions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New retextures, most of which were added to the WTP texture packs for better performance.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MCM settings can now be applied automatically via a universal WTP preset thanks to MCM Settings Manager.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finally some documentation in the form of the new &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/documentation/wtp-visuals/">WTP Visuals&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/documentation/wtp-gameplay/">WTP Gameplay&lt;/a> pages.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>ENB and lighting changes:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In WTP 2.0, I removed &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/4472">True Storms&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/9253">True Nights&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/5885">Subtle ENB&lt;/a>. The decision was not easy as I have never really played Fallout 4 &lt;em>without&lt;/em> True Storms, and I really love the murky nights with this combination of mods. Unfortunately, True Storms makes the game&amp;rsquo;s lackluster occlusion effect (intended to prevent rain and fogs in interiors) even more noticable. I also had a ton of people complain about dark nights.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this update, WTP is switching to &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/31991">Clarity&lt;/a> for some fantastic all around improvements to visuals as well as the lightweight &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/55662">FallOpt ENB&lt;/a> preset. This combination also mostly replaced &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/8768">Interiors Enhanced&lt;/a> which means that interiors are a little brighter now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Removal of CBBE and EVB:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I ended up removing the body replacers in this update. There is simply nothing I really need CBBE for and EVB male bodies do not have dismemberment support.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Removal of Workshop Re-arranged:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Workshop Re-arranged is a pretty great workshop overhaul. Unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s also extremely difficult to work with on account of its rebalancing edits which change many of the building requirements as well as junk scrap yields. I finally decided to ditch the mod and return to smaller, individual workshop additions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>BOS Power Armor Paint Jobs:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I realised that without the stat changes, there is no need to have separate Knight/Paladin/Sentinel paint jobs for the power armor as they are visually identical. The exception is the Left Arm piece which displays the rank insignia. I rectified this by adding a single &amp;ldquo;Brotherhood of Steel&amp;rdquo; paint job that can be applied to any piece of power armor, then limiting the rank-specific paint job to Left Arm pieces. Problem solved!&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-13">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>New Additions&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added FallOpt ENB&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added MCM Settings Manager&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fallout Priority - F4SE Plugin (may be placebo)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added NPC Drinking Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fixed Textures for Mirelurk Egg Omelette&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Institute Floor Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Automatron Load Screen Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added No Negative Affinity&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added No Negative Affinity DLC Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added No Crafting Experience&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added No Holotape Tease - Texture Replacement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Base Scrap Is Not Junk Jet Ammo (custom)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added NPC Protection Tweaks (custom)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Atmospheric Animated Menu Replacer (Night Version)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Clarity - A Visual Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added NMC&amp;rsquo;s Texture Bundle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Redder Red Rocket&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Subway Transit Sign HD Texture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added CC&amp;rsquo;s Vertibirds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Nuka Project&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Scrap Metal and Makeshift Welds - A Pipe Gun Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Duffle Bag Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added U.S. Covert Operations Manual Revised - Magazine Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Pipboy UHD - Holotape&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vault Suits UHD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added CC&amp;rsquo;s UHD Bloatflies - Reimagined&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Immersive Mouth and Teeth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Valkyr Female Body Textures&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Baka Wait Anywhere&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Easy Lockpicking and Hacking&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Consume Without Pickup&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Moonracer&amp;rsquo;s Armor Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Some Assembly Required - Atom Cats CPAO Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Locked Vault Tec Paint Job&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Locked Abraxo and Sugar Bombs Power Armor Paints&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added No PA Battery Pathing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Power Grid Tools&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Improved Workshop Lights&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Better Workshop Street Oil Lamps&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added DLC Light Radius Redux&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Wasteland Workshop Street Lamp and Ceiling Light Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Better Generators (x2)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Tune the Radios&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Shackin&amp;rsquo; Up - A Prefab Shack Mod&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Whisper&amp;rsquo;s Extra Pieces and Snaps&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Snappable Junk Fences&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added No More Gaps Under Junk Fences&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Graf&amp;rsquo;s Security Fences&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Craftable Turret Stands&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Wall Oil Lamps&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Better Workshop Street Oil Lamps - Wall Oil Lamps Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Pip-Boy Retextured&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added LOST Audio Tweaks - MWTCF DC Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Previs Repair Pack&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Updated Mods&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated ENBSeries binaries (no version number change)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated xSE Plugin Preloader F4 to 0.2.5.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout to 1.24.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout TBB Redistributables to 2021.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated High FPS Physics Fix to 0.8.4-5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Laser Weapons 1st Person Reposition to 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated WET - Water Enhancement Textures to 2.0.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Retro Radio Replacer to 0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Visible Idle Markers to 3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated BS Defence to 2.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated LOST Audio Tweaks to 2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated FO4Edit to 4.0.4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Removed Mods&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Subtle ENB&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Jamaica Plain Navmesh Fix (fix included in UFO4P)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Corpse Collision&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed No More Glowing Water Coolers (replaced by Clarity)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Fixed Flickering Puddles (Clarity removes the puddles)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed No Lockpick Activate (F4SE)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Depth of Field (DOF) Removal&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Valdacil&amp;rsquo;s Item Sorting - Perks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Main Menu Music Replacer - Wandering The Foothills&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed True Storms - Wasteland Edition&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed True Nights&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Interiors Enhanced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vehicle Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Really Red Rocket&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Authentic Hand-Made Weapons (removed from the Nexus)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed U.S. Covert Operations Manual - Magazine Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Proto Vault Suit&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Better Recon Scope&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Spiffy&amp;rsquo;s Workshop - Forged in Nuclear Fire - HQ Liberty Prime Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed CC&amp;rsquo;s UHD Bloatflies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Distinct Teeth for FO4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Caliente&amp;rsquo;s Beautiful Bodies Enhancer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Kellogg&amp;rsquo;s Gloves for CBBE Clipping Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Skeletal Adjustments for CBBE - Knee Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed CBBE Ida Body Texture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Enhanced Vanilla Bodies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Auto Hack&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Auto Lockpicking&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Better Explosives Redux (too overpowered)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Unique X-01&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed No Quest Autostart - BOS Fire Support&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Main Quest Choices Extended&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Nuka World Collectable Quest Markers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Corrunda&amp;rsquo;s Red Rocket - Light and Curb Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Fixed and Cleaned Homeplate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vault 88 Template - Optimised&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Obedient Concord Group (toggleable with Visible Idle Markers)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Workshop Re-arranged&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Grab The Damn Mag (not adding custom weapons)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed RAO - True Storms Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Game Configuration Menu (replaced with individual tweaks)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Boston FPS Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Boston FPS Fix - Hotfix for UFO4P 2.1.1a&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed River Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Other Edits&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Rebuilt all custom texture pack BA2s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Some retextures were increased from 2K to 4K&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Packed up ADs 2X Rez HDTP in a BA2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Switched to the merged legendary patch version of Some Assembly Required&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heavily edited the CRP (many patches are now separate)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Disabled ambient occlusion in the Fallout4Prefs.ini (in favour of ENB AO)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Increased fBlendSplitDirShadow from 48 to 96 in Fallout4Prefs.ini&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Increased iDirShadowSplits from 2 to 3 in Fallout4Prefs.ini&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Now using the HighFPSPhysicsFix_custom.ini feature&lt;/li>
&lt;li>My BAT files for testing are no longer included&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Changed interface color to a muted green matching the Pip-Boy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New separator colours in MO2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added MO2 Loot Preventifier (plugin by LostDragonist)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sort button above the load order in MO2 was removed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Installed NifSkope as an additional tool&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-8">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/installation/finalisation/">Finalisation&lt;/a>: Removed the LUTs section&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/installation/finalisation/">Finalisation&lt;/a>: Removed VSYNC section (it is now always enabled as it should be)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/installation/finalisation/">Finalisation&lt;/a>: Updated the FPS Cap section including the screenshot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/mod-config/">Mod Config&lt;/a>: Completely overhauled this page to account for automatic MCM settings loading and the new mods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed the Resources section&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added the Documentation section&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/documentation/game-folder-files/">Game Folder Files&lt;/a>: Updated the page with the latest additions and changes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/documentation/wtp-visuals/">WTP Visuals&lt;/a>: Added page to discuss WTP&amp;rsquo;s graphics mods, including a list of textures in the five WTP repacks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/documentation/wtp-gameplay/">WTP Gameplay&lt;/a>: Added page to discuss WTP&amp;rsquo;s gameplay changes, including custom hotkeys and unique item locations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Renamed the &amp;ldquo;Troubleshooting&amp;rdquo; page to &amp;ldquo;Known Issues&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/known-issues/">Known Issues&lt;/a>: Added &amp;ldquo;Invisible Spouse&amp;rdquo; bug&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/known-issues/">Known Issues&lt;/a>: Updated the &amp;ldquo;Flickering Puddles&amp;rdquo; bug, eliminated in WTP 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/known-issues/">Known Issues&lt;/a>: Removed the &amp;ldquo;Nights are too dark&amp;rdquo; section (they are no longer as dark in WTP 2.0)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/known-issues/">Known Issues&lt;/a>: Added the &amp;ldquo;Load screens appear frozen&amp;rdquo; issue (which is not actually an bug)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="release-163">Release 1.6.3&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>14/08/2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This update finally brings back WTP after an extended downtime due to Nexit. I was extremely unhappy to remove the Stormy Nights main menu replacer and Full Dialogue Interface (for which the string patch was taken down), but there is nothing to be done. I apologise that it took me so long to bring WTP back, it remains more of a smaller side project for me and sadly I have not felt the Fallout 4 itch in quite some time. Nevertheless, the list has always been doing surprisingly well, much better than I had expected, so I will definitely continue to maintain it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is update is &lt;strong>not save-safe&lt;/strong>. Please copy over the Game Folder Files into your root folder once again as the ENB binaries were updated.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-14">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Disabled frame limit in enblocal.ini (oversight from when I reinstalled ENBSeries in 1.6.2)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enabled VSYNC in High FPS Physics Fix (should always be on)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed the main menu replacer as it was deleted from the Nexus (damn shame, it&amp;rsquo;s been my favourite for years)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed More Attackers - Get Off My Buildzone as a master from the CRP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed More Attackers - Get Off My Buildzone (removed from the Nexus)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Full Dialogue Interface&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed String Patches for Full Dialogue Interface (removed from the Nexus)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed F4 Creation Kit Fixes from Game Folder Files&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ENBSeries binaries to 0.461&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.0.16&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Synthkind Redefined HD to 1.01&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated What&amp;rsquo;s Your Name to 1.12.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Vault 88 Essentials to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Extended Dialogue Interface&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-162">Release 1.6.2&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>27/06/2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is just a quick update to fix two minor issues and update a couple of mods. Since Wabbajack updated to 2.5.0.0, I had to recompile anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Update your &lt;strong>Game Folder Files&lt;/strong> to get the new ENBSeries binaries. The update is &lt;strong>save safe&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-15">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated ENBSeries to 0.458&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated the Unofficial Fallout 4 Patch to 2.1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout to 1.23.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.0.15a&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated FallUI - Inventory to 1.13.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated FallUI - HUD to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Console Commands Extender to 1.2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Maybe fixed UI elements sometimes being misaligned&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed a few minor issues in Home Plate (thanks C19i)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-161">Release 1.6.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>04/06/2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>As it turns out, I got sloppy last night. I&amp;rsquo;d already recompiled once when &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/41178">Bullet Counted Reload System&lt;/a> updated and part of the update was support for &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/49444">Tactical Reload&lt;/a>. I dropped in both, did a cursory check in xEdit, fixed some conflicts, and called it a day. Evidently I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have done that as something about the combination has caused frequent crashes in WTP 1.6 that was reported twice so far and I was able to reproduce it on my end. Dropping Tactical Reload fixed it so at least there was an easy solution. I haven&amp;rsquo;t investigated further why exactly the crashes happen because I frankly don&amp;rsquo;t care about the mod that much and don&amp;rsquo;t have time today either.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This update is &lt;strong>save safe&lt;/strong>. It&amp;rsquo;s a crash fix. You&amp;rsquo;ll be asked about missing plugins when loading your save, click Yes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-16">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Tactical Reload&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Replaced the TR version of BCR Lever Action Rifle with the regular one&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Tactical Reload as a master from the CRP&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-16">Release 1.6&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>03/06/2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Starting a new game is required.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For this update I checked out the new &lt;strong>FallUI&lt;/strong> suite of interface replacers and took the opportunity to review WTP&amp;rsquo;s existing interface mods. I came to the decision to once again remove &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/27216">Extended Dialogue Interface&lt;/a> and revert to &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/1235">Full Dialogue Interface&lt;/a> which I like far better. After careful consideration, I decided &lt;em>against&lt;/em> including &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/51813">FallUI - HUD&lt;/a> because even with my DEF_UI HUD preset, it would make item pickup prompts look &lt;a href="https://i.imgur.com/Bd9w9VZ.jpg">weird&lt;/a> with a huge gap between the item name and the button prompts. I also removed FallUI - Map because I didn&amp;rsquo;t like it. However, FallUI - HUD and FallUI - Map are still going to be installed in case someone wants them (but are disabled by default).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also removed &lt;strong>Widescreen&lt;/strong> support. I can&amp;rsquo;t test it, it&amp;rsquo;s additional headache, I&amp;rsquo;d have to write extra instructions for changing the aspect ratio in the various FallUI MCMs. Sorry to everyone on ultrawide monitors, it&amp;rsquo;s just not worth the effort to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When updating, please also move the Game Folder Files into your root folder and overwrite (ENB binaries updated).&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-17">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added zEdit (I needed it for one merge)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added deorder&amp;rsquo;s MO2 Plugins (only useful for me)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added F4 Creation Kit Fixes (only useful for me)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added DEF_HUD - My Preset (smaller vanilla, crosshair to dot)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Tactical Reload&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Jamaica Plain Navmesh Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Weston Water LOD Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Assaultron Left Hand Hydraulic Frame Arm Mesh Bug Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Perception Bug Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Carlisle Typewriter Mesh Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Car Physics Death Bug Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added 1 Rad Bugfix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Far Harbor Marine Armor Boots Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Cryo Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Cryolator Cryo-Cell Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Pool Rack Fix (finally the game is playable)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added X-01 Power Armor Neck and Minor Light FX Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FallUI - HUD (disabled by default)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Full Dialogue Interface&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added String Patches for Full Dialogue Interface&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added UNLIMITED POWER - Tesla Rifle Projectiles Create Visual Effect on Impact&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fix for Forsythia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Far Harbor Pine Branches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Natural Bundle - Masonry Set&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Natural Bundle - Submarine Set&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Defined Hightech Floor Tiles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fix for Tiles02&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added ADs 2X Rez&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Wall Worldmap&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Globes (retexture)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Library and Subway Tokens HD Remastered&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Deathclaws HD Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Flamer Project&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Leafblower Junk Jet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Synthkind Redefined&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Auto Lockpick&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Auto Hack&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Better Explosives Redux&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fortune Finder 4 Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vault 88 Template - Optimised&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Workshop Power Pack&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vault 88 Essentials&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vault 88 Essentials - WTP Tweaks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Whose Quest Is It Anyway&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added River Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mod Organizer 2 to 2.4.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ENBSeries to 0.455&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout to 1.23.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Bullet Counted Reload System to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.0.14a&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Wetness Shader Fix to 3.41&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Companion Stealth Distance Fix to 7.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated FallUI Confirm Boxes to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated FallUI Workbench to 1.2.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Fallout 4 Ultimate Window Overhaul to 3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Visible Idle Markers to 1.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated LOST Audio Tweaks to 1.7a&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated the LOST Audio Tweaks - True Storms and RAO Patch to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Extended Dialogue Interface&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Scrolling Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Change PoV&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Valentine Jaw Sync (part of Synthkind Redefined)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Weapon Rack Fixes (largely covered by UFO4P)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Detailed Deathclaws&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Fallout 3 NV Feral Ghouls Replacer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Simple Crafting Station - K-9 Harness Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Sprint Engine Limitations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reinstalled Fixed Flickering Puddles (was missing one file, may fix lingering issues)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FallUI - Map is now disabled by default&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rebuilt the Weapons BA2s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rebuilt the Creatures BA2s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deleted the broken IMAD record in True Nights to be on the safe side (I tweaked it before but can&amp;rsquo;t remember how)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated precombines for the area around the new Sanctuary bridge (thanks for talking me through that, Lively!)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Fortune Finder tweaks from Loot Logic Scrounger Fortune Finder Rebalance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reverted UNLIMITED POWER changes to Tesla Rifle damage, capacity, and reload speed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added new &amp;lsquo;Backpack&amp;rsquo; tag to DEV_INV_TAGS.xml&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Merged the three music plugins together and removed the separate plugins&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Replaced the now redundant music patch with the merged plugin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extracted the Fallout Suite BA2 since there is no longer a plugin to load it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed some conflicts between Better Explosives Redux and other mods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated INI files from scratch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>K-9 Harness&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Until now fadingsignal&amp;rsquo;s K-9 Harness for Dogmeat could be crafted at the crafting station which was the original implementation. I have never been happy with this and in this update I finally did something about it. You can now find exactly &lt;em>one&lt;/em> K-9 Harness in the world. The location happens to be a police station for obvious reasons - if you want to know where exactly you can find it, double-click the new K-9 Integration Patch in Mod Organizer 2 and check the &lt;strong>Notes&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Creation Club&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WTP 1.6 adds &lt;em>optional&lt;/em> support for some &amp;ldquo;creations&amp;rdquo; (only the Modular Military Backpack so far). You can find details and instructions &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fallout-4/wtp/wtp-resources/creation-club">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-9">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated a bunch of pages. Added stuff on the &lt;strong>Finalisation&lt;/strong> page. Don&amp;rsquo;t remember everything.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added a link for LostDragonist&amp;rsquo;s Steam Library Setup Tool on the &lt;strong>Fallout 4&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Widescreen support stuff from the &lt;strong>Finalisation&lt;/strong> page (sorry).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added new &lt;strong>Creation Club&lt;/strong> page under Resources for Modular Military Backpack support.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed the Custom Files page. All relevant documentation was moved into Mod Organizer 2 (check the Notes for each mod).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Linked to True Nights for instructions on how to change night brightness on &lt;strong>Troubleshooting&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-152">Release 1.5.2&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>06/04/2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This update is safe-save. Copy over the GFF into your root folder and overwrite (ENB binaries updated).&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-18">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Mod Organizer 2 to 2.4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Re-arranged and re-coloured MO2 separators&lt;/li>
&lt;li>WTP changelogs are no longer available through MO2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ENBSeries (no version change)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout 4 to 1.22.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated PrivateProfileRedirector to 0.5.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated High FPS Physics Fix to 0.8.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated What&amp;rsquo;s Your Name to 1.12.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Less Annoying Water Foam Circles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added No Quest Autostart - BoS Fire Support&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added No Quest Autostart - Automatron&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added No Quest Autostart - Vault-Tec&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added No Quest Autostart - Far Harbor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added No Quest Autostart - Nuka World&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed some unnecessary stuff from the Phoenix Tweaks plugin&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-10">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Finalisation:&lt;/strong> Shortened the Resolution section and moved Ultrawide tweaks to this page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ultrawide:&lt;/strong> Removed this page.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Turns out that Wabbajack auto-sets the resolution in the INI files.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="release-151">Release 1.5.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>08/03/2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I fixed some errors in &lt;code>Power Armor Lore-Friendly Distribution.esp&lt;/code> by reverting the levelled lists for Atom Cats power armor to vanilla. That means they&amp;rsquo;ll be wearing T-60 armor again (instead of T-51). I know I had Atom Cats T-51 armor &lt;em>somewhere&lt;/em> but it seems to have gotten lost, resulting in these errors. I fully admit that this is a lazy solution but it works and that was always enough for Todd anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While recompiling for WJ, I also updated the links to the website (see below).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="global-site-update">Global Site Update&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>08/03/2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I finally did some spring cleaning. For the longest time it annoyed me that in my original folder structure I had categorised pages by games, for example the TPF part of the website was called &amp;ldquo;Skyrim SE&amp;rdquo; in the top menu. But what if I want to start another SE project? And you don&amp;rsquo;t want to know the chaos in my pictures folder either.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The reason I hesitated for so long to change the folder names is because it breaks every, single, link. And while fixing the internal links and file paths was merely a minor annoyance, fixing all external links is more difficult - especially considering that other people may link to TPF as well and those links are now broken. Of course I also need to recompile both TPF and WTP for Wabbajack to update the links that open automatically upon installing a Wabbajack list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I finally updated now and I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with the changes. It likely will take some time for all external links to get fix plus I suspect I may have missing some internal links and file paths.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="changes">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed the Bioware section (see below).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Renamed &amp;ldquo;Skyrim SE&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;The Phoenix Flavour&amp;rdquo; (link changed from skyrim-se to tpf).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Renamed &amp;ldquo;Fallout 4&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Welcome to Paradise&amp;rdquo; (link changed from fallout to wtp).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated all internal links and file paths - hopefully.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cleaned up my pictures folder to remove any pictures that are no longer in the guide.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated the home page, it has two buttons now and a combination of the TPF and WTP pics.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="bioware">Bioware&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The current state of things is that I have published a guide for ME1 with a draft for an ME2 version waiting for revision. But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: Modding Bioware games is quite different from modding Bethesda games. I&amp;rsquo;ve only really dipped my toes in it and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t call myself an expert by any stretch of the imagination. Something I often criticise about various smaller Skyrim modding &amp;ldquo;guides&amp;rdquo; is that their authors barely know what they&amp;rsquo;re doing. It occured to me that my Mass Effect &amp;ldquo;guides&amp;rdquo; are in essence the same thing &lt;del>with better formatting&lt;/del>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To keep a longer story short, I have developed a strong sense of imposter syndrome over those excursions into Bioware land that is causing me a fair amount of stress. Something I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the past couple years is that if you have too many things putting pressure on you at once, cut out everything that&amp;rsquo;s non-essential. Well, this time the scissors are for the Bioware section of the TPF website.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="release-15">Release 1.5&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>06/03/2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-19">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Mod Organizer 2 to 2.4.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tweaked Pipboy INI settings (increased resolution, disabled fx)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Mator&amp;rsquo;s xEdit Patching Framework&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FO4Edit cache is now saved into the Tools\FO4Edit folder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated xSE Plugin Preloader to 0.2.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Changed xSE Plugin Preloader load method to OnThreadAttach&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout to 1.20.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated the Unofficial Fallout 4 Patch to 2.1.2b&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated High FPS Physics Fix to 0.8.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed additional High FPS Physics Fix INIs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Default settings for WTP are now 60FPS and no VSYNC&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Documentation includes instructions to change the settings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reinstalled DEF_UI and only chose DEF_HUD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reverted to vanilla DEF_UI profile&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FallUI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FallUI Workbench&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FallUI Map&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Re-added LooksMenu&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Better Confirm Boxes for PC&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added TRUBY9 ULTRAWIDE DEF_UI Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Better Confirm Boxes for PC - Widescreen Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Neutral Look Up Tables LUT&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fallout 4 Enhanced Color Correction&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Retro Radio Replacer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Classic Wasteland Survival Guide - Magazine Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added U.S. Covert Operations Manual - Magazine Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Total Hack - Magazine Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Hunting Rifle Set&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Ballistic Series&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fixed Creature Death Drops&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FO4 Photo Mode&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.0.10&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simple Sorting Overhaul to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Wetness Shader Fix to 3.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Sprint Stuttering Fix to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Hazmat Suit Redux to 0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skeletal Adjustments for CBBE to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated What&amp;rsquo;s Your Name to 1.11.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Fixed and Cleaned Homeplate to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated LOST Audio Tweaks to 1.6.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated LOST Audio Tweaks - True Storms and RAO Patch to Beta&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Pip-Boy Dual Color section&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Small Map Markers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed The Humble Hunting Rifle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed ScratchMade - New Combat Shotgun and Rifle Textures&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed The Top-Notch Tommy Gun&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Assault Rifle Retexture 2K&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed HUD Customisation stuff&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repacked the Clutter BA2s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repacked the Weapon BA2s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Changed ENB hotkeys to mirror TPF&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="simple-sorting-overhaul">Simple Sorting Overhaul&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>As we have now switched to FallUI from DEF_INV, I updated my INNRs (naming rules) to have the same format as Ruddy&amp;rsquo;s sorting patcher that FallUI was intended for. That means mods for armors and weapons will be displayed in smaller font below the item name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did take a look at the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/48826">Complex Sorter&lt;/a> for FallUI which would be very convenient for me but ultimately I prefer my own icons and INNRs. Plus they already cover my power armor changes and include my preferred power armor naming scheme.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-11">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I went over all pages and fixed what I thought needed fixing. Screenshots were updated, sentences were rephrased, and instructions were clarified.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Finalisation:&lt;/strong> Added instructions for the optional LUTs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Finalisation:&lt;/strong> Added Controller Fix instructions (required because of an issue with FallUI).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Finalisation:&lt;/strong> Expanded FPS and VSYNCs instructions (they are DIY now).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Game:&lt;/strong> Removed Hotkey instructions. No longer necessary with TPF ENB hotkeys.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mod Configuration:&lt;/strong> Added instructions for Photo Mode.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Renamed the &amp;ldquo;Documentation&amp;rdquo; section to &amp;ldquo;Resources&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ultrawide:&lt;/strong> Moved this page to the Resources section.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Customisation:&lt;/strong> Removed this section. Use the FallUI MCM to customise your UI.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Troubleshooting:&lt;/strong> Added a note about flickering puddles.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-141">Release 1.4.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>26/11/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-20">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Re-enabled Authentic Handmade Weaponry (accidentally disabled the plugin in 1.4)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-14">Release 1.4&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>23/11/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-21">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Weapon Debris Crash Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Sprint Stuttering Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Less Ugly Intercom&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Laser Series&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Plasma Project&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed The Lavish Laser Musket&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed The Lavish Laser Collection&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rebuilt the Weapons BA2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout to 1.17.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Wetness Shader Fix to 3.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Handmade Turrets to 1.3.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.0.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Indubitably Ivy to 0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated What&amp;rsquo;s Your Name to 1.10.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skeletal Adjustments for CBBE - Knee Fix to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated LOST Audio Tweaks to 1.5.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated custom Sound Slider Tweaks plugin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slightly tweaked High FPS Physics Fix presets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Unhid message box and tutorial messages in my DEF_UI preset&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-131">Release 1.3.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>24/10/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Just a minor fix and clean-up for yesterday&amp;rsquo;s update.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-22">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Bullet Counted Reload System to 1.05b&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Workshop Framework to 2.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added missing ALWAYS INCLUDE flags to High FPS Physics Fix profiles&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-13">Release 1.3&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>23/10/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This update fixes a number of issues reported by users (thanks, guys!). I am also officially changing the list name to &lt;strong>Welcome to Paradise&lt;/strong>. The website, Discord channels, and Mod Organizer 2 profile have all been edited accordingly.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-23">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Hopefully fixed radio songs not playing for good&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated xSE Plugin Preloader to 0.2.3 (XML unchanged, let me know if there are issues)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout 4 to 1.16.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed some untranslated UI bits (missing strings)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Auto Gamepad Switch (caused some issues)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed scrap tag for Stogie&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added High FPS Physics Fix plus pre-configured INIs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed the separate DEF_UI preset, now editing the one packaged with the main mod&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Re-enabled compass markers for locations / Dogmeat / PA in DEF_UI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turns out Archive2 is unreliable so I repacked a bunch of BA2s with CAO&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Unpacked custom BA2 for Bleak Beauty, Musical Lore, More Where That Came From, and Elvani&amp;rsquo;s Track Pack&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed some purple cars by reverting them to vanilla, it&amp;rsquo;s a band-aid fix but the best I could do&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-12">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Finalisation:&lt;/strong> Removed instructions for NVIDIA Inspector.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Finalisation:&lt;/strong> Added instructions for the newly-added High FPS Physics Fix and my pre-configured INIs.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-121">Release 1.2.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>01/10/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-24">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Actually fixed radio tracks not playing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated xSE Plugin Preloader to 0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Please delete &lt;strong>xSE PluginPreloader.ini&lt;/strong> from your &lt;strong>root&lt;/strong> folder. Move the new &lt;strong>xSE PluginPreloader.xml&lt;/strong> and updated &lt;strong>IpHlpAPI.dll&lt;/strong> into your &lt;strong>root&lt;/strong> folder and overwrite when prompted.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="release-12">Release 1.2&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>30/09/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-25">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout to 1.12.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Placed the new Buffout TBB Redist plugin in the Game Folder Files folder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Achievements (this is now a feature in Buffout)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Actually fixed the problematic True Nights record instead of bruteforce deleting it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Classic Hostered Weapons System to 1.04c&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Start Me Up - Basic Version&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Lively&amp;rsquo;s Start Me Up Tweak&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Resolved a conflict between Start Me Up and the UFO4P&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Inlined Lively&amp;rsquo;s PPPL INI file&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Sweet Roll 5000 and rebuilt Clutter BA2s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed Diamond City Radio tracks not playing (thanks Archie!)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-13">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/installation/finalisation/">Finalisation&lt;/a>: Added this new page and moved the game resolution instructions here.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/installation/finalisation/">Finalisation&lt;/a>: Added instructions on how to force VSYNC and cap the framerate.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/installation/new-game/">New Game&lt;/a>: Removed LooksMenu related instructions as that mod was removed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/installation/new-game/">New Game&lt;/a>: Added &lt;em>seriously&lt;/em> detailed instructions for Start Me Up.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-11">Release 1.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>27/09/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="mod-changes-26">Mod Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Now using Lively&amp;rsquo;s pppl.ini file&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Buffout to 1.11.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed one record from True Nights which can cause memory corruption according to Buffout&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed LooksMenu (don&amp;rsquo;t really need it anyway)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enabled the Classic Holstered Weapons Systems patch in Buffout&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adjusted loot / interact prompt and window position in my DEF_UI preset&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Switched to the Alternative Version of Fixed Flickering Puddles (hopefully fixing black pre-war Codsworth)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Skip raiding your own settlements (no time to troubleshoot the compilation error it causes)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="website-changes-14">Website Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/installation/wabbajack/">Wabbajack&lt;/a>: Added new section on how change the game resolution.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/appendix/troubleshooting/">Troubleshooting&lt;/a>: Added this page with a few known issues.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-101">Release 1.0.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>26/09/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Rolled back to &lt;strong>Buffout 4&lt;/strong> 1.7.0 as the latest version is causing crashes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="release-10">Release 1.0&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>26/09/2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Initial release. For more info check the &lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/phoenix-flavour-42049352">Patreon post&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fo4: Credits</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/credits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/fo4/wtp/credits/</guid><description>
&lt;h4 id="mod-list-curated-and-maintained-by-phoenix">Mod list curated and maintained by Phoenix.&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/users/1872172">Lively&lt;/a> for your help with earlier versions of WTP. You got the list going!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thanks to Halgari and the crew for creating Wabbajack. Please considering supporting Wabbajack on &lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/user?u=11907933">Patreon&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/users/6835982">SpringHeelJon&lt;/a> for your fantastic mods and your continued support for WTP.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/users/17506149">HoosteenElGuero&lt;/a> for &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/16541">Disable Dismemberment By Weapon&lt;/a> of which a tweaked, merged version is included.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/users/33123946">Herby&lt;/a> for &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/41121">LootBalance&lt;/a> of which an older, tweaked version is included.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thanks to the authors of all tools used in the creation of this list, especially &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/6194">Mod Organizer 2&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/2737">FO4Edit&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/67">BethINI&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thanks to the authors of all mods featured in the mod list, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t exist without you!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thanks to all the wonderful folks on our Discord server and especially my supporters on &lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/thephoenixflavour">Patreon&lt;/a>. &amp;lt;3&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>