<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Phoenix Flavour – Finalisation</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/</link><description>Recent content in Finalisation on The Phoenix Flavour</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tpf: Wrapping Up</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/wrapping-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/wrapping-up/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="conflict-resolution-patch">Conflict Resolution Patch&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Create a &lt;strong>FINAL PATCHES&lt;/strong> separator in Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Download the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/14223?tab=files">Conflict Resolution Patch&lt;/a> from the guide’s Nexus page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Install it as usual, place it last below the &lt;strong>FINAL PATCHES&lt;/strong> separator, and activate it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="load-order-txt">Load Order TXT&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The pre-made TXT will arrange your plugins exactly like the way they are sorted in my personal setup. This is much faster than adjusting the load order manually or setting up LOOT with custom rules.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click anywhere in the right pane (load order) and select &lt;strong>Enable all&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This will ensure all plugins are active prior to sorting them. Plugins may be unchecked automatically when renaming their file extensions from ESL to ESP as we did multiple times throughout the guide.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="applying-the-load-order">Applying the load order&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/14223?tab=files">Universal Load Order TXT&lt;/a> from the guide’s Nexus page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the archive and extract the &lt;strong>loadorder.txt&lt;/strong> to &lt;code>Mod Organizer 2\profiles\The Phoenix Flavour&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Restart Mod Organizer 2 and the changes will be applied.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>After applying the loadorder.txt and restarting MO2, there should be no plugins below the &lt;strong>Conflict Resolution Patch.esp&lt;/strong> in the load order (right pane).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If there are other plugins below the CRP, you either made a mistake during the mod installation, or a mod was updated and the loadorder.txt is not accounting for it yet. Go back to the mod(s) in question (they will be highlighted in the mod order when you click on the plugin in the load order) and re-install them according to the instructions in the guide.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are unable to resolve all issues, please join us on Discord and post your Modwat.ch link or a picture of the bottom of your load order in the &lt;code>#tpf-guide-support&lt;/code> channels.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="check-for-mo2-warnings">Check for MO2 Warnings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In Mod Organizer 2, check the notification icon in the top right corner (see screenshot below). Any issues found there should be fixed now. If it is greyed out, there are no warnings and you are good to go!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are multiple different warnings that you may encounter:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Missing Masters:&lt;/strong> One of your plugins is missing a master file. It is marked with an exclamation mark in your load order. This is most likely due to skipping a mod that was not optional or selecting the wrong option in a FOMOD installer. Go back to the mod’s instructions in the guide and double-check everything.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Form 43 Plugin:&lt;/strong> You forgot to re-save plugins in the Creation Kit. Re-save them now.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Outdated SKSE Plugin:&lt;/strong> Check the plugin&amp;rsquo;s mod page to see if there is a new version.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Files in Overwrite:&lt;/strong> Share a screenshot on Discord so we can take a look.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/check-for-form43-plugin.png" alt="Check for Form43 Plugins">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="flag-plugins-as-esl">Flag Plugins as ESL&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While at this point many installed plugins are already flagged as ESL (ESP-Lite) and we are not exceeding the maximum of 255 ESP+ESM plugins, there are several more plugins that may easily be flagged as ESL in order to save plugin slots. This completely removes the need to merge some plugins.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run &lt;strong>SSEEdit&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> in the plugin selection window to load all your mods.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait until SSEEdit has finished loading up your plugins and returns &lt;code>Background loader: finished&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click &lt;strong>Raven Rock - Fix Exit on Horseback.esp&lt;/strong> in the left pane (near the bottom) and select &lt;strong>Compact FormIDs for ESL&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A warning window will pop up, click &lt;strong>Yes, I’m absolutely sure&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Another warning will inform you that there are indeed FormIDs to renumber. Click &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The process itself takes a mere second. When it’s done, switch back to the &lt;strong>View&lt;/strong> tab at the bottom to see the plugin’s file header.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click the empty space to the right of &lt;strong>Record Flags&lt;/strong> and select &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the next window, check only &lt;strong>ESL&lt;/strong> and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The plugin is now successfully flagged as ESL! &lt;strong>Don’t close SSEEdit yet.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Plugins that contain no new records with new FormIDs and only edit existing records (from the official master files or other mods) do not need to have their FormIDs renumbered. When you attempt to renumber them, a window will pop up informing you that there was &lt;strong>Nothing to do&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="remaining-plugins">Remaining Plugins&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You will now need to repeat the process for a handful of other mods, most of which will not need their FormIDs renumbered. The plugins to ESL-ify are listed below. Simply add the ESL flag to each of them and don’t forget to renumber FormIDs first for those that need it.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>QuestsAreInSkyrimUSSEP.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;del>Raven Rock - Fix Exit on Horseback.esp&lt;/del> &lt;em>already flagged&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dawnguard Dont Hunt Cured Vampires.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ChargeDialogueFix.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>WindhelmSegregation.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move it Dammit.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Runandwalkpaces.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No More Standing Too Close SSE 1-0.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Realistic-Voice.esp &lt;strong>compact FormIDs&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No NPC Greetings.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Don&amp;rsquo;tTalkWithYourMouthFull.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Followers Don&amp;rsquo;t Draw Weapons.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NoMoreFollowerHuntingBow.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Random Encounter Tweaks.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>dD-No Spinning Death Animation Merged.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SparklesSE.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SimplySmallerWolfs2.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SIDT - Special Edition.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>dD-Medium Script Range.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>dD-Reduced Wound Size.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DeadlySpellImpacts.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enhanced Vanilla Trees SSE.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RUSTIC SOULGEMS - Sorted.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>homeymealyum.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GQJ_DG_vampireamuletfix.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Miscellaneous Quests…as Miscellaneous Quests.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mortal Enemies - No RunWalk Changes.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Realistic Melee Range.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Northerner Diaries in Skyrim.esp &lt;strong>compact FormIDs&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Still.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hun Lovaas.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NirShor-MusicalLore.esp &lt;strong>compact FormIDs&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>After renumbering the form IDs for Northern Diaries in Skyrim.esp and NirShor-MusicalLore.esp, the Phoenix - Merged Music Patch.esp will also be marked as updated which is intended behaviour as the previously renumbered form IDs are referenced there and updated accordingly.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Tpf: Nemesis</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/nemesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/nemesis/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="nemesis-setup">Nemesis Setup&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Nemesis Unlimited Behavior Engine&lt;/strong> is a tool used to add custom animations to Skyrim. It is an open-source replacement and upgrade for FNIS, and required for several animation-related mods in TPF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nemesis will generate a number of files specifically for your setup. In order to simplify the file management, we will set up an output folder ahead of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="new-separator">New Separator&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Create a &lt;strong>PATCHER OUTPUT&lt;/strong> separator in Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It should be at the bottom of your mod order, below the CRP.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="nemesis-output-folder">Nemesis Output Folder&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In Mod Organizer 2, click the tools icon above your mod order and select &lt;strong>Create empty mod&lt;/strong> (see picture below).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rename the new mod folder to &lt;strong>Nemesis Output&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drag the new empty mod (displayed in grey italics) below the &lt;strong>PATCHER OUTPUT&lt;/strong> separator and activate it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/create-empty-mod.png" alt="Create Empty Mod">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="add-nemesis-to-mo2">Add Nemesis to MO2&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open the &lt;strong>Executables&lt;/strong> window in Mod Organizer 2 (Tools &amp;gt; Executables or CTRL + E).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the blue plus icon and select &lt;strong>Add from file&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>Mod Organizer 2\mods\Nemesis Unlimited Behavior Engine\Nemesis_Engine&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Double-click &lt;strong>Nemesis Unlimited Behavior Engine.exe&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check the &lt;strong>Create files in mod instead of overwrite&lt;/strong> checkbox and select &lt;strong>Nemesis Output&lt;/strong> from the drop down menu.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to close the Tools window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/add-nemesis-to-mo2.png" alt="Add Nemesis to MO2">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="generate-nemesis">Generate Nemesis&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run &lt;strong>Nemesis&lt;/strong> (the executable we just added) through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There will be two warnings about missing (not yet generated) cache, click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to both.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>Update Engine&lt;/strong> button and wait for the process to be completed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When it&amp;rsquo;s done, check the &lt;strong>Jump Behavior Overhaul&lt;/strong> box.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the big &lt;strong>Launch Nemesis Behavior Engine&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nemesis will eventually return &lt;code>Behavior generation complete&lt;/code> and you can close the tool.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Back in Mod Organizer 2, press F5 to refresh and you can see that files were added to the &lt;strong>Nemesis Output&lt;/strong> mod folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A &lt;strong>FNIS.esp&lt;/strong> will appear at the bottom of your load order. Make sure it&amp;rsquo;s activated.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>FNIS.esp is an empty dummy plugin used to trick XPMSSE, the skeleton replacer, into thinking FNIS is actually present in the load order. Functionally, FNIS is replaced by Nemesis.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/run-nemesis.png" alt="Run Nemesis">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tpf: Facegen</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/facegen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/facegen/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="about-facegen">About Facegen&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Among the most common &amp;ldquo;bugs&amp;rdquo; in Skyrim is the dreaded &amp;ldquo;black face&amp;rdquo; which is simply mismatched facegen. NPC heads - specifically tintmasks like dirt, warpaints, makeup - are defined in their records (in the official master files and sometimes other mods that change them) but there must be matching textures and meshes present as well. The &amp;ldquo;black face&amp;rdquo; occurs when the facegen files (aforementioned textures and meshes) do not match the NPC record. The facegen files are generated by the Creation Kit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TPF is using a number of mods to improve NPC appearance. However, by default many of these mods will only affect the player character and facegen must be regenerated with those mods so that they can apply to NPCs as well. In this step we will regenerate facegen not only for all vanilla NPCs but also for NPCs added by certain mods for consistent and high quality facegen across the board.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The process of creating facegen was significantly simplified by &lt;strong>Nuukem&amp;rsquo;s Creation Kit Fixes&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>VictorF&amp;rsquo;s zEdit script&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Warning:&lt;/strong> For this process you need to have at least 20GB of free space on the hard drive where Mod Organizer 2 is installed on. You will generate about 13.4GB of facegen files (which are later compressed and packed to take up less than 1GB). In general you should have quite a bit more than 20GB of free space on your drive anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="creation-kit-tweak">Creation Kit Tweak&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By default the Creation Kit will generate facetint textures with a 512x512 resolution. Thanks to CK Fixes we can easily increase the resolution for higher quality output.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Navigate to your &lt;strong>root&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Double-click &lt;strong>skyrim64_test.ini&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scroll to &lt;strong>Line 32&lt;/strong> and change the line to &lt;code>TintMaskResolution=1024&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Save the file and close.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="npcswithfaces">NPCsWithFaces&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The official master files have a large amount of NPC records, not all of which need facegen. For example, we don&amp;rsquo;t need to regenerate facegen for children, NPCs that have templates (use facegen from other records), or simply creatures. Thankfully, we can use zEdit and a code snippet by VictorF to filter out relevant records and copy them to a separate plugin. We will also use it to filter out NPC records with facegen from those mods that add new NPCs at the same time.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download the &lt;strong>NPCsWithFaces - zEdit Script&lt;/strong> from the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/26092?tab=files">Nexus page&lt;/a> manually.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the archive and extract the script to &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\Tools\zEdit\scripts\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="open-in-zedit">Open in zEdit&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run &lt;strong>zEdit&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The regular &lt;strong>zEdit&lt;/strong> mode and &lt;strong>Skyrim SE&lt;/strong> should be selected by default. Click &lt;strong>Start Session&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the &lt;strong>Load Order&lt;/strong> window press &lt;strong>CTRL+A&lt;/strong> to select and then &lt;strong>Space&lt;/strong> to unselect all.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Now check only the following plugins:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Skyrim.esm&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Update.esm&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Dawnguard.esm&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>HearthFires.esm&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Dragonborn.esm&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Unofficial Skyrim Special Edition Patch.esp&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>SimpleVampFixesSSE.esp&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>NaturalHairColors.esp&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>CFTO.esp&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Immersive Patrols II.esp&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>OCW_Obscure's_CollegeofWinterhold.esp&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>ICNs_ImmersiveCollegeNPCs.esp&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>SolstheimLighthouse.esp&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>SkaalFishingCamp.esp&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to load the selected plugins.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="create-plugin">Create Plugin&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Proceed once zEdit has loaded the selected plugins (will only take a few second).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click anywhere in the left pane and select &lt;strong>Automate&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure the &lt;strong>NPCsWithFaces.js&lt;/strong> script is selected.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to run the script.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/zedit-npc-script.png" alt="zEdit NPC Script">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="output">Output&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>When the plugin has been generated, zEdit will return &lt;code>Script completed&lt;/code> and you can close the tool.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> when asked (NPCsWithFaces.esp should be checked).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In Mod Organizer 2, scroll to the bottom and double-click the &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Delete the (empty) &lt;strong>zEdit Backups&lt;/strong> folder, then close the &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> window.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click the &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> and select &lt;strong>Create Mod&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter &lt;strong>NPCs With Faces&lt;/strong> as the name and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move the new mod directly below the &lt;strong>PATCHER OUTPUT&lt;/strong> separator and activate it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Load order doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter for the plugin, leave it at the bottom but make sure it&amp;rsquo;s activated.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Overwrite must be completely empty at this point.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="regenerating-facegen">Regenerating Facegen&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now we get to the heart of the matter: Rebuilding facegen for all NPCs, vanilla and mod-added. Facegen is generated in the Creation Kit and thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/20061">Creation Kit Fixes&lt;/a> it&amp;rsquo;s fast and easy.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run the &lt;strong>Creation Kit&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go to &lt;strong>File&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong> and scroll all the way to the bottom of the load order in the left pane.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the &lt;strong>NPCsWithFaces.esp&lt;/strong> and click the &lt;strong>Set as Active File&lt;/strong> button, then click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to load the plugin.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/load-plugin-ck.png" alt="Open Plugin in CK">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="filter-npc-records">Filter NPC Records&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Proceed when the CK has loaded up the plugin and its dependencies.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In the list of record types on the left, expand &lt;strong>Actors&lt;/strong> and select &lt;strong>Actor&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check the box for &lt;strong>Show only active (*) forms&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The option to filter for active forms is added by CK Fixes and it&amp;rsquo;s ingenious. Checking it will make it so only records touched by the current active plugin are displayed which means we only see NPC records filtered out earlier in zEdit into the NPCsWithFaces plugin.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/filter-npc-records.png" alt="Filter NPC Records">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="export-facegen">Export Facegen&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The records should be sorted alphabetically (click the &lt;strong>Editor ID&lt;/strong> column if they aren&amp;rsquo;t).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>Abelone&lt;/strong> NPC near the top (we&amp;rsquo;re skipping the dummy NPCs).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scroll down all the way to the bottom. Hold SHIFT and click the final NPC &lt;strong>Zaynabi&lt;/strong> to highlight all records in between.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Press &lt;strong>CTRL + F4&lt;/strong> to export facegen and click &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> to confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can check the progress in the &lt;strong>Log&lt;/strong> window. Ignore the warnings.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Exporting facegen for all NPCs will take a few minutes. Wait until a window pops up that simply says &lt;strong>Done&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> and close the Creation Kit.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you run into errors and crashes trying to export facegen, try going a few at a time. For example, you can go through by letter, exporting for NPCs starting with A, then B, and so forth.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/ck-export-facegen.png" alt="Export Facegen">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="optimising-facegen">Optimising Facegen&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At this time you will have about 13.4GB of loose facegen files in your &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> folder. Before we slim those down, let&amp;rsquo;s clean up a bit:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Right-click your &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> folder and select &lt;strong>Create mod&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter &lt;strong>Facegen Output&lt;/strong> as the name and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move the mod below &lt;strong>NPCs With Faces&lt;/strong> in your mod order and activate it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deactive the &lt;strong>NPCs With Faces&lt;/strong> mod (it&amp;rsquo;s only needed for regenerating the facegen files themselves).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="cathedral-assets-optimizer">Cathedral Assets Optimizer&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Using CAO we will compress the facegen files and pack them neatly into BSAs. This will bring down the total file size from 13.4GB to around 770MB.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run &lt;strong>Cathedral Assets Optimizer&lt;/strong> (outside of Mod Organizer 2).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the &lt;strong>SSE - Optimise Facegen&lt;/strong> profile.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Open Directory&lt;/strong> and navigate to your &lt;strong>Facegen Output&lt;/strong> mod folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Run&lt;/strong> and wait for CAO to process all files.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This will take some time (about 5 minutes for me). The CAO log will eventually return &lt;code>[INFO] Process completed&lt;/code>. Close CAO.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Return to Mod Organizer 2 and press F5 to refresh. Two new plugins will appear at the bottom of your load order.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure both &lt;strong>Facegen Output.esp&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Facegen Output0.esp&lt;/strong> are checked so they can load the BSAs containing the facegen.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Tpf: AllGUD</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/allgud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/allgud/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="sseedit-scripts">SSEEdit Scripts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While we install the base mod already, there is a number of additional steps to complete before the mod is fully implemented.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download the &lt;strong>AllGUD xEdit Scripts&lt;/strong> main file from the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/28833?tab=files">AllGUD&lt;/a> mod page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the downloaded archive and double-click the folder inside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract everything from the &lt;strong>Edit Scripts&lt;/strong> folder to &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\Tools\SSEEdit\Edit Scripts&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="fixed-texture-script">Fixed texture script&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One of the AllGUD scripts assigns faulty texture file paths to the generated meshes which will prevent the resulting objects from looking as intended. Fortunately, this was fixed by Dusky and provided to us (&lt;a href="https://github.com/foreverphoenix/the-phoenix-flavour/issues/26">source&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download the fixed script from &lt;a href="https://www.mediafire.com/file/fd0d6qj78lpjbas/AllGUD_AlternateTextureModelsplosion_-_Fixed.pas/file">Mediafire&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move the file to &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\Tools\SSEEdit\Edit Scripts&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="alternate-textures-patches">Alternate Textures Patches&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before we can generate weapon meshes, there are some weapons that use Alternate Textures which doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with AllGUD. Thankfully, one of the AllGUD SSEEdit scripts was created to patch these weapons.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run SSEEdit through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the plugin selection window, simply click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to load all plugins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait until SSEEdit returns &lt;strong>Background loader: finished&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click anywhere in the left pane (plugin list) and hit &lt;strong>CTRL + A&lt;/strong> to select all plugins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click the selected plugins and select &lt;strong>Apply Script&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the &lt;strong>AllGUD AlternateTextureModelsplosion - Fixed&lt;/strong> script and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter &lt;strong>AllGUD - Alternate Textures Patch&lt;/strong> as file name and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Leave the next two windows blank and only click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> both times.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eventually SSEEdit will return &lt;strong>Done: Applying script&lt;/strong>, and you can close the window.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> when prompted to save your changes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/allgud-alt-textures-fixed.png" alt="Alternate Textures Patch">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="output">Output&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Back in Mod Organizer 2, scroll down all the way to the &lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong> folder which contains the new plugin and meshes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click it and select &lt;strong>Create Mod&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter &lt;strong>AllGUD - Alternate Textures Patch&lt;/strong> as the name and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Activate the new mod in your mod order.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The plugin will now show up at the bottom of your load order, make sure it is checked.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="weapon-mesh-generator">Weapon Mesh Generator&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In Mod Organizer 2, click the tools icon above the mod order pane and select &lt;strong>Create empty mod&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter &lt;strong>AllGUD - Weapon Meshes&lt;/strong> as the name and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Leave the new mod at the bottom of your mod order and activate it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/create-empty-mod.png" alt="Create empty mod">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="fixed-script">Fixed Script&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The original script has a bug. A fixed version is available on the Nexus.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/38151?tab=files">AllGUD Weapon Mesh Generator Script Fix&lt;/a> manually.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the downloaded archive and extract the script to &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\Tools\SSEEdit\Edit Scripts&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Confirm when asked to overwrite.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="running-the-script">Running the script&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run SSEEdit through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the plugin selection window, simply click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to load all plugins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait until SSEEdit returns &lt;strong>Background loader: finished&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click anywhere in the left pane (plugin list) and hit &lt;strong>CTRL + A&lt;/strong> to select all plugins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click the selected plugins and select &lt;strong>Apply Script&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the &lt;strong>AllGUD Weapon Mesh Generator&lt;/strong> script and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the empty field below &lt;strong>Output Meshes Folder&lt;/strong> and navigate to &lt;code>Mod Organizer 2\mods&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the &lt;strong>AllGUD - Weapon Meshes&lt;/strong> folder you created in the previous step and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Start&lt;/strong> to begin generating the meshes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eventually SSEEdit will return &lt;strong>Done: Applying script&lt;/strong>, and you can close the window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/allgud-weapon-meshes.png" alt="AllGUD Weapon Patcher">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="skeleton-patcher">Skeleton Patcher&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In Mod Organizer 2, once again click the tools icon above the mod order pane and select &lt;strong>Create empty mod&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter &lt;strong>AllGUD - Skeleton Meshes&lt;/strong> as the name and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Leave the new mod at the bottom of your mod order and activate it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/create-empty-mod.png" alt="Create empty mod">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="running-the-script-1">Running the script&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run SSEEdit through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the plugin selection window, simply click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to load all plugins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait until SSEEdit returns &lt;strong>Background loader: finished&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click anywhere in the left pane and select &lt;strong>Apply Script&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the &lt;strong>AllGUD Skeleton Patcher&lt;/strong> script and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the empty field below &lt;strong>Output Meshes Folder&lt;/strong> and navigate to &lt;code>Mod Organizer 2\mods&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the &lt;strong>AllGUD - Skeleton Meshes&lt;/strong> folder you created in the previous step and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Start&lt;/strong> to begin generating the meshes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eventually SSEEdit will return &lt;strong>Done: Applying script&lt;/strong>, and you can close the window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Selecting all plugins first with CTRL + A is not necessary for this script.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/allgud-skeleton-patcher.png" alt="AllGUD Skeleton Patcher">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tpf: SSELODGen</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/sselodgen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/sselodgen/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SSELODGen is a tool for regenerating various LOD (level-of-detail) resources. We will be using it to generate better terrain LOD (distant ground textures) since the vanilla terrain LOD is of extremely low quality. This will also improve distant grass blending. Tree LOD and object LOD are much better handled with DynDOLOD (which is done in the next step) but afterwards we will once again use SSELODGen for Occlusion generation.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download the latest version of &lt;a href="https://forum.step-project.com/topic/13451-xlodgen-terrain-lod-beta-66-for-fnv-fo3-fo4-fo4vr-tes5-sse-tes5vr-enderal/">SSELODGen&lt;/a> from MEGA (see screenshot for the link).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\Tools&lt;/code> and create a new &lt;strong>SSELODGen&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the downloaded archive, double-click the &lt;strong>xLODGen&lt;/strong> folder, and extract all files into your new directory.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/xlodgen-download.png" alt="Download xLODGen">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="add-sselodgen-to-mo2">Add SSELODGen to MO2&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In Mod Organizer 2, open the &lt;strong>Executables&lt;/strong> window (Tools &amp;gt; Executables or CTRL + E).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the blue plus icon to add a new executable and select &lt;strong>Add from file&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\Tools\SSELODGen&lt;/code> and double-click &lt;strong>xLODGenx64.exe&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change the &lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> to &lt;strong>SSELODGen&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Arguments&lt;/strong>, add &lt;code>-sse -o:&amp;quot;...\Your Modding Folder\Tools\SSELODGen\Output\&amp;quot;&lt;/code> (change to full file path on your system).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to close the window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/add-xlodgen-to-mo2.png" alt="Add xLODGen to MO2">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="sse-terrain-tamriel">SSE-Terrain-Tamriel&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In the &lt;a href="https://stepmodifications.org/forum/topic/13451-xlodgen-terrain-lod-beta-76-for-fnv-fo3-fo4-fo4vr-tes5-sse-tes5vr-enderal-enderalse/">SSELODGen&lt;/a> post on the STEP forum, scroll down to &lt;strong>Recommended Optionals&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>SSE-Terrain-Tamriel-Extended.esm&lt;/strong> link (see screenshot).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Download the file from MEGA.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a new folder: &lt;code>Mod Organizer 2\mods\SSE-Terrain-Tamriel-Extended&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move the downloaded ESM into the new folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In Mod Organizer 2, press F5 to refresh. The new mod will show up at the bottom of your load order.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place the mod anywhere below the &lt;strong>PATCHER OUTPUT&lt;/strong> separator and enable it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the load order, drag the new plugin up all the way below &lt;strong>Lanterns Of Skyrim II.esm&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure the plugin is checked.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/download-lodgen-esm.png" alt="SSE-Terrain-Tamriel">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="terrain-lod-generation">Terrain LOD Generation&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run &lt;strong>SSELODGen&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait for the tool to load your mods.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click in the &lt;strong>Worldspaces&lt;/strong> window and &lt;strong>Select All&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>On the right side, only &lt;strong>Terrain LOD&lt;/strong> should be checked.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mirror the settings for all LOD levels (LOD4, LOD8, LOD16, LOD32) below.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Generate&lt;/strong> to begin the process. This may take a while (around 40-50 minutes for me).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;em>All credits to TechAngel - we&amp;rsquo;re using &lt;a href="https://stepmodifications.org/forum/topic/15184-xlodgen-terrain-settings-compare/?tab=comments#comment-242372">his custom settings&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="lod4-settings">LOD4 Settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/sselodgen-lod4.png" alt="SSELODGen LOD4">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="lod8-settings">LOD8 Settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/sselodgen-lod8.png" alt="SSELODGen LOD8">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="lod16-settings">LOD16 Settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/sselodgen-lod16.png" alt="SSELODGen LOD16">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="lod32-settings">LOD32 Settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/sselodgen-lod32.png" alt="SSELODGen LOD32">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="output">Output&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Once the LOD generation is complete, close &lt;strong>SSELODGen&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\Tools\SSELODGen&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rename the new &lt;strong>Output&lt;/strong> folder inside to &lt;strong>SSELODGen - Terrain LOD&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move the folder to &lt;code>Mod Organizer 2\mods&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In Mod Organizer 2, press F5 to refresh.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Activate the new mod in the mod order.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Disable &lt;strong>SSE-Terrain-Tamriel-Extended&lt;/strong> in the mod order.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="aqwm-conflict">AQWM Conflict&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The mod &lt;strong>A Quality World Map&lt;/strong> is editing terrain LOD textures to add roads and other improvements to the map. Unfortunately these edited textures are now overwritten by the generated terrain LOD. We could potentially solve this problem by packing the generated terrain LOD files into a BSA so the loose files from A Quality World Map overwrite, but at the end of the day it is much faster to simply hide the conflicting files from the xLODGen output.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Double-click &lt;strong>SSELODGen - Terrain LOD&lt;/strong> in your mod order.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Switch to the &lt;strong>Conflicts&lt;/strong> tab and select &lt;strong>Advanced&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>Overwrites&lt;/strong> column to sort by overwriting mods.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Highlight all files shown to overwrite A Quality World Map.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click them and select &lt;strong>Hide&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Close the window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/aqwm-xlodgen-conflict.png" alt="AQWM Terrain LOD Conflict">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tpf: Grass Cache</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/grass-cache/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/grass-cache/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="about-grass-cache">About Grass Cache&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Grass cache is generated using No Grass In Objects, a mod we installed and configured earlier in the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/mod-installation/essential-mods">Essential Mods&lt;/a> step. This will allow us to use NGIO&amp;rsquo;s extended grass feature so grass is rendered further in the distance until it blends with terrain LOD (almost) seamlessly.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="mo2-plugin">MO2 Plugin&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Close Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the Nexus page for &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/42161?tab=files">No Grass In Objects&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Optional Files&lt;/strong>, manually download &lt;strong>Grass Generation MO2 Plugin v1&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the download archive and extract &lt;strong>GrassPrecacher.py&lt;/strong> to &lt;code>Mod Organizer 2\plugins&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Restart Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="grass-generation">Grass Generation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Generating grass cache takes a good chunk of time. Skyrim is launched and will be displaying the loading screen during the entire process. It can and will crash any number of times in which case the MO2 plugin will automatically restart it. &lt;strong>Stay away from your PC until the process is complete.&lt;/strong> There will be a small message box informing you when grass cache was fully generated.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In Mod Organizer 2, there will be a new &lt;strong>Precache Grass&lt;/strong> option under &lt;strong>Tools&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select it to begin the grass generation process.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A warning will pop up. If you are ready, click &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/start-grass-cache.png" alt="Start Grass Cache">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="output">Output&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>When the message box pops up - &lt;strong>Grass generation finished successfully!&lt;/strong> - click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Back in Mod Organizer 2, you will be informed that grass cache was successfully generated, click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> again.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Double-click your &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> and delete the &lt;strong>NetScriptFramework&lt;/strong> folder inside (it contains grass cache crash logs).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Close the &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> again and right-click it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select &lt;strong>Create Mod&lt;/strong> and name it &lt;strong>Grass Cache&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click the new mod and select &lt;strong>Ignore missing data&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Activate the mod in your mod order.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Tpf: DynDOLOD</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/dyndolod/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/dyndolod/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="dyndolod-and-performance">DynDOLOD and Performance&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Contrary to popular belief, DynDOLOD is not inherently performance-intense. With the &lt;strong>Low&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Medium&lt;/strong> presets and regular tree LOD, you will hardly notice a performance impact at all, even on weaker machines, while distant terrain is still drastically improved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, more taxing is what is typically referred to as &amp;ldquo;ultra tree LOD&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;3D tree LOD&amp;rdquo;. This is a DynDOLOD feature which disables regular tree LOD, the two dimensional, flat &amp;ldquo;cut-outs&amp;rdquo;. Instead, object LOD is generated for distant trees, utilising 3D meshes which improves the visual quality of tree LOD to the point where you can barely tell fully-rendered trees and distant trees apart anymore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3D tree LOD is not recommended for people with less than 4GB of VRAM. For everyone else, there is still a potential performance impact but it is usually negligible on modern machines (and very much worth the visual improvement).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You will have the option to generate &lt;em>either&lt;/em> regular or 3D tree LOD.&lt;/strong> Choose accordingly. Later on, you can always re-run DynDOLOD to generate the other type of tree LOD, depending on how well the game runs for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dyndolod-setup">DynDOLOD Setup&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open the Nexus page for &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/32382?tab=files">DynDOLOD&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Miscellaneous Files&lt;/strong>, download the latest version of &lt;strong>DynDOLOD 3.00&lt;/strong> manually.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\Tools&lt;/code> and create a new &lt;strong>DynDOLOD&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the downloaded &lt;strong>DynDOLOD&lt;/strong> archive and move all files into your new directory.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="texgen-executable">TexGen Executable&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Switch back to Mod Organizer 2 and open the &lt;strong>Executables&lt;/strong> window (Tools &amp;gt; Executables or CTRL + E).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the blue plus icon to add a new executable and select &lt;strong>Add from file&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\Tools\DynDOLOD&lt;/code>and double-click &lt;strong>TexGenx64.exe&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Arguments&lt;/strong>, add &lt;code>-sse&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="dyndolod-executable">DynDOLOD Executable&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Once again, click the blue plus icon to add a new executable and select &lt;strong>Add from file&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\Tools\DynDOLOD&lt;/code>and double-click &lt;strong>DynDOLODx64.exe&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Arguments&lt;/strong>, add &lt;code>-sse&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to save and close the &lt;strong>Executables&lt;/strong> window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/texgen-dyndolod-executables.png" alt="Texgen DynDOLOD Executables">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="texgen">TexGen&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Launch &lt;strong>TexGen&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Trees/Grass Billboards&lt;/strong>, check the boxes for &lt;strong>Tree&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>HD Tree&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>Rendered&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Increase &lt;strong>Min Texture Size&lt;/strong> to &lt;strong>256&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Start&lt;/strong> to begin the process.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The generation will take a while (around 20 minutes for me) and you should step away from your PC in the meantime.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/texgen-settings.png" alt="TexGen Settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="texgen-output">TexGen Output&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Once TexGen has finished, click &lt;strong>Exit TexGen&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\Tools\DynDOLOD&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut (CTRL + X) the &lt;strong>TexGen_Output&lt;/strong> folder and paste (CTRL+V) it to &lt;code>Mod Organizer 2\mods&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Refresh Mod Organizer 2 (F5) and it will appear at the bottom of your mod order.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place it below the &lt;strong>PATCHER OUTPUT&lt;/strong> separator and activate it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="dyndolod-generation">DynDOLOD Generation&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run &lt;strong>DynDOLOD&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the DynDOLOD Wizard window, click &lt;strong>Advanced&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the &lt;strong>Advanced&lt;/strong> window, you can see a list of all worldspaces at the top.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click inside and &lt;strong>Select all&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Load rules for&lt;/strong> check both &lt;strong>Candles&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>FXGlow&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Also check &lt;strong>Glow Windows&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>High&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Fake lights in child worlds&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Select one of the presets:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Low&lt;/strong> if you struggle with performance.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Medium&lt;/strong> as the default option.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>High&lt;/strong> for modern machines.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you have 4GB of VRAM or more, you can generate 3D tree LOD.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Check the box for &lt;strong>Ultra&lt;/strong> next to &lt;strong>Generate tree LOD&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to start generating LOD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step away from your PC while DynDOLOD is working.&lt;/strong> This may take around 20-30 minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/dyndolod-settings.png" alt="DynDOLOD Settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dyndolod-output">DynDOLOD Output&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Once DynDOLOD is done, click &lt;strong>Save &amp;amp; Exit&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go to &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\Tools\DynDOLOD&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut (CTRL+X) the &lt;strong>DynDOLOD_output&lt;/strong> folder and paste it (CTRL+V) to &lt;code>Mod Organizer 2\mods&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Refresh Mod Organizer 2 (F5) and it will appear at the bottom of your load order.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place it last below the &lt;strong>PATCHER OUTPUT&lt;/strong> separator and activate it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move &lt;strong>DynDOLOD.esm&lt;/strong> below your other ESMs at the top of your load order.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Leave &lt;strong>DynDOLOD.esp&lt;/strong> at the very bottom as the last plugin.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure both plugins are activated.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="dyndolod-loading-screens">DynDOLOD Loading Screens&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As DynDOLOD was such a revolutionary mod when it came out, there&amp;rsquo;s been an ongoing joke that one had to give their firstborn to the author, sheson, for using it - like in the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rumpelstiltskin">fairy tale&lt;/a>. Also there&amp;rsquo;s a golden cow. Both memes were added to the mod as easter eggs and while the cow is optional in the FOMOD, the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/dyndolod-loading-screen.png">three loading screens&lt;/a> featuring those memes are part of the generated DynDOLOD.esm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Removing the loading screens can be done easily in SSEEdit after generating DynDOLOD. You can skip this step if they don&amp;rsquo;t bother you.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run &lt;strong>SSEEdit&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> in the plugin selection window to load all plugins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait until SSEEdit has loaded up your plugins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Double-click &lt;strong>DynDOLOD.esm&lt;/strong> in the left pane.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click the &lt;strong>Load Screen&lt;/strong> section and click &lt;strong>Remove&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely sure&lt;/strong> and confirm deletion of all records.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Close SSEEdit and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to save your changes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/delete-dyndolod-loadscreens.png" alt="Delete DynDOLOD Load Screens">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tpf: Occlusion</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/occlusion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/occlusion/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="generate-occlusion-data">Generate Occlusion Data&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We already installed SSELODGen for terrain LOD earlier so we simply need to fire it up again to generate Occlusion. Occlusion essentially tells the game what is visible to the player and must be rendered while invisible objects (on the other side of a mountain for instance) don&amp;rsquo;t have to be rendered at the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This will also fix the giant hole in the Sea of Ghosts behind Winterhold.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run &lt;strong>SSELODGen&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the worldspaces window, check &lt;strong>Tamriel &amp;ldquo;Skyrim&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>DLC2SolstheimWorld &amp;ldquo;Solstheim&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Uncheck all options except for &lt;strong>Occlusion&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set &lt;strong>Quality&lt;/strong> to &lt;strong>3&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set &lt;strong>Height&lt;/strong> to &lt;strong>100&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Generate&lt;/strong> and wait for the process to complete.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Occlusion generation is very CPU intense and will likely hold your processor load at 100% for the duration.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/generate-occlusion-data.png" alt="Generate Occlusion Data">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="output">Output&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Once SSELODGen returns &lt;strong>LOD generation complete&lt;/strong>, you can close the window.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click the &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> folder in Mod Organizer 2 and select &lt;strong>Create mod&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter &lt;strong>SSELODGen - Occlusion Data&lt;/strong> as the name and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Activate the mod in the mod order.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure &lt;strong>Occlusion.esp&lt;/strong> is at the bottom of your load order and active.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Tpf: ENBSeries</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/enbseries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/enbseries/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-enbseries">What is ENBSeries?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>ENBSeries is a post-processing injector by Boris Vorontsov. Unlike ReShade, it is not universal but built for specific games and hooks directly into the engine. Effects are therefore highly advanced and specific to each games. ENB is also capable of fixing bugs and improving performance plus it offers additional features such as VSYNC, a screenshot hotkey, and a toggleable FPS counter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The effects vary in their performance impact. A full preset, especially when Skyrim is run on high resolutions, can bring even high-end PCs to their knees. Fortunately, Skyrim SE with its generally improved performance runs a great deal better with ENBSeries presets and 60FPS+ on a reasonable resolution (1080p) are comfortably attainable on most machines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TPF uses &lt;strong>Serio&amp;rsquo;s ENB&lt;/strong>, preset for Cathedral Weathers that is fairly performance-friendly and doesn&amp;rsquo;t break vanilla imagespaces (for Nighteye). For better compatibility with our lighting overhaul, we will be using a version of it tweaked specifically for the guide.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="is-installing-enbseries-mandatory">Is installing ENBSeries mandatory?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Yes and no.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ENB and Serio&amp;rsquo;s preset are part of the guide. You are not supposed to skip these instructions. However, disabling ENBSeries is as simple as pressing a single key ingame or clicking &amp;ldquo;Uninstall&amp;rdquo; in ENB Man.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem is that the guide was made with ENB in mind. For example, Skyrim&amp;rsquo;s native ambient occlusion was disabled early on in the guide in favour of ENB AO. A number of mods installed up until this point are exclusively for ENB, fixing mesh brightness or adding effects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultimately, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t encounter any major issues when disabling ENB. If you don&amp;rsquo;t like the effect or find the performance impact too jarring, you can essentially skip this step or uninstall ENB later on. The point is that I will not be responsible for any visual inconsistencies or bugs stemming from a user&amp;rsquo;s refusal to use ENBSeries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose not to use ENBSeries, it is advisable to re-enable Skyrim&amp;rsquo;s native ambient occlusion and lower the particle count, both done in the SkyrimPrefs.ini file.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="enbman">ENBMan&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>ENBMan is one of several ENB manager tools available. It happens to my favourite which is why we are using it for TPF. One downside of ENBMan is that importing files directly from archives usually doesn&amp;rsquo;t work so an extra step is required, extracting files, and then importing them in ENBMan. That&amp;rsquo;s a small inconvenience for an otherwise highy convenient tool though.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrim/mods/57620?tab=files">ENBMan&lt;/a> (the main file) manually from the Nexus.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract &lt;strong>ENBMan.exe&lt;/strong> to &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\Tools\ENB Man&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Run &lt;strong>ENBMan.exe&lt;/strong> and click the green plus to add a new game.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the folder icon and point ENBMan to your &lt;strong>SkyrimSE.exe&lt;/strong> (located in your root folder).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You might want to edit the name to indicate that it’s the Special Edition (I’ve changed it to &lt;strong>Skyrim SE&lt;/strong>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the green checkmark to confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Double-click the new &lt;strong>Skyrim SE&lt;/strong> profile.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/enb-game-setup.png" alt="Game Setup">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="enbseries-binaries">ENBSeries Binaries&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>On the website for &lt;a href="http://enbdev.com/download_mod_tesskyrimse.htm">ENBSeries for Skyrim SE&lt;/a>, click on the latest version number (near the bottom).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scroll down and click the &lt;strong>download&lt;/strong> below the changelog.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the downloaded archive and double-click the &lt;strong>WrapperVersion&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract the following files from the &lt;strong>WrapperVersion&lt;/strong> folder to &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\temp&lt;/code>:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>d3d11.dll&lt;/li>
&lt;li>d3dcompiler_46e.dll&lt;/li>
&lt;li>enblocal.ini&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="import-to-enbman">Import to ENBMan&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Back in ENBMan, click the arrow under &lt;strong>Binaries&lt;/strong> and select &lt;strong>Add&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter &lt;strong>ENBSeries&lt;/strong> and the version number as name (eg &lt;strong>ENBSeries 0.452&lt;/strong>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the green checkmark to confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drag the three files from your temp folder into the &lt;strong>Binary&lt;/strong> window.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the green checkmark to confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Delete the files from your &lt;strong>temp&lt;/strong> directory.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/install-enb-binaries.png" alt="Install ENB Binaries">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="global-ini-settings">Global INI Settings&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click the gears icon under &lt;strong>Global Settings&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A new window will come up. Click the green plus icon.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter &lt;strong>enblocal.ini&lt;/strong> as name. It will now appear in the list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Double-click your new &lt;strong>enblocal.ini&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the new window, click &lt;strong>Import Settings&lt;/strong> in the top bar.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\Tools\ENBMan\Games\Skyrim SE\Binaries\ENBSeries 0.4xx&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Double-click the &lt;strong>enblocal.ini&lt;/strong> inside to import it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Press CTRL+A to select all settings and click the green checkmark button in the toolbar to enable them.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="better-hotkeys">Better Hotkeys&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m personally not a fan of the default ENB ingame hotkeys. &amp;ldquo;KeyUseEffect&amp;rdquo;, for instance, is on Shift+F12. At the same time, F12 is the Steam hotkey for &amp;ldquo;Take Screenshot&amp;rdquo;. You can see how that might result in many unwanted screenshots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Check the screenshot below and mirror my values in the input section to get the following hotkeys:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>KeyCombination:&lt;/strong> Disabled.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>KeyDof:&lt;/strong> Disabled.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>KeyEditor:&lt;/strong> F11&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>KeyFPSLimit:&lt;/strong> Disabled.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>KeyScreenshot:&lt;/strong> Disabled.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>KeyShowFPS:&lt;/strong> F7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>KeyUseEffect:&lt;/strong> F10&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This means you can quickly toggle ENB ingame with F10, open the GUI to customise the preset with F11, and bring up a nifty FPS counter anytime with F7. No default keys are affected (like F5 and F9 for Quick Save and Quick Load respectively) and screenshots you can continue to take with F12 using the Steam overlay.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you want different hotkeys, use &lt;a href="https://keycode.info/">this super useful website&lt;/a> to figure out any key&amp;rsquo;s numeric value.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/enb-better-hotkeys.png" alt="ENB Better Hotkeys">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="save-global-configuration">Save Global Configuration&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click the green checkmark at the bottom, then click &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> to confirm and save your changes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Back in the &lt;strong>Global Configuration Files&lt;/strong> window, check the box next to &lt;strong>enblocal.ini.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the green checkmark to close the window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/enb-global-ini.png" alt="ENB Better Hotkeys">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="serios-enb">Serio&amp;rsquo;s ENB&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/30506?tab=files">Serio&amp;rsquo;s ENB&lt;/a> mod page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Download the &lt;strong>Serio&amp;rsquo;s ENB - TPF Edits&lt;/strong> miscellaneous file manually.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the downloaded archive and double-click the folder inside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract the following files to &lt;code>Your Modding Folder\temp&lt;/code>:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>enbseries&lt;/li>
&lt;li>enblocal.ini&lt;/li>
&lt;li>enbseries.ini&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="disable-distant-reflections">Disable Distant Reflections&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open the &lt;strong>enbseries.ini&lt;/strong> in a Notepad++.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scroll down to &lt;strong>Line 1122&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set &lt;strong>DisableDistantReflections&lt;/strong> to &lt;strong>true&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hit CTRL+S to save your changes and close the window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This will improve the way water looks in the distance.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="create-a-new-preset">Create a new preset&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In ENBMan, click the arrow under &lt;strong>Presets&lt;/strong> and select &lt;strong>Blank preset&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter a name for the new preset: &lt;code>Serio's ENB for Cathedral Weathers 1.10&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the green checkmark to confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/create-new-preset.png" alt="Create New Preset">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="import-files-into-preset">Import files into preset&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Drag-and-drop all files from the &lt;strong>temp&lt;/strong> folder into ENB Man.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong> both times when asked to add the palettes to ENB Man.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove all files inside the &lt;strong>temp&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Reference picture shows a different preset but the process is the same.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/install-enb-preset.png" alt="Import Preset Files">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="activate-the-preset">Activate the preset&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Select the latest version of ENBSeries under &lt;strong>Binary&lt;/strong> and tick the checkbox.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the green checkmark at the bottom of the window to install the preset.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Reference picture shows a different preset but the process is the same.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/activate-enb-preset.png" alt="Enable Preset">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tpf: First Launch</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/first-launch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/finalisation/first-launch/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="a-test-game">A Test Game&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>All mods are installed. The ENB preset is configured correctly. DynDOLOD is generated. Now comes the moment of truth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once arrived at this point it is important to test your setup in order to make sure your game looks as intended, performs well, and runs stable so that you can finally start a new playthrough without a high risk for nasty surprises.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In Mod Organizer 2, select &lt;strong>SKSE&lt;/strong> in the exectuables drop-down and hit &lt;strong>Run&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the main menu, open the console by pressing the tilde key (above TAB, next to 1).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Type in &lt;code>coc riverwood&lt;/code> and hit Enter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After the loading screen, you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself in Riverwood with a test character.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Before you continue, wait for all messages in the upper left corner to run through&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="immersive-hud">Immersive HUD&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Changes to MCM settings do not carry over across save games so it would be a waste of time to configure all MCMs for a test run. There are merely two changes in the Immersive HUD MCM that I recommend for now.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Press &lt;strong>ESCAPE&lt;/strong> and select the &lt;strong>MCM&lt;/strong> Option.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scroll down and click on &lt;strong>Immersive HUD&lt;/strong> to open the mod&amp;rsquo;s MCM.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the &lt;strong>Activation&lt;/strong> tab, select the following two options:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Key press toggles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Link ALL SkyUI Widgets&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can also change the hotkey to a different one if its inconvenient for you (default is X).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This will make it so that the clock widget from A Matter of Time is toggled along with the rest of the HUD, and that you only have to press the button once to toggle all elements.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="depth-of-field">Depth of Field&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While the default Depth of Field effect is fairly ugly, you will have noticed that we specifically left it turned on while configuring INI settings way back during the Setup section. This is because the DoF effect is tied to the underwater blur effect - turn off DoF and you will be able to see as clearly underwater as above the surface. The solution to this is leaving the effect on but turning it down all the way so that the DoF effect doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually kick in.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Press &lt;strong>ESCAPE&lt;/strong> and go into &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Display&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn down &lt;strong>Depth of Field&lt;/strong> all the way.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/tpf/finalisation/turn-down-dof.jpg" alt="Turn down DoF">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="testing-suggestions">Testing Suggestions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I recommend you spend at least 10 to 20 minutes ingame. Enjoy the improved graphics and take some screenshots! Once you have quit the game, proceed with the next step.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Activate the ENBSeries FPS counter (&lt;strong>F7&lt;/strong>) to monitor your frame rate.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It may be convenient to use the console in order to enable godmode (&lt;code>tgm&lt;/code>) and disable enemy AI (&lt;code>tcai&lt;/code>) for testing purposes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Travel around Skyrim and visit your favourite locations (open the console and type &lt;code>tmm 1&lt;/code> to enable all map markers).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Especially intense areas where you frame rate might drop are:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the southern forest, especially when looking down at Falkreath,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the swamp surrounding Morthal,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the bridge looking at Riverwood,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the Rift, particularly when approaching Riften from the south.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>When you are satisfied, close Skyrim SE again.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you encounter any bugs, performance lower than expected, or even crashes, please join us on Discord and provide us with detailed information about the problem. Any outstanding issues should be solved before diving back into Skyrim for a proper playthrough.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="continue-with-the-mod-configurationtpfmod-configuration-page">Continue with the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/mod-configuration/">Mod Configuration&lt;/a> page.&lt;/h4></description></item></channel></rss>