<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Phoenix Flavour – Slidikins' Strenuous Skyrim</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sss/</link><description>Recent content in Slidikins' Strenuous Skyrim on The Phoenix Flavour</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Skyrim-Se: Introduction</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sss/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sss/introduction/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/sss/sss.png" alt="Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Slidikins’ Strenuous Skyrim (SSS)&lt;/strong> is an extension of &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/tpf/introduction/">The Phoenix Flavour (TPF)&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>, The Phoenix Flavour itself is not required as everything you need will be provided through &lt;a href="installation%20Guide.md">Wabbajack installation&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What to expect from The Phoenix Flavour:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>A Better Skyrim:&lt;/strong> The guide includes hundreds of mods across several dozen categories, all carefully selected to fit Phoenix’s vision of a lore-friendly, improved but not radically changed Skyrim. The Phoenix Flavour strives to provide a solid upgrade of the vanilla experience with modern visuals and rebalanced gameplay.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Custom Files and Patches:&lt;/strong> Both the final patch as well as some patches and plugin replacers installed during the mod setup have been made specifically for the guide by Umgak and Phoenix. They ensure compatibility as well as consistency between all included mods.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Performance:&lt;/strong> The Phoenix Flavour was created for gameplay rather than screen-archery and will for most people deliver solid framerates on a 1080p monitor resolution. For higher resolutions, better hardware is required. Through INI changes, reasonable texture resolutions, a performance-friendly grass overhaul as well as a skippable ENB section and the choice to use lower settings in DynDOLOD, you can tweak your game until you reach a stable framerate.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Stability:&lt;/strong> Skyrim SE itself is already very stable compared to Classic Skyrim. You may still experience the occasional freeze or crash, but they will be very rare (perhaps once every 20 to 30 hours). These happen in Vanilla and they will happen in TPF.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Key differences between SSS and base TPF:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Survival Mode:&lt;/strong> It uses &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Survival_Mode">&lt;em>Survival Mode&lt;/em>&lt;/a> from the Creation Club, meaning you’ll need to eat, sleep, and keep warm alongside other changes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Reduced HUD:&lt;/strong> Your HUD will be minimized to limit on-screen information. You’ll no longer see enemy information or active effects while in combat, for example, and will need to use your intuition and context clues to assess your opponents.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Strict Level Cap:&lt;/strong> Maximum level is 50 with a total of 55 perk points granted. Use them wisely. Additionally, skills also can not be made Legendary.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Equipment Upkeep:&lt;/strong> The level cap puts more importance on your equipment choices. Weapon and armor tempering degrades over time as well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Preparedness Rewarded:&lt;/strong> Enemies such as bandits, draugr, the forsworn, and dragons have been overhauled making for harder and more varied encounters. Bringing the right tools for the job&amp;ndash;along with accounting for &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/59394">&lt;em>Enemy Resistance Tweaks&lt;/em>&lt;/a>&amp;ndash;will go a long way towards preventing stalls in your adventures.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;br>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://loadorderlibrary.com/lists/slidikins-strenuous-skyrim" style="background: rgb(132, 155, 182) none repeat scroll 0% 0%; border-radius: 1000px; padding: 12px 25px; color: rgb(0, 0, 0); display: inline-block; font: bold 15px / 1 &amp;quot;Roboto&amp;quot;, sans-serif; text-align: center; text-shadow: rgb(202, 202, 202) 1px 1px;">Full Modlist&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="to-get-started-head-to-the--installation-guideskyrim-sesssinstallation-guide-">To get started, head to the &amp;raquo; &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sss/installation-guide">Installation Guide&lt;/a> &amp;laquo;&lt;/h4></description></item><item><title>Skyrim-Se: Installation Guide</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sss/installation-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sss/installation-guide/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="requirements">Requirements&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/489830/The_Elder_Scrolls_V_Skyrim_Special_Edition/">Skyrim Special Edition&lt;/a> on Steam&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/">Nexus Mods&lt;/a> Account&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://aka.ms/vs/16/release/vc_redist.x64.exe">Visual C++ 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://dotnet.microsoft.com/download/dotnet-framework/thank-you/net48-web-installer">.NET Framework 4.8&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A Nexus Premium subscription is highly recommended for a significantly faster and easier installation. Without Premium, you will need to manually click &amp;ldquo;download&amp;rdquo; for every mod while Premium allows Wabbajack to automatically download everything for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="skyrim-se-setup">Skyrim SE Setup&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="update-the-game">Update the Game&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim requires the latest version of Skyrim SE.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During installation, your vanilla files will be copied into SSS&amp;rsquo; folder and patched if necessary. In order for this to work you will need to have the current Steam installation of the game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are unsure if your Steam installation is up to date, follow these steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open your Steam Library and navigate to &lt;strong>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Special Edition&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right click and select &lt;strong>Properties&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under &lt;strong>Local Files&lt;/strong>, select &lt;strong>Verify integrity of game files&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait for the process to identify and obtain any files it requires.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Launch the game. It should prompt you to download updated Creations. Do so.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="set-language-to-english">Set Language to English&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SSS requires the English language version of Skyrim SE.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are currently playing in a language other than English, please go into the settings for Skyrim SE in your Steam library and revert the language to English. After changing the language, Steam should automatically download the required files (launch the game to force the download if it doesn’t).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After updating the game language, please launch the game once and quit from the main menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="wabbajack-installation">Wabbajack Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Next, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to install the Wabbajack tool itself:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download &lt;a href="https://www.wabbajack.org/">Wabbajack&lt;/a> from the official website.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract to a high level folder (i.e. &lt;code>C:\Wabbajack\&lt;/code>).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Do not install Wabbajack into UAC protected directories.&lt;/strong> These include &lt;code>Program Files&lt;/code> and &lt;code>Program Files x86&lt;/code> as well as the Downloads, Desktop, Documents, etc., folders.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Double-click &lt;strong>Wabbajack.exe&lt;/strong> to launch to tool. It will automatically update itself to the latest version.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-the-list">Choosing the List&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>Browse Modlists&lt;/strong> button in the Wabbajack tool.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find &lt;strong>Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim&lt;/strong> in the gallery and click the arrow to download the installation file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once downloaded, the button will change to a sideways arrow. Click it again.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/sss/installation/sss-on-wj.png" alt="Wabbajack Gallery">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="configuration">Configuration&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Before you can begin installing the list, you need to define two file paths:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Installation Location&lt;/strong> is where Mod Organizer 2 and all of the mods will be installed. Choose a high-level folder such as &lt;code>C:\Slidikins Strenuous Skyrim&lt;/code> that is outside UAC protected folders (Program Files, Documents, etc.) that&amp;rsquo;s on your fastest drive, such as an SSD.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Including the apostrophe in &lt;code>Slidikins' Strenuous Skyrim&lt;/code> can cause issues on some systems, especially if the default language isn&amp;rsquo;t English. You may want to omit it when choosing an Installation Location.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Download Location&lt;/strong> is where the downloaded mod archives will be stored. By default, they will be placed within your installation folder. I recommend you instead place them elsewhere, such as an HDD with plenty of space. They are not needed for running the game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/sss/installation/sss-installation-wj.png" alt="List Configuration">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="installation-process">Installation Process&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Once you have set target folders for the &lt;strong>Installation Location&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Download Location&lt;/strong>, the &lt;strong>Start&lt;/strong> button (arrow) to the right of the folder paths will light up. Click it to start installation. If you have Nexus Premium the process will be automatic. It may take several hours depending on the speed of your internet connection. If you do not have Premium, Wabbajack will prompt you with the mod pages where you&amp;rsquo;ll have to click each download button manually.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You can follow along as Wabbajack installs the list. It will display summaries and links to the mods being installed. Don’t let the log worry you. Unless the installation is aborted completely the warnings are inconsequential.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>While Wabbajack runs perfectly fine most of the time, an installation may fail for various reasons. &lt;strong>If it does, try restarting Wabbajack first.&lt;/strong> You will not lose progress as it will pick up where it left off. Should it fail again, please join us on &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/xRrHRsb5e9">Discord&lt;/a>, grab the &lt;code>Slidikins' Strenuous Skyrim&lt;/code> role, and post your &lt;code>wabbajack.current.log&lt;/code> in the &lt;code>#sss-support&lt;/code> channel. You can find all Wabbajack logs in your Wabbajack folder under &lt;code>\Wabbajack\logs\&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="playing-the-game">Playing the Game&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Navigate to your &lt;strong>Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim&lt;/strong> folder and launch &lt;strong>ModOrganizer.exe&lt;/strong> within. In the top right drop-down menu, &lt;strong>Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim&lt;/strong> (a renamed &lt;code>skse64_loader.exe&lt;/code>) should already be selected and you can now launch the game by clicking &lt;strong>► Run&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim uses the &lt;strong>Stock Game Folder&lt;/strong> system. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to move anything around as you would in some other lists.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/sss/installation/launch-sss.png" alt="Launching the Game">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="mcm-instructions">MCM Instructions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There are a large number of Mod Configuration Menus (MCMs) in this list. &lt;strong>Thankfully, presets are automatically applied so you don&amp;rsquo;t need to edit anything manually.&lt;/strong> These are the recommended settings for enjoying Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim; give them a try before changing them around.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="widescreen-support">Widescreen Support&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Basic support for 21:9 and 32:9 resolutions has been added for those with ultrawide monitors. To enable it:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Go to the &lt;strong>(Optional) Widescreen Support&lt;/strong> section of the modlist in Mod Organizer 2&amp;rsquo;s left pane and expand it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enable the two mods that correspond to your desired aspect ratio&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go down to the very last separator, &lt;code>-----&lt;/code>, expand it and open &lt;strong>Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim - Configuration and Runtime Files&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under &lt;code>INI Files&lt;/code>, find &lt;strong>SKSE\Plugins\SSEDisplayTweaks_Custom.ini&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edit &lt;strong>Line 6&lt;/strong> to match your desired resolution (and removed the &lt;code>;&lt;/code>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>As the Configuration and Runtime files may be overwritten by future updates, you may want to place changed files in a separate mod folder, such as &lt;code>[NoDelete] Custom Configurations&lt;/code>, placed at the end.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="performance-profile">Performance Profile&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If the list is too demanding out of the box, there is an alternative Performance profile intended for lower-end systems. This profile uses alternatives to the more intensive features (grass, LODs, shaders) to provide similar visuals at a lower cost.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Note that saves are profile-specific. You can switch from the regular to the performance profile mid-playthrough, but you would have to copy over the saves from &lt;code>\Slidikins' Strenuous Skyrim\profiles\Slidikins' Strenuous Skyrim\saves\&lt;/code> to &lt;code>\Slidikins' Strenuous Skyrim\profiles\Slidikins' Strenuous Skyrim (Performance)\saves\&lt;/code> manually. Ignore the warnings when resuming your adventure.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>See the picture below for how to switch profiles in MO2:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/sss/installation/swap-mo2-profile.png" alt="Swapping Profiles">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="gameplay-guide">Gameplay Guide&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sss/gameplay-guide">Gameplay Guide&lt;/a> highlights some of the key differences between vanilla Skyrim and SSS. It does not cover every single change made by the hundreds of mods in the list as that would be far too long. Read it if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to be left out in the cold.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="have-fun">Have fun!&lt;/h4></description></item><item><title>Skyrim-Se: Gameplay Guide</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sss/gameplay-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sss/gameplay-guide/</guid><description>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;ve installed &lt;strong>Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim&lt;/strong>, chances are you&amp;rsquo;ve just added hundreds of mods without the opportunity to read each one&amp;rsquo;s description thoroughly. To save you some time and to help you get adjusted, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to boil down the essentials of what you need to know going into the game.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note:&lt;/strong> Though the list aims to have a &amp;ldquo;vanilla&amp;rdquo; feel, several mechanics and quests have been adjusted. Guides written for the original game will be misleading. I recommend you push those guides and videos aside and discover &lt;strong>Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim&lt;/strong> firsthand.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="1-reduced-hud">1. Reduced HUD&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The first thing you&amp;rsquo;ll probably notice when you take control of the Prisoner is a lack of on-screen information. By default, the only HUD element that is always displayed is your Health Bar (and attached Shout Meter). Stamina and Magicka Bars appear whenever they are adjusting, and the Crosshair will dynamically appear when needed, such as with a ranged weapon or spell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enemy information is completely hidden from you as the player. You&amp;rsquo;ll no longer be able to see the health of an enemy or their level. You won&amp;rsquo;t even be able to see their name in most situations. Keep that in mind as &lt;strong>enemy strength can vary within a single area&lt;/strong>. Some foes will go down easily, others will present a challenge. Proceed with caution and always have a backup plan in case you find yourself outmatched.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lastly, activation prompts have been removed. Most of the time the UI will give no indication you&amp;rsquo;re about to steal an item. (Stealth indicators are also removed so it&amp;rsquo;s up to you to determine if you&amp;rsquo;re hidden or not.) Locked containers and doors won&amp;rsquo;t broadcast their difficulty either. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to try your hand at it and decide for yourself if it&amp;rsquo;s worth the lockpicks.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Tip:&lt;/strong> If you do get caught committing crimes (shame on you!), don&amp;rsquo;t reload! Getting caught is part of the criminal&amp;rsquo;s journey and can enhance your roleplay experience. Skipping town for awhile will gradually lower your bounty (&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/11452">&lt;em>Wergild Depreciation&lt;/em>&lt;/a>). A silver tongue will also help with the occassional bribe.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In general, expect the game to tell you far less information, leaving you to infer a lot of it on your own.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="relevant-control-changes">Relevant Control Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Journal:&lt;/strong> &lt;code>F4&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Quick Inventory:&lt;/strong> &lt;code>F2&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Quick Magic:&lt;/strong> &lt;code>F3&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Quick Stats:&lt;/strong> &lt;code>F1&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Toggle Compass:&lt;/strong> &lt;code>X&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Favorite Groups 1-4:&lt;/strong> &lt;code>9&lt;/code>,&lt;code>0&lt;/code>, &lt;code>-&lt;/code>, and &lt;code>=&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Horse Hotkey:&lt;/strong> &lt;code>H&lt;/code> (&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/54225">&lt;em>Simplest Horses&lt;/em>&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Toggle 1st/3rd Person View:&lt;/strong> &lt;code>F&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Toggle 3rd Person View Mode:&lt;/strong> &lt;code>↑&lt;/code> (in 3rd Person View)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="2-survival-and-exploration">2. Survival and Exploration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This list will automatically enable &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Survival_Mode">&lt;em>Survival Mode&lt;/em>&lt;/a> at the start of the game. You&amp;rsquo;ll be expected to engage with its mechanics, specifically &lt;em>eating&lt;/em>, &lt;em>sleeping&lt;/em>, and &lt;em>keeping warm&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="hunger">Hunger&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Fuel for your adventurer, food will be a near-constant concern on your journey. Neglecting to eat will lower your maximum Stamina, slow your Magicka Regeneration, and eventually affect your physical prowess. Luckily, food is somewhat abundant in Skyrim if you know where to look.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fruits and vegetables are commonly found in barrels all around the region.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hunt wild animals for meat if you prefer protein in your diet, or utilize &lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Fishing">&lt;em>Fishing&lt;/em>&lt;/a> to source from the waters of Skyrim.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>With a dash of salt you can cook the above into simple meals. Merchants can provide recipes that will allow you to cook more nutritious meals.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Different types of foods given different bonuses, each lasting 20 real-time minutes. A varied diet can have a profound effect on your dungeon crawling.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you have a heavy coin pouch, you can always buy ingredients or fully cooked meals from vendors to save yourself time.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="fatigue">Fatigue&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Before long, you will find yourself Lethargic or Tired and in need of sleep. Several options are available to you though you may want to act fast before the penalties to your maximum Magicka and Stamina Regeneration make it hard to fight effectively. Your experience rate will also drop when you are fatigued and improve when you&amp;rsquo;re properly rested.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A multitude of bedrolls are scattered around Skyrim. You won&amp;rsquo;t wake up Well Rested, but it&amp;rsquo;s free.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sleeping in town is another option. However, the cost of an inn depends on the location, with major cities charging a premium.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Of course, you can always take what you want from the local brigands. Bandit camps typically have a warm, indoor bed to enjoy once the owners have been evicted.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eventually you&amp;rsquo;ll want to purchase a permanent residence for something dependable and reliable.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="cold">Cold&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Skyrim is a cold, northern environment and ignoring the elements will lead to your downfall. Your Health is directly at risk when succumbing to the cold but there are ways of dealing with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Avoid the obvious hazards. Snowstorms clearly mean freezing temperatures, as are lakes and rivers in snowy regions. Stay out of them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Purchasing or cooking hot soups and stews can warm you up as needed along your travels.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wearing clothes with a lot of coverage and/or fur will leave you warmer than other options. Conversely, metal armor is more susceptible to lower temperatures. Heavy armor users may want to carry a change of clothes for the road.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The realm changes with each season, with the winter months being the coldest of the year. Factor that into your preparations.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="other-notes">Other Notes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Your Health will only regenerate so much on its own. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to utilize other sources of regeneration to recover further, such as food, potions, perks, or Restoration magic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Containers are no longer bottomless. If you want to hoard goods and materials you&amp;rsquo;ll need to find a suitable location with enough chests for your stash. (&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/13826">&lt;em>Container and Arrow Weight Restrictions&lt;/em>&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Similarly, your Carry Weight has been reduced, encouraging you to reconsider what&amp;rsquo;s worth leaving the house with as well as what&amp;rsquo;s worth picking up in a dungeon.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Imperial Septims won&amp;rsquo;t be found in places where it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make sense. You&amp;rsquo;ll find foreign or ancient coins in their place. Merchants can exchange these for Septims at various rates. (&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/51439">&lt;em>C.O.I.N. - Coins of Interesting Natures&lt;/em>&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="additional-reading">Additional Reading&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/56374">&lt;em>Survival Mode Improved&lt;/em>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/96876">&lt;em>Gourmet - A Cooking Overhaul&lt;/em>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/97542">&lt;em>Candlehearth - An Inn Overhaul&lt;/em>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="3-crafting">3. Crafting&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The hard limit on player level (Lv50) and perk points (55 from leveling, 2 from quests) makes it harder to invest in multiple crafting skills, while at the same time makes it more worthwhile to utilize them all. As you make your mark on Skyrim, don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to pour some of your earnings into crafted goods you can not create yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="alchemy">Alchemy&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Alchemical goods can be found in almost every settlement at the general store if not a dedicated apothecary. Many of the available potion effects last for a minute or longer and provide percentage-based buffs making them viable at all levels of play. You can always craft your own alchemy potions and poisons as well, combining useful effects to save on Carry Weight. Even without perk investment it&amp;rsquo;s worth your while to dabble in Alchemy. Ingredients can be found everywhere so there&amp;rsquo;s nothing to lose!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="smithing">Smithing&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>With the exception of the quintessential Mage, most adventurers will get some benefit from Smithing. Higher tier weapons and armor have been removed from the random loot lists so your options for obtaining them are limited to hunting very specific enemies or crafting them yourself. Weapons and armor can be improved (a master at the craft can add +10 base damage/armor with a single ingot) but they will degrade back to their original stats as they&amp;rsquo;re used in fights (&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/74790">&lt;em>Simple Degradation&lt;/em>&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="enchanting">Enchanting&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Enchanting will give you the extra oomph you need to go from good to great, no matter your playstyle. Novice enchanters can add noticeable boosts to their gear but it&amp;rsquo;s a long investment before one can rival the skill of an adept or expert enchanter. Until then, keep an eye out for enchanted gear from merchants. The price tag can be daunting but the benefits of a well picked enchantment are worth it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="additional-reading-1">Additional Reading&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/57138">&lt;em>Thaumaturgy - An Enchanting Overhaul&lt;/em>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/52130">&lt;em>Apothecary - An Alchemy Overhaul&lt;/em>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="4-combat">4. Combat&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Removing combat related HUD elements alone increases difficulty but keep in mind there are additional changes to combat under the hood. For starters, you&amp;rsquo;ll be more vulnerable when on the offensive, such as power attacking, drawing a bow, or casting a spell. A poorly timed attack could send you to an early grave so pick your spots carefully.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Tip:&lt;/strong> Even though health bars were removed, &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/46501">&lt;em>Just Blood&lt;/em>&lt;/a> will add increasing bloody overlays on enemies as a rough indicator of their Health. Keep an eye out for this subtle effect.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>On top of that, enemies have been placed into tiers and you&amp;rsquo;ll want to build your strength up before tackling some of them. For example, Falmer and Dwemer ruins are best avoided until Lv20 or so, and Daedra until Lv30. Of course, this is just a general rule, but keep that in mind if you run into a figurative wall on your adventures. Dragons in particular are much tougher than they are in the vanilla game, with their levels soaring higher than your Lv50 cap. But you&amp;rsquo;re Dovahkiin, you&amp;rsquo;ll figure it out. Learning and paying attention to the resistances of an enemy will be a huge boon in your favor when tackling challenging creatures.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="followers">Followers&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It sounds like the deck is stacked against you, and in many ways it is. But you don&amp;rsquo;t have to go it alone. Keep in mind the following changes when bringing a follower along:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>NPCs, including followers, use ammo the same way you do. If your follower uses a bow, make sure to keep them supplied with arrows.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Followers and summoned/reanimated creatures are affected by the same difficulty modifiers as you, the player. This makes them much less effective at higher levels without compensating with better equipment.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Followers who run out of Health will be in a &amp;ldquo;downed&amp;rdquo; state for up to 2 minutes unless healed by Restoration magic. Enemies will ignore them in this state, redirecting their ire towards you. (&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/41228">&lt;em>STAYDOWN&lt;/em>&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mercenaries will charge more for their services based on factors such as their level. (&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/45677">&lt;em>Dynamic Mercenary Fees&lt;/em>&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="relevant-control-changes-1">Relevant Control Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lock On:&lt;/strong> &lt;code>Middle Mouse Button&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Cycle Targets:&lt;/strong> &lt;code>Mouse Scroll Wheel Up/Down&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Locking on is a convenient way to keep an enemy centered on your screen in first-person or third-person perspective. It&amp;rsquo;s a completely optional mechanic and offers no mechanical advantage otherwise. You&amp;rsquo;ll still need to aim at your targets, even when locked on.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="additional-reading-2">Additional Reading&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/34549">&lt;em>Blade &amp;amp; Blunt - A Combat Overhaul&lt;/em>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/33487">&lt;em>Arena - An Encounter Zone Overhaul&lt;/em>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/51310">&lt;em>Dragon War - A Dragon Overhaul&lt;/em>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="tips--tricks">Tips &amp;amp; Tricks&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As you can probably infer from the name of this addon, your adventure in Skyrim will have its difficult moments. Here are some tips that I’ve found useful for making the journey in one piece.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="early-game-level-1---10">Early Game (Level 1 - 10)&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="take-it-easy-and-start-small">Take it Easy and Start Small&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>You’ve just escaped Helgen by the skin of your teeth. You don’t have much to your name, and you don’t have nifty perks that deliver the pain to your enemies. Take a moment to collect yourself in town. Craft a bit and make a little money to get yourself started. The Skyrim Uncapper is configured to give less character exp for your crafting skills, so there’s no need to worry about overleveling yourself out of the gate. There will be plenty of time to delve into dungeons later. Make sure you’re properly equipped now.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="stay-in-range-of-whiterun">Stay in Range of Whiterun&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The urge to explore is strong but try to fight it off in the early game. There is plenty to do in Whiterun Hold once you’ve reached Riverwood, and that content should get you to Level 10 without too many hitches. A &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/17576">&lt;em>Missives&lt;/em>&lt;/a> board can be found in Whiterun if you need additional tasks. Bleak Falls Barrow can be handled easily by Level 5, though you may want to wait until you’re in the Level 10-15 range before tackling Dragon Rising. Also, buy Breezehome. All of the other homes are more expensive and you’ll need someplace reliable to store your valuables until you can afford them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="bring-a-light">Bring a Light&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The interior lighting is changed so that light comes from visible, reasonable sources. Torches, candles, windows, etc. and so on. This can make certain areas, such as dungeons, quite dark at times. Carry a source of light with you (such as a torch) so that you don&amp;rsquo;t find yourself lost in the shadows.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="mid-game-level-10---30">Mid Game (Level 10 - 30)&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="find-a-follower">Find a Follower&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, consider choosing someone to accompany you on your adventures. Ideally they should complement your skill set. If you&amp;rsquo;re a frontliner, consider a follower good at archery (supply them with arrows!) or magic. Or vice versa if you like to attack from range. Just remember to provide them with quality equipment as their usefulness will plummet if they can&amp;rsquo;t keep up in fights.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="buy-a-horse">Buy a Horse&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Okay, now forget what I just said about staying local. It’s time to explore and get into the thick of it! Time passes fast on the overworld so unless you want to spend all of daylight traveling from Point A to Point B, invest in a horse to shorten your travel times. And if you’re really going far I recommend making use of the carriages from time to time. Since your carry weight (and that of your follower) is halved, horses are also the best way to move a lot of supplies from one place to another. (Press &lt;code>H&lt;/code> while looking at the horse to use its saddlebags.)&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="join-a-faction">Join a Faction&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Go find yourself a faction (i.e. The Companions) that suits your character and sign up. Their quests will support the skills you’re looking to improve. As you progress through the tier, also consider signing up for the Stormcloaks or the Imperial Legion if you have a stake in the civil war. Their quests are less focused but they’ll provide plenty of targets to practice on for more experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="late-game-level-30---50">Late Game (Level 30 - 50)&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="spend-your-septims">Spend Your Septims&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>At this point you probably have a hole burning in your pocket from a pile of extra septims. Spend it! You get 5 training opportunities per level, use your gold to bump skills towards a perk you desperately need. Or buy high quality equipment that just isn&amp;rsquo;t appearing for you in boss chests. Don&amp;rsquo;t hoard your wealth like the dragons you&amp;rsquo;re meant to kill; put your money to good use.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="utilize-crafting">Utilize Crafting&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I can’t stress this enough. In the late game you might deal with areas that are scaled above your Level 50 limit, some at that point before you even reach the cap. You’ll want every advantage you can get to bridge the gap and most of those advantages are obtained through crafting. If you ignored this early on, now’s a good time to reconsider it. If on Master or Legendary difficulty, you might even need to make different equipment sets for different types of enemies.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="and-draughts-of-fate-unwound">And Draughts of Fate Unwound&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Combining the previous two tips into one, don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to use your excess cash on Draughts of Fate Unwound from apothecaries. These will refund all of your perk points, allowing you to redistribute them in ways that are more useful to your current goals. Can&amp;rsquo;t find the highest tier gear? Use a draught and craft it yourself. Already crafted everything you need and no longer want the crafting perks? Use a draught and spend those points on other skills. (For this reason it&amp;rsquo;s not a bad idea to dabble in all 3 crafting skills regardless of your build as you play.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skyrim-Se: Changelog</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sss/changelog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sss/changelog/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="release-500b">Release 5.0.0b&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Details to come later.&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;h5 id="frameworks">Frameworks&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Beautifully Overhauled and Objectively Better Icons Enriched for SkyUI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Constructible Object Custom Keyword System NG&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Andrealphus&amp;rsquo; Papyrus Functions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="essentials">Essentials&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Vanilla Complex Parallax - College of Winterhold&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vanilla Complex Parallax - Markarth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vanilla Complex Parallax - Minor Architecture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vanilla Complex Parallax - Riften&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vanilla Complex Parallax - Solitude&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vanilla Complex Parallax - Whiterun&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vanilla Complex Parallax - Windhelm&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vanilla Complex Parallax - Clutter and Furniture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vanilla Complex Parallax - Dawnguard&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vanilla Complex Parallax - Dragonborn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vanilla Complex Parallax - Dungeons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vanilla Complex Parallax - Farmhouses&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vanilla Complex Parallax - Landscape&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="controls">Controls&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Hank&amp;rsquo;s Gamepad and Controller Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="texture--mesh-fixes">Texture &amp;amp; Mesh Fixes&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Whiterun Fence Base Seam Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Whiterun Mesh Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Whiterun Wall Rubble Fixed&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="general-fixes">General Fixes&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added LOD Unloading Bug Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="skse-plugins---fixes">SKSE Plugins - Fixes&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Alchemy XP Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Universal Rim Lighting Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="interface">Interface&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Kome&amp;rsquo;s Inventory Tweaks&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="optional-widescreen-support">(Optional) Widescreen Support&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added NORDIC UI - 21x9 Aspect Ratio Support&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added NORDIC UI - 32x9 Aspect Ratio Support&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="lod-resources">LOD Resources&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed xLODGen Resource - SSE Terrain Tamriel&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="mesh-improvements">Mesh Improvements&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Whiterun Objects SMIMed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Better Whiterun Floors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Whiterun Dragonsreach Double Door Mesh and Placement Fix - 3D Whiterun Trellis Expansion Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed 3D Trellis Improved - Gildergreen Plaza&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Sconces of Solstheim - Improved DLC2 Braziers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Whiterun Objects SMIMed - Warmaiden&amp;rsquo;s Holes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Sconces of Skyrim - Markarth and Dwemer Braziers Improved&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Sconces of Solitude - Unique Solitude Braziers - Base Object Swapper&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="graphics-baseline">Graphics Baseline&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Skyland - Whiterun - Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Skyland Offset Shingles Fixed - Aligned Whiterun Roofs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Modified Skyland AIO&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Tomato&amp;rsquo;s Whiterun - Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="community-shaders">Community Shaders&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed SSE Parallax Shader Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="landscape">Landscape&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed ERM - Enhanced Rocks and Mountains - Rugged Rock Texture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Fantasia Landscapes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Fantasia Landscapes - Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Ashbound - Solstheim Revisited&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Tomato&amp;rsquo;s Complex Landscapes Parallax AIO&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added ERM - Complex Parallax Materials&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="fire--candles">Fire &amp;amp; Candles&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Embers XD - Survival Mode Improved Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="snow--ice">Snow &amp;amp; Ice&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Skyrim Remastered - Glaciers and Ice&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="wild-creatures">Wild Creatures&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Rustic Frostbite Spider&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="magic--perks">Magic &amp;amp; Perks&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Aetherius - Starting Spells Addon (included in main mod)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Aetherius - NPC Spell Absorption Addon (included in main mod)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="crafting">Crafting&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Dragon Priest Hood Variants&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="enemy-overhauls">Enemy Overhauls&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Dragon War - Deadly Spell Impacts Patch (included in main mod)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Dragon War - Dragonactorscript Infinite Loop Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="quest-start-adjustments">Quest Start Adjustments&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Dark Brotherhood Rising Revengeance&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="immersion">Immersion&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Rain Extinguishes Fires&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="miscellaneous">Miscellaneous&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Dragon War - Durnehviir Resurrected Patch (included in main mod)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="sound-fx">Sound FX&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Dragon War - Audio Overhaul for Skyrim Patch (included in main mod)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="saints-and-seducers">Saints and Seducers&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Skyrim Extended Cut - Saints and Seducers - Skyking Signs Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="new--expanded-quests">New &amp;amp; Expanded Quests&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Dragon Hunting - Apothecary Patch (included in main mod)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Dragon Hunting - Paarthurnax Quest Expansion Patch (included in main mod)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Dragon Hunting - AYOPCoW Patch (included in main mod)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Destroy The Dark Brotherhood - Quest Expansion&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="new-animations">New Animations&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Vanargand Animations II - Unarmed Normal And Power Attacks&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="final-patches">Final Patches&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Komegaki&amp;rsquo;s Inventory Tweaks - Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Jonado&amp;rsquo;s Random Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated SSELODGen to b111&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated SSEEdit to 4.1.5f&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD to 3.00 Alpha-173&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Spell Perk Item Distributor to 7.1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Container Item Distributor to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Base Object Swapper to 3.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Inventory Interface Information Injector to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Constructible Object Custom Keyword System to 1.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Custom Skills Framework to 3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Description Framework to 2.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Object Categorization Framework to 5.6.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Crash Logger to 1.14.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated powerofthree&amp;rsquo;s Tweaks to 1.10.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Unofficial Skyrim Special Edition Patch to 4.3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Navigator - Navmesh Fixes to 1.5.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated More Information Console to 1.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Open Animation Replacer to 2.3.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Rock Traps Trigger Fixes to 1.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Assorted Mesh Fixes to 0.105&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyrim Landscape and Water Fixes to 8.7.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Landscape Fixes For Grass Mods to 5.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skill of Sneaking to 1.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated CoMAP - Common Marker Addon Project to 4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dialogue History to 1.1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NORDIC UI - Oxygen Meter 2 Patch to 1.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NORDIC UI - More Informative Console to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated SkyUI - 21x9 Aspect Ratio Support to 3.8.9&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated SkyUI - 32x9 Aspect Ratio Support to 3.8.9&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD - Resources to 3.00 Alpha-50&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD - Scripts to 2.82.9&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Static Mesh Improvement Mod Improvement Mod to 1.10&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Better Whiterun Floors to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyrim Objects SMIMed - Noble Furniture to 0.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyland AIO - Better Imperial Forts to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Particle Patch for ENB to 1.3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Terrain Parallax Blending Fix to 4.3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Subsurface Scattering to 1.0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Azurite Weathers II to 2.57&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Natural Waterfalls to 2.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Window Shadows RT - Updated (no version change)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DALC Fix Preset to 4.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Embers XD to 3.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simplicity of Snow to 0.20&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simplicity of Snow - Parallax to 0.20&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Snowy Surfaces Sound Collision and Aesthetics to 1.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Snowy Ships for Snowy Regions to 2.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Icy Mesh Remaster to 2.41&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Aspens Ablaze to 2.37&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Aspens Ablaze - DynDOLOD 3 Add-On to 2.36.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Aspens Ablaze - DynDOLOD 3 Add-On - Performance to 2.36.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Cathedral - 3D Mountain Flowers - Base Object Swapper to 0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Unique Wooden Bridges to 0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyking Signs to 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyking Unique Signs to 1.03&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Designs of the Nords to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Forgotten Retex Project to 8.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Scallions of Skyrim - High Polygon Leeks to 0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Silver Armor and Weapons Retexture to 2.0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon Priest Retexture to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Sleek Nose On Winter Bears - Enhanced and Reshaped Snout to 1.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Iconic&amp;rsquo;s Spiders of Skyrim to 1.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Better Third Person Selection to 0.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Adamant - A Perk Overhaul to 5.9.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mundus - A Standing Stone Overhaul to 1.13&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mundus - A Standing Stone Overhaul - USSEP Patch to 1.13&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Aetherius - A Race Overhaul to 2.14.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Stormcrown - A Shout Overhaul to 1.1.17&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Artificer - Xavbio Textures Addon to 1.0.11&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Gourmet - A Cooking Overhaul to 1.1.12&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Gourmet - AI Overhaul Patch to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Gourmet - Cooking Pots and Baking Ovens to 1.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Gourmet - Hearthfire Crispy Dumplings Patch to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Misc Dialogue Edits to 1.9.5.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated More Dialogue Options to 1.5.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Misc Dialogue Edits - NGCDT Patch to 1.9.5.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Visiting Advisor Outfit Tweak (no version change)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Scared of Shootings to 0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Blade and Blunt - A Combat Overhaul to 3.7.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dynamic Random Dragons to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Wait Your Turn - Sands of Time Patch yto 1.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - A Dragon Overhaul to 4.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Misc Dialogue Edits - Save the Icerunner Patch to 1.9.5.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated More Dialogue Options - AYOP Thieves Guild Patch to 1.5.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Misc Dialogue Edits - Bring Meeko to Lod Patch to 1.9.5.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Falmer Equip Armor to 1.1.11&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Default Face NPCs Fixed - Fishing to 1.19.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated COTN - Morthal - Patch Collection to 3.2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated COTN - Falkreath to 1.3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated COTN - Falkreath - Patch Collection to 1.22&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Gourmet - COTN Cooking Pots and Baking Ovens Patch to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Seasonal Landscapes - Additions to 1.10&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Seasonal Landscapes - Unfrozen - More Patches to 1.10.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Extended Cut Saints and Seducers - Mysticism Rebalance to 2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated House of Horrors - Quest Expansion to 1.13&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Only Cure - Quest Expansion to 1.03&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Innocence Lost - Quest Expansion to 1.11&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon Hunting to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Beyond Skyrim Morrowind - Bonemold Weapon Pack to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Gourmet - Actual Sweet Roll Variants Patch to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated EVG Conditional Idles to 1.51&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPC Animation Remix to 1.9&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Gourmet - Tamrielic Distribution Patch to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Gourmet - Tamrielic Distribution &amp;amp; Hand to Hand Patch to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Gourmet - Tamrielic Distribution &amp;amp; Rare Curios Patch to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated COTN - Optimized Meshes to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-500a3">Release 5.0.0a3&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The good news is that Alpha 2 had no new issues. The bad news is that I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to test Alpha 3 before my upcoming 2-week vacation so I&amp;rsquo;m keeping it as an Alpha. Provided Alpha 3 has no major issues, the next version should be the beta. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect there to be many problems here, maybe a few minor visual issues due to Dynamic Cubemaps or Seasonal Landscapes - Unfrozen, but the game is playable and most reports said the performance is great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Issues fixed since last Alpha:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Characters carrying shields will properly use them for cover in the rain, equipped or not.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Terrain blending is much better than it was.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Draugr are no longer insomniacs waiting for you in the last room of a dungeon.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Favorites menu controls &lt;em>mostly&lt;/em> fixed. Pressing ESC/F4 to open the Journal still doesn&amp;rsquo;t close it. I&amp;rsquo;ll clean up these mods once it&amp;rsquo;s sorted.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Issues still unfixed:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Lots of green grass in snowy areas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Solstheim ash isn&amp;rsquo;t snow covered in the winter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Random Dragons occassionally kill themselves (vanilla bug)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This Update is Save-Safe with the previous Alphas. Save inside before updating.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-1">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;h5 id="frameworks-1">Frameworks&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added ImGui Icons&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="essentials-1">Essentials&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Achievement Mods Enabler&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vanilla Complex Parallax - College of Winterhold&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vanilla Complex Parallax - Markarth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vanilla Complex Parallax - Minor Architecture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vanilla Complex Parallax - Riften&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vanilla Complex Parallax - Solitude&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vanilla Complex Parallax - Whiterun&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vanilla Complex Parallax - Windhelm&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vanilla Complex Parallax - Clutter and Furniture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vanilla Complex Parallax - Dawnguard&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vanilla Complex Parallax - Dragonborn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vanilla Complex Parallax - Dungeons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vanilla Complex Parallax - Farmhouses&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vanilla Complex Parallax - Landscape&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deleted all duplicate files in the Vanilla Complex Parallax series&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="controls-1">Controls&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Cobb Controlmap Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Hank&amp;rsquo;s Gamepad and Controller Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Modified Hank&amp;rsquo;s Gamepad and Controller Fixes to include Modern Toggle Walk-Run Fix changes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="skse-plugins---fixes-1">SKSE Plugins - Fixes&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Capture Warmer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Mfg Fix NG&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="skse-plugins---tweaks">SKSE Plugins - Tweaks&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Wash That Blood Off&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="interface-1">Interface&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Dialogue History&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="optional-nordic-ui">(Optional) Nordic UI&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Nordic UI - ImGui Icons&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="graphics-baseline-1">Graphics Baseline&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Terrain Parallax Blending Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="community-shaders-1">Community Shaders&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Subsurface Scattering&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Water Caustics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Water Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added HDR Bloom&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Dynamic Cubemaps&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="fires--candles">Fires &amp;amp; Candles&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added SD&amp;rsquo;s Horn Candles - Horn Candles Double Flame Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fires and Embers Clipping Fix - Realistic Water Two Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="snow--ice-1">Snow &amp;amp; Ice&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Modified Paraphernalia - Snow Colour Fixes to the Standard version&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="appearance">Appearance&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Vanilla Makeup HD&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="architecture">Architecture&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Unique Wooden Bridegs&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="misc-structures">Misc Structures&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Skyking Signs - Books of Skyrim Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Skyking Unique Signs&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="interior--dungeons">Interior &amp;amp; Dungeons&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added SB - Pressure Plate Trap Blending&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="armor--weapons">Armor &amp;amp; Weapons&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed 3-Vane Fletching for Ebony Arrows&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Dynamic Cubemaps - Metals&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="skeleton">Skeleton&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Immersive Equipment Displays - Extra Skeleton Nodes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Modified Immersive Equipment Displays defaults to work with EVG Conditional Idles&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="new--expanded-quests-1">New &amp;amp; Expanded Quests&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Infiltration - Quest Expansion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Infiltration - Quest Expansion - Lawless Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="conflict-resolution">Conflict Resolution&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Resolved texture set issue between Modular Armory and Ebony Armors and Weapons Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Resolved script conflict between Finding Helgi and At Your Own Pace - Thieves Guild&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Resolved a few simple conflicts from Infiltration - Quest Expansion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Resolved conflicts between Skyking Unique Signs and COTN mods&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="configuration">Configuration&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Disabled splashes in Splashes of Storms&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-1">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD to Alpha-169&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Spell Perk Item Distributor to 7.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Keyword Item Distributor to 3.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated KreatE to 1.2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Beautifully Overhauled and Objectively Better Icons Enriched for SkyUI to 2.1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Constructible Object Custom Keyword System NG to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Infinity UI to 2.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPCs Names Distributor to 2.5.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Description Framework to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Object Categorization Framework to 5.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Crash Logger to 1.13.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Photo Mode to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated SSE Engine Fixes to 6.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Unofficial Skyrim Modder&amp;rsquo;s Patch to 2.6.2beta&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Open Animation Replacer to 2.2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Landscape Fixes for Grass Mods to 5.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Light Detachment Fix to 1.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Compass Navigation Overhaul to 2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD - Resources to Alpha-49&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated LOD Model Library for DynDOLOD to 1.5.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Community Shaders to 0.8.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Tree LOD Lighting to 1.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Grass Lighting to 1.4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Screen-Space Shadows to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Complex Parallax Materials to 1.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Light Limit Fix to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Wetness Effect to 1.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Fantasia Landscapes - Parallax to 1.02&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Natural Waterfalls to 2.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Window Shadows RT - Updated to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DALC Fix Preset to 2.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Embers XD to 2.9.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Snowy Ships for Snowy Regions to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Icy Mesh Remaster to 2.41&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Aspens Ablaze to 2.36&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Smaller Cathedral 3D Plants to 1.8.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyking Signs to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Pillows - Xtudo HD Version to 3.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Glass Armors and Weapons Retexture to 2.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Ebony Armors and Weapons Retexture to 2.0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mysticism - A Magic Overhaul to 2.4.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mundus - A Standing Stone Overhaul to 1.12.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mundus - A Standing Stone Overhaul - USSEP Patch to 1.12.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Gourmet - A Cooking Overhaul to 1.1.9&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Narrative Gameplay Consistent Dialogue Tweaks to 1.9.6a&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Blade and Blunt - A Combat Overhaul to 3.6.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPCs Take Cover to 1.01&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Wait Your Turn - Sands of Time Patch to 2.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Dragon Cult - A Draugr Overhaul to 1.4.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Starfrost - Survival Spells Addon to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated COTN - Dawnstar - The Hawking Horker Patch to 1.21&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Seasonal Landscapes - Additions to 1.8.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Whispering Door - Quest Expansion to 1.11&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon Hunting to 1.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon Hunting - Apothecary Patch to 1.0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyrim on Skooma to 69.69&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyrim on Skooma - Gourmet Patch to 1.0.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Beyond Skyrim Morrowind - Bonemold Weapon Pack to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Unofficial Skyrim Modders Patch - Patch Emporium to 1.3.32&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="outputs">Outputs&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regenerated Synthesis Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated LODGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated TexGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated DynDOLOD (and Performance)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-500a2">Release 5.0.0a2&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Issues fixed since last Alpha:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Starting the game with a controller plugged in should no longer crash the game. Nor should plugging one in after launching the game. However, you can&amp;rsquo;t switch between KB&amp;amp;M and Controller at will anymore.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ultrawide options (21:9 and 32:9) are actually supported this time. Instructions on the Installation page have been updated to let people know what to do.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Abandoned Shack has all of its walls once again. It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been &lt;em>that&lt;/em> abandoned.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DynDOLOD now uses the more stable DLL version. This results in a larger output file but should result in far, far fewer crashes when loading saves.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This update is save-safe with 5.0.0a.&lt;/strong> Just make sure to save indoors where DynDOLOD isn&amp;rsquo;t active due to the new outputs.&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-2">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;h5 id="controls-2">Controls&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Auto Input Switch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Modern Toggle Walk-Run Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Cobb Controlmap Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Modified Cobb Controlmap Fix to include Modern Toggle Walk-Run Fix changes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="optional-widescreen-support-1">(Optional) Widescreen Support&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Convenient Dialogue UI - 21x9 Aspect Ratio Support&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Convenient Dialogue UI - 32x9 Aspect Ratio Support&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="lod-resources-1">LOD Resources&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed DynDOLOD - NG&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added DynDOLOD - DLL&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added DynDOLOD - Scripts&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="misc-structures-1">Misc Structures&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Skyrim 3D Signs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Skyrim 3D Signs - Navigation Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Skyrim 3D Signs - Missing Generic Signs Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed A Blacksmith Sign&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Skyking Signs&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="valuable-objects">Valuable Objects&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Stacks of Septims - 3D Coin Piles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Ancient Imperial Septims - Stacks of Septims Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="immersion-1">Immersion&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added C.O.I.N. - Stacks of Septims Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="cities-of-the-north">Cities of the North&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed COTN - Winterhold - Skyrim 3D Signs Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-2">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Object Categorization Framework to 5.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated powerofthree&amp;rsquo;s Tweaks to 1.9.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DALC Fix Preset to 2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Fires and Embers Clipping Fix to 2.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Blade and Blunt - A Combat Overhaul to 3.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPC Animation Remix to 1.8.2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="outputs-1">Outputs&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regenerated DynDOLOD (and Performance)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-500ɑ">Release 5.0.0ɑ&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2024-03-03&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This update is big. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t always meant to be that way. It was supposed to just be 4.19.1, the update where &lt;em>Seasonal Landscapes - Unfrozen&lt;/em> was finally added in all of it&amp;rsquo;s glory. However, as I went through making that happen and testing the results, I kept finding oddities that nagged at me until I was forced to reckon with the remnants of TPF 5.0 Beta that&amp;rsquo;ve been present in the list since 4.16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As it removes all reference to TPF 5.0, it&amp;rsquo;s only fitting that this version is called SSS 5.0 itself. A quick, quick summary of the massive list of changes below:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Visuals have been overhauled. New lighting, new weather, a lot of new textures, and a switch from ENB to &lt;em>Community Shaders&lt;/em>. The game is brighter with a fresh coat of paint, and should perform even better on your computer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Weapons Armor Clothing and Clutter Fixes&lt;/em> has been removed. Still a great mod but it&amp;rsquo;s been marked for removal since SSS 4.16 and this was finally the time to rip off the bandaid. Items have returned to &lt;em>mostly&lt;/em> vanilla stats (there&amp;rsquo;s still &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/83825">Armor Rating Adjustment for Adamant&lt;/a>) for better consistency with added items.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>More Questing &lt;em>At Your Own Pace&lt;/em>. The Companions and Thieves Guild have been switched over to the mod series, giving a bit more uniformity to the three main factions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Seasonal Landscapes - Unfrozen&lt;/em> in all of its glory. The game&amp;rsquo;s calendar has been changed to 28 day &lt;strong>seasons&lt;/strong> so you&amp;rsquo;ll see the change 3x as frequently as you would previously. The game starts in the middle of Summer where things are at their most temperate, followed by Autumn which is what most people are used to. Use this time to prepare for the brutal Winter Skyrim is known for.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This version absolutely needs a new save file! Don&amp;rsquo;t even try it. Seriously. Crash City.&lt;/strong> Also keep is mind that this is an &lt;em>Alpha&lt;/em> release. There&amp;rsquo;s no guarantee that the next release will be save-safe with this one. This is primarily for testing and working out the bugs before releasing a &lt;em>Beta&lt;/em> which is expected to be more stable and likely to be save-safe with the full release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pop the full details below for the list of changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-3">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Several mods have been reinstalled with different compatibility options or archives to account for other changes, including but not limited to enabled Complex Parallax Materials. These have not been noted because the changelog is already long enough as is.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="mod-organizer-2">Mod Organizer 2&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Fluency Themes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Bethesda Plugin Manager&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="skyui">SkyUI&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Sky UI - Remove QuickSave Button&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added SkyUI - Quest Journal Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="frameworks-2">Frameworks&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed KiLoader for Skyrim&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added KreatE&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Constructible Object Custom Keyword System NG&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Object Categorization Framework&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Item Property Manipulator&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="essentials-2">Essentials&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Weapons Armor Clothing and Clutter Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Script Optimization and Fixes Compilation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Unofficial Skyrim Modder&amp;rsquo;s Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Achievements Mods Enabler&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="animations">Animations&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Moved Flute Animation Fix (from TPF 5.0 Fixes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved No Spinning Death Animation (from TPF 5.0 Fixes)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="general-fixes-1">General Fixes&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Keywords Fixed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Mannequin Management&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Lights Out - Solitude Lighthouse Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed College of Winterhold Quest Start Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Chillwind Depths CTD Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Robber&amp;rsquo;s Gorge Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vampire Allies Factions Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Motionless Rocks Killing People Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved DLC2 March of the Dead Fix (from TPF 5.0 Fixes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Butterflies Land True (from TPF 5.0 Fixes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Shalidor&amp;rsquo;s Maze Puzzle Sound Fix (from TPF 5.0 Fixes)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="script-fixes">Script Fixes&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Simply Optimized Scripts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed WIDeadBodyCleanupScript Crash Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed World Encounter Hostility Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed High Gate Ruins Puzzle Reset Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Mage Armor Script Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed MQ104PlayerScript Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Magic Student (WIChangeLocation04) Quest Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed King Olaf&amp;rsquo;s Fire Festival Not Ending Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Scare My Enemy Bug Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Modern Clap Bug Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed CritterSpawn Congestion Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Dragonactorscript Infinite Loop Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Neloth&amp;rsquo;s Experimental Subject Quest (DLC2TTR4a) Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="tpf-50-fixes">TPF 5.0 Fixes&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Nilheim BQ Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Potema Minion&amp;rsquo;s Fixlet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Nifty AI Tweaks AIO&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Dawnguard Don&amp;rsquo;t Hunt Cured Vampires&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Charge Dialogue Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Rude Imperial Soldiers Escort Prisoner Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Nordic Carved Clipping Fix (incorp. into Conflict Resolution)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed NPC&amp;rsquo;s Run and Walk at Your Pace&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Move It Dammit&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed No More Standing Too Close&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Don&amp;rsquo;t Talk With Your Mouth Full&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Followers Don&amp;rsquo;t Draw Weapons (incorp. into Conflict Resolution)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Avanchnzel Dwemer Piston Sound Hotfix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Butterflies Unchained&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Dawnguard Rune Axe Bug Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Allow Dialogue Progress Bugfix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Section (moved everything else to other sections)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="texture--mesh-fixes-1">Texture &amp;amp; Mesh Fixes&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Sound Hammering Sounds&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="skse-plugins---fixes-2">SKSE Plugins - Fixes&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Stagger Direction Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Stagger Direction Fix - NG&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Swapped Combat Music Fix to &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/110459">this mod&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Stagger Effect Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Sky Reflection Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Grass Sampler Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added TAA Sharpen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Light Detachment Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="general-tweaks">General Tweaks&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed NARC Remade - No Animals Report Crimes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed NARC Remade - Vampire Allies Faction Fix Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Wedding Wreath Is Enchantable&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Simply Smaller Wolves (from TPF 5.0 Fixes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Dwemer Gates Don&amp;rsquo;t Reset (from TPF 5.0 Fixes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Assorted Tiny Tweaks - Roggvir&amp;rsquo;s Amulet of Talos (from TPF 5.0 Fixes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Armor Rating Adjustment for Adamant&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Creation Club - Adjustments, Rebalancing, and Variants&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="skse-plugins---tweaks-1">SKSE Plugins - Tweaks&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Soaking Wet - Character Wetness Effect&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Custom Window&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Desktop Splash Screen&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="interface-2">Interface&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed moreHUD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed moreHUD - Settings Loader&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Weapons - I4 Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Shouts - I4 Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Standing Stones - I4 Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="skse-plugins---interface">SKSE Plugins - Interface&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Moved Horse Stamina HUD (from Miscellaneous)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Instantly Skip Dialogue&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Regional Save Names&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="optional-nordic-ui-1">(Optional) Nordic UI&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added NORDIC UI - Quest Journal Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added NORDIC UI - Active Effects for SkyUI (just in case people enable them)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added NORDIC UI - More Informative Console&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="optional-widescreen-support-2">(Optional) Widescreen Support&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed SkyUI - Remove QuickSave Button - 21x9 Aspect Ratio Support&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Constructible Object Custom Keyword System - 21x9 Aspect Ratio Support&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added SkyUI - 32x9 Aspect Ratio Support&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="lod-resources-2">LOD Resources&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added DynDOLOD - TexGen Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="mesh-improvements-1">Mesh Improvements&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Windhelm Bridge Stairs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Markarth Fixed AF (from Mountains &amp;amp; Rocks)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added The Citadel of Snow - The Windhelm Bridge Reforged&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Better Windhelm Ground Meshes - Valunstrad&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Whiterun Objects SMIMed - Dragonreach Stairs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Whiterun Objects SMIMed - Warmaiden&amp;rsquo;s Holes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="graphics-baseline-2">Graphics Baseline&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Moved Particle Patch for ENB (from ENBSeries)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Restored &lt;code>vampirecattle&lt;/code> textures to Ruins Clutter Improved&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Skyland AIO - Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Skyland - Whiterun - Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Skyland - Solitude - Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Shaders of Solstheim - Ash and Moss - Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="enbseries">ENBSeries&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed ENBSeries - Binaries&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed ENBSeries - Settings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed ENB Helper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed ENB Helper Plus&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed ENB Input Disabler&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed ENB Extender for Skyrim&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed ENB IMOD Separator&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Section (moved everything else to other sections)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="community-shaders-2">Community Shaders&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Section&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added SSE Parallax Shader Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Community Shaders&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Tree LOD Lighting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Grass Lighting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Grass Collision&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Screen-Space Shadows&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Complex Parallax Materials&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Water Blending&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Light Limit Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Light Limit Fix - Improved Candleglow Lights&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Light Limit Fix - Particle Lights Instead of Fake Glow&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Water Caustics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Water Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Wetness Effect&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="weather--sky">Weather &amp;amp; Sky&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Cathedral Night Sky&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Skygazer Moons - Masser and Secunda HD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Mists of Tamriel&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Mists of Tamriel - Settings Loader&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved No More Blinding Fog (from ENBSeries)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Azurite Mists&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Azurite Weathers II&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Rally&amp;rsquo;s Celestial Canvas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Twilight&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="landscape-1">Landscape&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Depths of Skyrim - An Underwater Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim - Depths of Skyrim Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Stones of Solitude - Better Blended Rock Piles (from Mountains &amp;amp; Rocks)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added ERM - Enhanced Rocks and Mountains&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added ERM - Enhanced Rocks and Mountains - DynDOLOD Add-On&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added ERM - Enhanced Rocks and Mountains - Rugged Rock Texture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fantasia Landscapes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fantasia Landscapes - Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Natural Waterfalls&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Natural Waterfalls - Markarth Mossy AF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="lighting">Lighting&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Renamed section (from Lux Lighting)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Lux&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Lux - Contraband Confiscation Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Lux - Pilgrim - Daedric Shrines&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed High Hrothgar Fixed - Lux Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed ENB Complex Particle Lights for Windows&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Lux Via&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Lux Orbis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Lux Orbis - Misc Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed High Hrothgar Fixed - Lux Orbis Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Window Shadows RT&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Window Shadows RT - Updated&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added WindowShadows - High Hrothgar Fixed Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Skyrim is Luminous&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added DALC Fix Preset&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="fire--candles-1">Fire &amp;amp; Candles&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed WeldingMans Smelter with ENB Light&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed ENB Particle Lights - Dwemer Lanterns&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Rudy Fix for Smoke (from ENBSeries)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Diverse Campfires - Base Object Swapper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Diverse Campfires - FLM Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fires and Embers Clipping Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Fires and Embers Clipping Fix - SB - Fixed Windhelm Entrance Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="visual-fx">Visual FX&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Improved Weapon Impact Effects&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Parallax Spell Impacts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Particle Lights for ENB - Light Orbs - Motes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Falmer Pullchain ENB Light&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Rain Extinguishes Fires&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Word Wall Transparency Fix for ENB (from ENBSeries)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved No More Blinding Fog (from ENBSeries)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Ghost Pile Seam Fix (from ENBSeries)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Deadly Spell Impacts - Cleaned and Upscaled&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Deadly Spell Impacts - AOS ISC Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Parallax Spell Impacts - AOS ISC Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="mountains--rocks">Mountains &amp;amp; Rocks&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Majestic Mountains&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Majestic Mountains - Double-Sided Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Skyrim - A Mountainous Experience&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Majestic Mountains - More Accurate Collision&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Majestic Mountains - More Accurate Collision - AME Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Majestic Mountains - LOD Pack&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Stones of Solitude - Majestic Mountains Rocks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Section (moved everything else to other sections)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="water--splash-fx">Water &amp;amp; Splash FX&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Rudy Fix for Splashes Of Storms and ENB&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Water Effects Brightness and Reflection Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Water Effects Brightness and Reflection Fix - Realistic Water Two Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Water Effects Brightness and Reflection Fix - Splashes of Skyrim&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="snow--ice-2">Snow &amp;amp; Ice&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Simplicity of Snow - Majestic Mountains Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Majestic Snow&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Majestic Snow - Projecteddiffuse&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Majestic Snow - LOD Resources&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Actually Flat Flat Snow Drifts (from ENBSeries)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Modified Snowy Surfaces Sound Collision and Aesthetics to add the Unfrozen patch, made an edit to &lt;code>seasons\Unfrozen_SUM.ini&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Arctic - Frost Effects - ISC Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Simplicity of Snow - Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Paraphernalia - Snow Colour Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Snowy Statics Consistency&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Snowy Carts for Snowy Regions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Snowy Ships for Snowy Regions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="improved-trees">Improved Trees&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Happy Little Trees - Less Vibrant Pine Wood&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Happy Little Trees - Aspen Trees&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Happy Little Trees - Aspen Addendum&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Spooknik&amp;rsquo;s Tundra Trees&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Cathedral - 3D Thicket and Dead Shrub&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Happy Little Trees - DLC Trees&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Aspens Ablaze&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Aspens Ablaze - DynDOLOD 3 Add-On&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Aspens Ablaze - DynDOLOD 3 Add-On - Performance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Alternate Marsh for Happy Little Trees&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Skyland Happy Little Trees Bark&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Skyland Happy Little Trees Bark - Aspens Ablaze Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added TMD The Rift Leaves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added TMD The Rift Leaves - Seasons Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Happy Little Trees - Lighter Pine Trees&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="grass-overhaul">Grass Overhaul&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Landscapes - Cathedral Concept&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Cathedral Landscrapes - Snow as Marsh Grass Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Origins of Forest&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Origins of Forest - ENB Complex Grass&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed QW&amp;rsquo;s Grass Patch 2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed QW&amp;rsquo;s Grass Patch 2 - ENB Complex Grass&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Folkvangr Clutter Remover&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="plants--mushrooms">Plants &amp;amp; Mushrooms&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Cathedral - 3D Mountain Flowers - Hearthfire Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Cathedral - 3D Mountain Flowers - Resized and Desaturated&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed High Poly Fern Meshes by mindflux&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Rudy HQ - More Lights for ENB - Nirnroots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Better Nirnroot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Mari&amp;rsquo;s Reach Ferns - Vanilla Mesh Tweaks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed ICFur&amp;rsquo;s Improved Reach Fern&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Rudy HQ - More Lights for ENB - Glowing Mushrooms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Cathedral - 3D Tundra Shrubs (from Improved Trees)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Reach Fern Texture Replacer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Smaller Cathedral 3D Plants&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Subtypes of Snowberries - Base Object Swapper&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="appearance-1">Appearance&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Detailmap Seamfix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Ethereal Elven Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Subsurface Scattering Shaders for Skins&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="raid-weathers">RAID Weathers&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed RAID Weathers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Mists of Tamriel - RAID Weathers Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Section&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="enb-presets">ENB Presets&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed The Vanilla ENB Two&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed The Vanilla ENB Two (Performance)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Rudy ENB - Raindrops&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Section&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="architecture-1">Architecture&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed FYX - 3D Shack Kit Walls - Lux Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed FYX - 3D Shack Kit Walls - Froki&amp;rsquo;s Shack and Abandoned Shack Fix - Lux Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Real 3D Walls&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Simplicity of Snow - 3D Walls Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Skyrim Landscape Overhaul - Stone Walls&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved FYX - 3D Whiterun Tree Circle (from Lighting)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Classic HD Remastered Farmhouses&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FYX - 3D Farmhouse Walkway&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FYX - 3D Farmhouse Walkway - SLaWF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FYX - 3D Farmhouse Walkway - Simplicity of Snow Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FYX - 3D Whiterun Drawbridge Gate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FYX - 3D Whiterun Castle Bridge&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FYX - 3D Whiterun Guard Towers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Whiterun Gatehouse Castle Walls Mesh Fix - FYX and SMIM Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FYX - 3D Whiterun Scaffold&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FYX - 3D Dock Ramp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FYX - Solitude Arch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FYX - Black-Briar and Riftweald Manors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FYX - The Temple of Mara&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FYX - 3D Honeyside Deck Floor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FYX - Palace of The Kings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FYX - Windhelm Stable Roof&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FYX - Hrothgar Steps Collisions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Improved Solitude Walls&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FYX - RavenRock Docks and Fences Round Posts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Rally&amp;rsquo;s Riekling Outposts - Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="misc-structures-2">Misc Structures&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Rally&amp;rsquo;s Handcarts - Base Object Swapper&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="interiors--dungeons">Interiors &amp;amp; Dungeons&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed RUSTIC ALCHEMY TABLE - for Revamped Assets Skyrim&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Centered Blue Palace Throne&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Centered Blue Palace Throne - Window Shadows Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Alchemy Station Variants - Base Object Swapper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Alchemy Station Variants - ElSopa Potions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added WeldingMans Enchanting Table Variants - No ENB Light&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added FYX - Imperial Doors Collisions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="various-clutter">Various Clutter&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Static Swaps Variety - Fishing Poles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Static Swaps Variety - Festival Flags&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="valuable-objects-1">Valuable Objects&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Rudy HQ - More Lights for ENB - Soul Gems&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Rustic Animated Potions and Poisons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Apothecary Patch for Potion Remodels&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved ElSopa - Potions Redone (from ElSopa&amp;rsquo;s Potions Redone)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved ElSopa - Potions Redone - Missing Vanilla Potions (from ElSopa&amp;rsquo;s Potions Redone)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved ElSopa - Potions Redone - Falmer Blood Elixir (from ElSopa&amp;rsquo;s Potions Redone)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved ElSopa - Potions Redone - Apothecary Patch (from ElSopa&amp;rsquo;s Potions Redone)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Vaermina&amp;rsquo;s Torpor - Xtudo&amp;rsquo;s Version (from ElSopa&amp;rsquo;s Potions Redone)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved The White Phial - Xtudo&amp;rsquo;s Version (from ElSopa&amp;rsquo;s Potions Redone)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Sleeping Tree Sap - Xtudo&amp;rsquo;s Version (from ElSopa&amp;rsquo;s Potions Redone)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Potion of Blood - Xtudo&amp;rsquo;s Version (from ElSopa&amp;rsquo;s Potions Redone)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="food-ingredients--potions">Food, Ingredients, &amp;amp; Potions&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Renamed Section (from Food &amp;amp; Ingredients)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Removed Alchemy Ingredients ENB Light&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Subdivide and Smooth - Hagraven - Alchemy Ingredients ENB Light Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Survival Stews - SMIM Meshes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="clothing--jewelry">Clothing &amp;amp; Jewelry&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed several files from RUSTIC CLOTHING that are now overridden&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="armors--weapons">Armors &amp;amp; Weapons&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Open Face Guard Helmets - WACCF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Frankly HD Shrouded Armor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Frankly HD Thieves Guild Armors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Frankly HD Nightingale Armor and Weapons&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="xavbios-retextures">Xavbio&amp;rsquo;s Retextures&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Robes Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Ancient Falmer Armors and Weapons Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Dark Brotherhood Armors Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vampire Armors and Weapons Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Thieves Guild Armors Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Dawnguard Armors and Weapons Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Nightingale Armor and Weapons Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="undead-daedra--dragons">Undead, Daedra, &amp;amp; Dragons&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Skeleton Replacer HD - Lux Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Skeleton Replacer HD - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Arvak Burning Hooves Restored&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Iconic&amp;rsquo;s Arvak Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="elsopas-potions-redone">ElSopa&amp;rsquo;s Potions Redone&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed ElSopa - Potions Redone - ELIF Inventory Size Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed ElSopa - Potions Redone - Praedy&amp;rsquo;s Soul Husk Extract&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed ElSopa Potions Redone - Less Emissive and Fixed Inventory Size&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed ElSopa Potions Redone - Less Emissive and Fixed Inventory Size - Xtudo ELIF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Modified all other mods in this section to be ENB Light-free&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Section (moved everything else to Valuable Objects)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="magic--perks-1">Magic &amp;amp; Perks&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Mysticism - Poison Crash Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Mysticism - USSEP Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Mysticism - Deadly Spell Impacts Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="crafting-1">Crafting&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Simple Smithing Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Artificer - Bandit War Expanded Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Artificer - Bond of Matrimony Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Simple Smithing Overhaul Simplified&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Onyx textures to CCOR - Assets for Jewelry Crafting Expanded&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Artificer - At Your Own Pace - Companions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Artificer - Madmen Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="alchemy-cooking--farming">Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Apothecary - Rustic Animated Potions and Poisons Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Cooking Categories Improvement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Simplicity of Seeding&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Gourmet - True Homecooked Meals Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="npc-dialogue--behavior">NPC Dialogue &amp;amp; Behavior&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed AI Overhaul - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Tavern AI Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Hunters Not Bandits&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vilkas Outsider Comment Conditions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vigilant of Stendarr Improvements and Additions - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Realistic Conversations (from TPF 5.0 Fixes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved No NPC Greetings (from TPF 5.0 Fixes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Ulfric&amp;hellip; Tullius&amp;hellip; Give Me A Break (from TPF 5.0 Fixes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Fugitive Piss Off (from TPF 5.0 Fixes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Assorted Tiny Tweaks - Falion Is Rude (from TPF 5.0 Fixes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added NGCDT - Guard Dialogue Overhaul Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="marriage--adoption">Marriage &amp;amp; Adoption&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Bond of Matrimony (Wedding Band Enhancement - Left Hand Rings)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Vittoria&amp;rsquo;s Alternate Wedding - AI Overhaul Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Vittoria&amp;rsquo;s Alternate Wedding - Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="combat--encounter-zones">Combat &amp;amp; Encounter Zones&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Follower Trap Safety&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Improved Traps - Follower Trap Safety Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Dynamic Weather and Time Based Detection&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Wait Your Turn - Enemy Circling Behaviour (from Enemy Overhauls)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Wait Your Turn - Sands of Time Patch (from Enemy Overhauls)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Seeking Out Sneaks (from Enemy Overhauls)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added NPC Trap Safety - SPID&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added NPCs Take Cover&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Disable NPC Taunt&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="enemy-overhauls-1">Enemy Overhauls&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Timid Beasts - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Dragon War - Dragonactorscript Infinite Loop Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Disable Draugr Combat Idles&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="quest-start-adjustments-1">Quest Start Adjustments&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed At Your Own Pace - College of Winterhold - SSS Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Improved Companions - Questline Tweaks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Aela Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Approach If You Don&amp;rsquo;t Help&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed The Companions - Don&amp;rsquo;t Be A Milk Drinker&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Customizable Companions Questline Progression Requirements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed The Companions Ain&amp;rsquo;t Hachikos&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Improved College Entry - Questline Tweaks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Misc. College of Winterhold Tweaks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Finding Velehk Sain - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Thieves Guild Requirements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Thieves Guild Requirements - Thieves Guild Reformation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Thieves Guild Requirements - Settings Loader&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed More Dialogue Options - Thieves Guild Reformation Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed TPF - Quest Mods Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added At Your Own Pace - Thieves Guild&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added At Your Own Pace - Companions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Save the Icerunner - The Choice is Yours Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added More Dialogue Options - ATOP Thieves Guild Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Diplomatic Dragons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Calcelmo Has Standards&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Calcelmo Has Standards - Say No To Calcelmo TCIY Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="immersion-2">Immersion&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Trade &amp;amp; Barter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Mysticism - Trade and Barter Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Adamant - Trade and Barter Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Trade &amp;amp; Barter - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Candlehearth - Tavern AI Fix Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moved Hawk Patch - Base Object Swapper (from TPF 5.0 Fixes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Candlehearth - USMP Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="miscellaneous-1">Miscellaneous&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Raven Rock - Fix Exit on Horseback&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed TPF - Horse Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Left Hand Rings Modified - 1st Person View&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Left Hand Rings Modified - SkyUI Icon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed PlayerPayCrimeGold Tweak&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Contraband Confiscated - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="survival--fishing">Survival &amp;amp; Fishing&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Fishing - WACCF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="city-overhauls">City Overhauls&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Spaghetti&amp;rsquo;s Cities - NotSoFestive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Spaghetti&amp;rsquo;s Towns - NotSoFestive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Icy Windhelm&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Better Windhelm Ground Meshes - Icy Windhelm&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Dawnstar - The Hawking Horker&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="cities-of-the-north-1">Cities of the North&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed COTN - Dawnstar - Partitioned Meshes for Lighting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed COTN - Morthal - Partitioned Meshes for Lighting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed COTN - Winterhold - Partitioned Meshes for Lighting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Simplicity of Snow - Cities of the North&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added COTN - Dawnstar - The Hawking Horker Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="faction-hqs">Faction HQs&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Spaghetti&amp;rsquo;s Faction Halls - AIO&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Spaghetti&amp;rsquo;s Faction Halls - AIO - No College of Winterhold&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="mandragorasprout-statues">Mandragorasprout&amp;rsquo; Statues&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Daedric Shrines - Mehrunes Dagon - Majestic Mountains Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Statue of Kynareth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Daedric Shrines - Mehrunes Dagon - ERM Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="seasons-of-skyrim">Seasons of Skyrim&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Seasonal Weathers Framework - RAID Weathers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Seasons of Skyrim - Remove Unwanted Grass&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Seasonal Landscapes - Cathedral Landscapes Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Seasonal Landscapes - QW&amp;rsquo;s Grass Patch 2 Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Seasonal Landscapes - Stones of Solitude - MM Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Seasonal Weathers Framework - Azurite Weathers II&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Seasons of Skyrim - Less Snowy Shacks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Snowy Ships for Snowy Regions - Seasonal Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Cathedral - 3D Sword Ferns - Seasons of Skyrim Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Seasonal Landscapes - Whiterun Objects SMIMed Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Seasonal Landscapes - Skyrim Objects SMIMed - Warmaiden&amp;rsquo;s Holes Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Seasonal Landscapes - FYX - 3D Whiterun Tree Circle Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Seasonal Landscapes - FYX - RavenRock Docks and Fences Round Posts Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Seasonal Landscapes - Unfrozen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Seasonal Landscapes - Unfrozen - ENB Complex Grass&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Seasonal Landscapes - Unfrozen - More Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/91634">Seasonal Landscapes - Unfrozen - Remaining&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Seasonal Landscapes - Unfrozen - Windhelm Mesh Fixes (custom patch)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Seasonal Landscapes - Unfrozen Folkvangr&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Seasonal Landscapes - Stones of Solitude Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Seasonal Diverse Tundra Shrubs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Seasonal Spiffed Up Tundra Scrubs&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="saints--seducers">Saints &amp;amp; Seducers&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Skyrim Extended Cut - Saints and Seducers - WACCF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="new--expanded-quests-2">New &amp;amp; Expanded Quests&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Face Sculptor Expanded&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Missives - Unique Missive Boards&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Missives - Quest Edits for Unique Missive Board Mods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Modified Missives - Quest Edits for Unique Missive Board Mods to account for Missives are in Skyrim&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="new-mechanics">New Mechanics&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Dynamic Lowered Hoods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Hand to Hand - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Swapped Pilgrim - Deadric Shrines A.I.O. Patch for &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/109432">this mod&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Skyrim on Skooma&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Skyrim on Skooma - Gourmet Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="new-items">New Items&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Armor and Clothing Extension&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Armor and Clothing Extension - Spell Perk Item Distributor Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Armor and Clothing Extension - ICE AYOP COW Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Thaumaturgy - WACCF ACE Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed aMidianBorn Armor Variants Lite - Simple Smithing Overhaul Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Lunar Armory - Simple Smithing Overhaul Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Ancient Nord Stalhrim - WACCF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Beyond Skyrim Morrowind - Bonemold Weapon Pack - WACCF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Beyond Skyrim Morrowind - Bonemold Weapon Pack - Thaumaturgy WACCF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Beyond Skyrim Morrowind - Bonemold Weapon Pack - Tamrielic Distribution WACCF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Bonemold in Solstheim - An Integration Mod - WACCF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Bonemold Set - Simple Smithing Overhaul Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed East Empire Company Armor - WACCF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed East Empire Company Armor - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Dawnguard Arsenal - WACCF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Dawnguard Arsenal - SSO Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed BCS Lost Library - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Armor and Clothing Extension - Robes Only (with edits)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added aMidianBorn Armor Variants Lite - Simple Smithing Overhaul Simplified Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Lunar Armory - Simple Smithing Overhaul Simplified Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Bonemold Set - Simple Smithing Overhaul Simplified Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Dawnguard Arsenal - Simple Smithing Overhaul Simplified Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="new-creatures--enemies">New Creatures &amp;amp; Enemies&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Civil War Deserters - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed More Werewolves - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Daedric Beasts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Daedric Beasts - Timing is Everything Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Cannibal Draugr on Solstheim - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Nocturnal Moths - Lux Via Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="new-animations-1">New Animations&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added Vanargand Animations II - Unarmed Pugilism Stance&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="content-integration">Content Integration&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Tamrielic Distribution - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Open World Loot - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="final-patches-1">Final Patches&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Removed Mesh Patches for Lux and Lux Orbis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Spelling Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Unique Artefacts Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Old People Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Enchantable Special Item Fix - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removed Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim - Landscape Patch (Performance)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Unofficial Skyrim Modders Patch - Patch Emporium&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added COTN - Optimized Meshes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Keyword Patch Collection&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim - Equipment Conflict Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim - Quest Conflict Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim - Character Conflict Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="conflict-resolution-1">Conflict Resolution&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>For now, separated patch into different modules: Equipment, Quests, Characters, and Other&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Almost all existing enties have been reviewed for current relevance and deleted/moved accordingly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added swap file for Happy Little Shrubs and Seasonal Landscapes - Unfrozen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Resolved many conflicts between Default Face NPCs Fixed and other mods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reverted ONAM of ITMPotionUse &lt;code>000B6435&lt;/code> as it was making the drinking sound silent&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reverted change to Dark Brotherhood kidnapping; it once again requires Delayed Burial to be completed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edited Nocturnal Moths script to account for Four Seasons changes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edited Seasonal Weathers Framework scripts to account for Four Seasons changes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edited Azurite Weathers II script to account for Four Seasons changes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edited Seasonal Alchemy - Add-on scripts to account for Four Seasons changes (some critters will disappear during Winter, a few will also disappear during Autumn)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="updates-3">Updates&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD to 3.00 Alpha-167&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Address Library for SKSE Plugins to 11.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated PapyrusUtil to 4.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated JContainers to 4.2.9&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Keyword Item Distributor to 3.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Sound Record Distributor to 1.5.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Scaleform Translation Plus Plus to 1.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Fuz Ro D-oh - Silent Voice to 2.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Constructible Object Custom Keyword System to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Photo Mode to 1.3.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated powerofthree&amp;rsquo;s Tweaks to 1.9.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Unofficial Skyrim Special Edition Patch to 4.3a&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Navigator - Navmesh Fixes to 1.5.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Classic Sprinting Redone to 2.3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Paired Animation Improvements to 1.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Open Animation Replacer to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Glowing Mushroom Collision Fixes to 1.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyrim Landscape and Water Fixes to 8.5.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Capture Warmer to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Oxygen Meter 2 to 1.0.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD - NG to Alpha-15&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated LOD Model Library for DynDOLOD to 1.4.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Markarth Fixed AF (FOMOD Update)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated High Hrothgar Fixed to 1.07&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyland AIO to 4.32&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyland Bits and Bobs - A Clutter Overhaul to 1.9&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Particle Patch for ENB to 1.2.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Storm Lightning to 1.4.21&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Embers XD to 2.9.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Water In Wells - Mesh-only Animated Wells to 0.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Rally&amp;rsquo;s Solstheim Plants to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Spice Of Life - Orc Longhouses - FYX 3D Patches to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Rally&amp;rsquo;s Crates to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Rally&amp;rsquo;s Market Stalls to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Pillows - Xtudo HD Version to 3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Rally&amp;rsquo;s Bees and More to 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Glass Armors and Weapons Retexture to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mysticism - A Magic Overhaul to 2.4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mundus - A Standing Stone Overhaul to 1.12.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mundus - A Standing Stone Overhaul - USSEP Patch to 1.12.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Aetherius - A Race Overhaul to 2.12.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Aetherius - Starting Spells Addon to 2.12.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Aetherius - NPC Spell Absorption Addon to 2.12.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Scion - A Vampire Overhaul to 2.2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Stormcrown - A Shout Overhaul to 1.1.16&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Artificer - An Artifact Overhaul to 1.0.11&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Artificer - USSEP Patch to 1.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Alchemy Plus to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Guard Dialogue Overhaul to 3.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Narrative Gameplay Consistent Dialogue Tweaks to 1.9.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Brawl Lines Expansion Patch - NGCDT Patch to 1.9.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Blade and Blunt - A Combat Overhaul to 3.4.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Kryptopyr&amp;rsquo;s Patch Hub mods to 4.0.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lawless - A Bandit Overhaul to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lawless - SimonRim Patch to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lawless - Expanded Enemy Coverage Addon to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lawless - Patch Collection to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated C.O.I.N. - Coins of Interesting Natures to 2.1.3.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Immersive Display Overhaul to 1.31&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated XP32 Maximum Skeleton Special Extended to 5.06&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Survival Mode Improved to 1.5.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Kynareth Replaces Talos - Civil War Consequence to 2.0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Seasons of Skyrim to 1.8.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Turn of the Seasons to 1.0.7.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Seasonal Landscapes - Additions to 1.8.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Extended Cut Saints and Seducers - Mysticism Rebalance to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Heart of Dibella - Quest Expansion to 1.03&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Hand to Hand - An Adamant Addon to 1.5.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Pilgrim - A Religion Overhaul to 1.2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated East Empire Company Armor to 2.0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lepidoptera - Apothecary Patch to 1.2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Gesture Animation Remix to 2.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPC Animation Remix to 1.8.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Immersive Equipping Animations to 2.02&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="outputs-2">Outputs&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regenerated Synthesis Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated LODGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated TexGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated DynDOLOD (and Performance)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-41903">Release 4.19.0.3&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2024-01-22&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well, that was a waste of time. There&amp;rsquo;s no longer a &amp;ldquo;Best of Both Worlds&amp;rdquo; approach to this, I&amp;rsquo;m learning, so the list has been reverted fully to 1.6.640 exes, plugins, and archives. This means it&amp;rsquo;s no longer compatible with updated USSEP and a few mods I wanted to put into 4.19.1, but it also won&amp;rsquo;t have the odd bugs that have been plaguing the list since 4.19.0.1. Hopefully.&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-4">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Official Master Files:&lt;/strong> Reverted all archives and plugins back to 1.6.640 versions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Creation Club:&lt;/strong> Removed the Resource Pack&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SkyUI:&lt;/strong> Reverted SkyUI - Remove QuickSave Button back to its original version&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Essentials:&lt;/strong> Removed Backported Extended ESL Support&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Widescreen Support:&lt;/strong> Reverted SkyUI - Remove QuickSave Button - 21x9 Aspect Ratio Support back to its original version&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Configuration:&lt;/strong> Hid the Stealth Meter through SkyHUD as well as previous methods&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="updates-4">Updates&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Downgraded Unofficial Skyrim Special Edition Patch to 4.9.2a&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Enemies Respect Encounter Zones to 1.4.2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="outputs-3">Outputs&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regenerated Synthesis Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated LODGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated TexGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated DynDOLOD (and Performance)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-41902">Release 4.19.0.2&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2024-01-20&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Bethesda released a second update (1.6.1170) which means another recompile is necessary in order to keep the list installable on WJ. And it&amp;rsquo;s for the better, as 4.19.0.1 handled that last update (1.6.1130) poorly and there were stability issues. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that&amp;rsquo;s fixed now with this release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The executables (and SKSE) are remaining on 1.6.640. The rest (plugins and archives) are using the newest versions that Steam and Bethesda provide. There should be no more mismatching references and all of the bugs that generated. Other than that, I mainly stuck to mod updates since the last release, and some bug fixes I had discovered while working on 4.19.1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A New Game is not required for this update&lt;/strong>, but honestly I&amp;rsquo;d still recommend it. The saves I tested seem to make the jump just fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>ATTENTION:&lt;/strong> Download instructions for the list have changed with this update. Verify your game files in Steam to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re on 1.6.1170, then open the game and download the DLC content from the Creation market. Regardless if you own the AE Content Pack or not, you need the versions of the free Creations from that menu to install the list.&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-5">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Kept list at 1.6.640 but now uses all 1.6.1170 archives and plugins&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All plugins from 1.6.1170 have been cleaned as well&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mod Organizer 2:&lt;/strong> Added LOOT Warning Checker MO2 Plugin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SkyUI:&lt;/strong> Patched SkyUI - Remove QuickSave Button to include the Difficulty Persistence Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Essentials:&lt;/strong> Turned on &lt;code>SaveGameMaxSize&lt;/code> in SSE Engine Fixes by default&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Essentials:&lt;/strong> Added Backported Extended ESL Support&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>(Optional) Nordic UI:&lt;/strong> Added NORDIC UI - Convenient Dialogue UI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>(OPTIONAL) Widescreen Support:&lt;/strong> Patched SkyUI - Remove QuickSave Button - 21x9 Aspect Ratio Support to include the Difficulty Persistence Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Edited Base Object Swapper file in Ashbound - Solstheim Revisited to remove conflict within itself&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Trees:&lt;/strong> Fixed Dragonborn swaps for Happy Little Shrubs, removed one that conflicted with Ashbound - Solstheim Revisited&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Xavbio&amp;rsquo;s Retextures:&lt;/strong> Added Unique Armors and Weapons Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Unique Artifacts:&lt;/strong> Removed Modular Armory - Unique Nettlebane&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Unique Artifacts:&lt;/strong> Removed Frankly HD Masque of Clavicus Vile&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Unique Artifacts:&lt;/strong> Removed Frankly HD Miraak&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Unique Artifacts:&lt;/strong> Removed Masks of the Dovah Sonaak&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Unique Artifacts:&lt;/strong> Removed Modular Armory - Masks of the Dovah Sonaak Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Unique Artifacts:&lt;/strong> Removed Spellbreaker Oblivionized&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Wild Creatures:&lt;/strong> Removed aMidianBorn Book of Silence - Ash Spawn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NPC Dialogue &amp;amp; Behavior:&lt;/strong> Bandit Lines Expansion - Werebeasts Don&amp;rsquo;t Talk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NPC Dialogue &amp;amp; Behavior:&lt;/strong> Added NPCs React To Frenzy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enemy Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Added Lawless - Default Face NPCs Fixed Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Quest Start Adjustments:&lt;/strong> Removed More Radiant Quests for the Companions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Quest Start Adjustments:&lt;/strong> Added Customizable Companions Questline Progression Requirements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Survival &amp;amp; Fishing:&lt;/strong> Added Default Face NPCs Fixed - Fishing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Survival &amp;amp; Fishing:&lt;/strong> Added Fishing Preview&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Cities of the North:&lt;/strong> Removed bad reference from Spaghetti&amp;rsquo;s Cities AIO - CotN Dawnstar Patch plugin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Animations:&lt;/strong> Removed UNDERDOG Animations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Animations:&lt;/strong> Added UNDERDOG - Death Animations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Lowered fCombatSearchSightRadius to 1024 (will not affect existing saves)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Resolved many conflicts between Default Face NPCs Fixed and other mods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Extended Skyrim Landscape and Water Fixes&amp;rsquo; HelgenMud swap to the Helgen used in the intro of the game&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-5">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Mod Organizer 2 to 2.5.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Root Builder to 5.0.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated LOOT Warning Checker to 1.3.0 rc2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Profile Sync to 2.0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Fluency Themes to 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NIF Preview to 3.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD to 3.00 Alpha-165&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Address Library for SKSE Plugins to 10&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated JContainers to 4.2.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Spell Perk Item Distributor to 6.8.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Keyword Item Distributor to 3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Sound Record Distributor to 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated KiLoader for Skyrim to 1.0.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Scaleform Translation Plus Plus to 1.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Description Framework to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Crash Logger to 1.12.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated SSE Display Tweaks to 0.5.16&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Unofficial Skyrim Special Edition Patch to 4.3alpha&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated More Informative Console to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ConsoleUtils to 1.5.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Auto Input Switch to 1.2.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Zero Bounty Hostility Fix to 0.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Assorted Mesh Fixes to 0.91&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Load Screen Shading Fix to 0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated TrueHUD - HUD Additions to 1.1.9&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated SkyUI - 21x9 Aspect Ratio Support to 3.8.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD - Resources to 3.00 Alpha-47&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD - NG to Alpha-13&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ENBSeries - Binaries (no version change)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Storm Lightning to 1.4.19&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Embers XD to 2.9.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Just Blood - Dirt and Blood Lite to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simplicity of Snow to 0.19&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Happy Little Trees to 2.05&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Default Face NPCs Fixed to 1.17&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Overlooked Dungeon Objects Retextures to 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Rally&amp;rsquo;s Torchbugs to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Rally&amp;rsquo;s Bliss Bugs to 1.3, resized&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Rally&amp;rsquo;s Bugs In Jars to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon Armors and Weapons Retexture to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Additional Dremora Faces to 1.3.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Better Third Person Selection to 0.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Adamant - A Perk Overhaul to 5.9.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Thaumaturgy - Weapon Enchantment XP Tweak to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Bandit Lines Expansion to 1.09&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Civil War Lines Expansion to 1.09&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Forsworn and Thalmor Lines Expansion to 1.02&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Vampire Lines Expansion to 1.02&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Immersive Rejections to 1.13&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Bring Meeko To Lod to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Falmer Equip Armor to 1.1.10&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated C.O.I.N. - Coins of Interesting Natures to 2.1.3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Candlehearth - Unofficial Patches to 1.16&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Immersive Death Cycle to 1.04&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Headhunter - Bounties Redone to 1.52&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Missile&amp;rsquo;s Immersive Equipment Display Presets to 2.0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Weapon Styles - DrawSheathe Animations for IED to 2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simple Fishing Overhaul to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Baited - A Fishing Artifact Overhaul to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Survival Mode Improved to 1.4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Morthal Where&amp;rsquo;s Wares to 2.25&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated COTN - Dawnstar - Unique Door Design to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Seasonal Landscapes - Additions to 1.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Nilheim - Misc Quest Expansion to 1.13&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Update The Heart of Dibella - Quest Expansion to 1.01&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Adamant - Bard Perks Addon - Pilgrim Integration to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPC Animation Remix to 1.8&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="outputs-4">Outputs&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regenerated Synthesis Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated LODGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated TexGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated DynDOLOD (and Performance)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-41901">Release 4.19.0.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-12-11&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So, Bethesda went ahead and updated Skyrim, mostly for reasons I don&amp;rsquo;t agree with nor want to get into but it required me to update the list in order for Wabbajack to work again. So, here&amp;rsquo;s a few updates to go along with the mandatory back-end changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note:&lt;/strong> I did not have time to fully test this but I&amp;rsquo;ve no reason to believe it&amp;rsquo;s any less stable than the version prior. I&amp;rsquo;ve left all vanilla archives the same with the exception of &lt;code>Skyrim - Misc.bsa&lt;/code> and the list continues to run on 1.6.640. I also did not update MO2 to v2.5.0, although I&amp;rsquo;ve included archives for that update as well as some of the plugins that would also need installing. I don&amp;rsquo;t plan on making the jump to the newest version of SSE anytime soon, so mods such as USSEP and AI Overhaul (which was updated for USSEP) have not been touched.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This works with existing 4.19.0 saves.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peep the details below for the full change list. The only big thing I&amp;rsquo;ll note is that SimonRim&amp;rsquo;s suite has seen a number of updates that you may want to check out individually (respective updates to the Example Builds will come later, stealthily), and that I&amp;rsquo;ve removed &lt;code>Use Or Take&lt;/code> and &lt;code>Read or Take&lt;/code>. They are great and useful mods, however without visible Activation text I found that they add confusion for players who don&amp;rsquo;t know they&amp;rsquo;re there.&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-6">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Frameworks:&lt;/strong> Added Description Framework&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Interface:&lt;/strong> Added SimonRim - I4 Addons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Interface:&lt;/strong> Added Vanilla Item Descriptions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SKSE Plugins - Interface:&lt;/strong> Removed Use or Take SKSE&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SKSE Plugins - Interface:&lt;/strong> Removed Read or Take SKSE&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NPC Dialogue &amp;amp; Behavior:&lt;/strong> Added Brawl Lines Expansion Patch - NGCDT Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NPC Dialogue &amp;amp; Behavior:&lt;/strong> Added Scared of Shootings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enemy Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Replaced plugin for The Dragon Cult to prevent crashes with spectral draugr&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Quest Start Adjustments:&lt;/strong> Added A Lovely Letter - NGCDT Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Quest Start Adjustments:&lt;/strong> Added Calcelmo Has Standards&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Quest Start Adjustments:&lt;/strong> Edited TPF - Quest Mods Patch to remove A Lovely Letter changes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Removed some DisableDisenchant keywords from artifacts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Performance Profile:&lt;/strong> Ensured everything was actually enabled&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-6">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD to 3.00 Alpha-159&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Address Library for SKSE Plugins to 9.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Spell Perk Item Distributor to 6.7.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated SSE Display Tweaks to 0.5.14&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Sprint Sneak Movement Speed Fix to 1.1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Landscape Fixes For Grass Mods to 5.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Landscape Fixes For Grass Mods - Vanilla Military Camps (No Version Change)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Equip Enchantment Fix (No Version Change)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Soaking Wet - Character Wetness Effect to 1.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD - Resources to 3.00 Alpha-44&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Storm Lightning to 1.4.18&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lux Via to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lux Orbis to 4.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simplicity of Snow to 0.18&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Icy Mesh Remaster to 2.38&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Default Face NPCs Fixed to 1.15&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Ancient Imperial Septims to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Adamant - A Perk Overhaul to 5.9&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Adamant - Bard Perks Addon to 1.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Stormcrown - A Shout Overhaul to 1.1.15&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Thaumaturgy - An Enchanting Overhaul to 1.4.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Apothecary - An Alchemy Overhaul to 1.3.9&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Misc Dialogue Edits to 1.9.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Misc Dialogue Edits - NGCDT Patch to 1.9.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Blade and Blunt - A Combat Overhaul to 3.3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - A Dragon Overhaul to 3.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Deadly Spell Impacts Patch to 3.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Misc Dialogue Edits - Save the Icerunner Patch to 1.9.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Misc Dialogue Edits - Bring Meeko to Lod Patch to 1.9.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Falmer Equip Armor to 1.0.9&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Durnehviir Resurrected Patch to 3.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated PlayerPayCrimeGold Tweak to 1.0.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Audio Overhaul for Skyrim Patch to 3.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Conditional Dog Barking to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated XP32 Maximum Skeleton Special Extended to 5.05&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simple Dual Sheath to 1.5.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Immersive Equipment Displays to 1.7.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Weapon Styles - DrawSheathe Animations for IED to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simple Fishing Overhaul - FLM Addon to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Seasonal Landscapes - No Dead Pine Tree Resurrection to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Hand to Hand - An Adamant Addon to 1.5.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Pilgrim - A Religion Overhaul to 1.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPC Animation Remix to 1.7&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-4190">Release 4.19.0&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-11-25&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>At long last, we&amp;rsquo;re at version 4.19! &lt;strong>This will require a new save file if you&amp;rsquo;re on anything other than the 4.19.0 beta.&lt;/strong> So, what&amp;rsquo;s new with this version?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Firstly, there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of attention given to &lt;em>Seasons of Skyrim&lt;/em>, expanding the areas it affects, making sure it looks more how it should, and even letting it affect alchemy ingredient availability. To make that more manageable, the calendar has been adjusted so that each season is only 30 in-game days, down from 90. (Some of you may remember me playing around with &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/71967">&lt;em>Seasonal Landscapes - Unfrozen&lt;/em>&lt;/a> but it was ultimately dropped. Perhaps in 4.20 that will be revisited.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Secondly, a good number of bugs have been addressed. I want to give a big thanks to everyone on the &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/xRrHRsb5e9">Discord&lt;/a> that reported the issues. I know I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to resolve every last one, but the fixes I did include help make this release even more polished than the last.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Outside of that you won&amp;rsquo;t see too many major gameplay changes from 4.18. &lt;em>Fishing&lt;/em> is a bit more robust in that you&amp;rsquo;ll now need bait (read: cheap bug ingredients) to participate and &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/97542">&lt;em>Candlehearth&lt;/em>&lt;/a> gives you the option to store goods in inns. Many mods have been updated, however, and there&amp;rsquo;s a few gameplay changes to be found in the pile of changelogs. Nothing that would surprise you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A new save is required for this update.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As always, if you run into any issues, let me know and I&amp;rsquo;ll try and have it fixed in the next update.&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-7">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Textures &amp;amp; Mesh Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed Gourd Plant Mesh Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SKSE Plugins - Fixes:&lt;/strong> Added Capture Warmer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>(Optional) Nordic UI:&lt;/strong> Added NORDIC UI - Compass Navigation Overhaul Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Renamed TPF - Depths of Skyrim Patch to Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim - Depths of Skyrim Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Forwarded old Depths of Skyrim entries from QW&amp;rsquo;s Grass Patch to Depths of Skyrim - SSS Patch.esp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lux Lighting:&lt;/strong> Modified Lux Orbis - Daedric Shrines AiO Patch to account for Pilgrim - Daedric Shrines Patch changes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lux Lighting:&lt;/strong> Removed &lt;code>/meshes/architecture/windhelm/whgrayquarter02.nif&lt;/code> from Lux Orbis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fire &amp;amp; Candles:&lt;/strong> Added FYX - Sparks React to the Wind&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fire &amp;amp; Candles:&lt;/strong> Added FYX - Campfire Reacts to the Wind&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Snow &amp;amp; Ice:&lt;/strong> Added Simplicity of Snow - Majestic Mountains Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Grass Overhaul:&lt;/strong> Removed Veydosebrom Regions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Grass Overhaul:&lt;/strong> Removed QW’s Grass Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Grass Overhaul:&lt;/strong> Removed QW Grass Patch - No Fall Forest Leaf Piles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Grass Overhaul:&lt;/strong> Removed QW Grass Patch - Re-Enable Rocks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Grass Overhaul:&lt;/strong> Removed QW Grass Patch - ENB Complex Grass&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Grass Overhaul:&lt;/strong> Added Origins Of Forest&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Grass Overhaul:&lt;/strong> Added Origins of Forest - ENB Complex Grass&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Grass Overhaul:&lt;/strong> Added Folkvangr - Summer Tundra&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Grass Overhaul:&lt;/strong> Added QW&amp;rsquo;s Grass Patch 2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Grass Overhaul:&lt;/strong> Added QW&amp;rsquo;s Grass Patch 2 - ENB Complex Grass&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Plants &amp;amp; Mushrooms:&lt;/strong> Added Kabu&amp;rsquo;s Really Gourd Plant Replacer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Valuable Objects:&lt;/strong> Removed White Phial Replacer - ENB Light Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Xavbio&amp;rsquo;s Retextures:&lt;/strong> Added Dragon Priest Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Undead, Daedra, &amp;amp; Dragons:&lt;/strong> Removed aMidianBorn Book of Silence - Dragon Priest&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Undead, Daedra, &amp;amp; Dragons:&lt;/strong> Removed aMidianBorn Book of Silence - Dragon Priest Acolytes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Undead, Daedra, &amp;amp; Dragons:&lt;/strong> Removed Rustic Dragons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Undead, Daedra, &amp;amp; Dragons:&lt;/strong> Removed Frankly HD Dragon Bones&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Undead, Daedra, &amp;amp; Dragons:&lt;/strong> Removed Deiform Alduin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Undead, Daedra, &amp;amp; Dragons:&lt;/strong> Removed Deiform Alduin - Eye Textures&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Undead, Daedra, &amp;amp; Dragons:&lt;/strong> Removed Deiform Alduin - Particle Lights&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Undead, Daedra, &amp;amp; Dragons:&lt;/strong> Added Iconic&amp;rsquo;s Dragon Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ElSopa&amp;rsquo;s Potions Redone:&lt;/strong> Merged v3.1 update with ElSopa - Potions Redone - Missing Vanilla Potions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Crafting:&lt;/strong> Added Thaumaturgy - Player Spell Lighting Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Crafting:&lt;/strong> Edited JewelryCircletOrichalcEmerald &lt;code>000166d6&lt;/code> in Jewelry Crafting Expanded to have the correct Model FileName&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Horses &amp;amp; Fast Travel:&lt;/strong> Added AE Patch to zzjay&amp;rsquo;s Horse Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NPC Dialogue &amp;amp; Behavior:&lt;/strong> Removed Rent Room Dialogue Tweak&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NPC Dialogue &amp;amp; Behavior:&lt;/strong> Removed Windhelm Segregation - Stay At New Gnisis Cornerclub&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NPC Dialogue &amp;amp; Behavior:&lt;/strong> Added Misc Dialogue Edits - NGCDT Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enemy Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Removed Dragon War - Deiform Alduin Particle Lights Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enemy Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Added Wait Your Turn - Sands of Time Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Quest Start Adjustments:&lt;/strong> Added Realistic Dark Brotherhood Kidnapping&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Quest Start Adjustments:&lt;/strong> Adjusted edits to Thieves Guild radiant quests in TPF - Quest Mods Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Immersion:&lt;/strong> Removed Coherent Inns Prices&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Immersion:&lt;/strong> Added Misc Dialogue Edits - Bring Meeko to Lod Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Immersion:&lt;/strong> Added Soups of Skyrim - Fishing and Gourmet Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Immersion:&lt;/strong> Added Candlehearth - An Inn Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Immersion:&lt;/strong> Added Candlehearth - Tavern AI Fix Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Immersion:&lt;/strong> Added Candlehearth - Unofficial Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Miscellaneous:&lt;/strong> Removed Unequip Quiver&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Miscellaneous:&lt;/strong> Added Contraband Confiscation - Gourmet Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Survival &amp;amp; Fishing:&lt;/strong> Added Simple Fishing Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Survival &amp;amp; Fishing:&lt;/strong> Added Simple Fishing Overhaul - FLM Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Survival &amp;amp; Fishing:&lt;/strong> Swapped U Can&amp;rsquo;t Touch Fish for the Chance Edition&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>City Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Added Better Windhelm Ground Meshes - Icy Windhelm&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Cities of the North:&lt;/strong> Removed COTN - Morthal - Skyrim 3D Signs Patch (included in the Patch Collection now)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Faction HQs:&lt;/strong> Added Obscure&amp;rsquo;s College of Winterhold - AI Overhaul Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seasons of Skyrim:&lt;/strong> Added Four Seasons - Faster Seasons of Skyrim&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seasons of Skyrim:&lt;/strong> Added Seasonal Alchemy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seasons of Skyrim:&lt;/strong> Added Seasonal Alchemy Add-on&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seasons of Skyrim:&lt;/strong> Added Seasonal Landscapes for ENB Complex Grass&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seasons of Skyrim:&lt;/strong> Added Seasonal Landscapes - QW&amp;rsquo;s Grass Patch 2 Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seasons of Skyrim:&lt;/strong> Added Seasonal Landscapes - Whiterun Stairs Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seasons of Skyrim:&lt;/strong> Added Seasonal Landscapes - Stones of Solitude - MM Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seasons of Skyrim:&lt;/strong> Added Seasonal Landscapes - Additions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seasons of Skyrim:&lt;/strong> Added Seasonal Landscapes - No Dead Pine Tree Resurrection&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seasons of Skyrim:&lt;/strong> Added Seasonal Landscapes - No Dead Pine Tree Resurrection - Happy Little Tree Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Saints and Seducers:&lt;/strong> Removed Saints and Seducers - Mysticism Rebalance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Mechanics:&lt;/strong> Removed Pilgrim and Daedric Shrines Consistency and Tweaks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Mechanics:&lt;/strong> Added Pilgrim - Daedric Shrines AIO Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Mechanics:&lt;/strong> Added Pilgrim - Statue of Sithis Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Creatures and Enemies:&lt;/strong> Updated Imperial Armors and Weapons Retexture - Civil War Deserters Patch to include necessary textures from Imperial Armors and Weapons Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Animations:&lt;/strong> Added Vanargand Animations II - Unarmed Non Combat Locomotion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Animations:&lt;/strong> Added Improved Idle Laydown Animations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Copied DBEntranceQuest &lt;code>00050F2E&lt;/code> from The Choice is Yours to overwrite edits by Quest Conflict Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Edited &lt;code>000C28F4&lt;/code> to add a proximity check to Ancano&amp;rsquo;s Sparks sound effect&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Edited &lt;code>0009CD43&lt;/code> to allow alchemy merchants a higher chance to stock more potions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Edited HUDShouting &lt;code>00064697&lt;/code> to better reflect TrueHUD&amp;rsquo;s interface&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Removed HUDDetection &lt;code>00064694&lt;/code> loadscreen as there&amp;rsquo;s no Sneak HUD in the list&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Configuration:&lt;/strong> Edited Immersive Equipment Displays settings to work with EVG Conditional Idles&amp;rsquo; shield cover function&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Configuration:&lt;/strong> Adjusted &lt;code>bForceNPCsUseAmmo&lt;/code> to &lt;code>0&lt;/code> in Skyrim.ini&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Configuration:&lt;/strong> Edited Immersive Equipment Displays settings to hide ammo when ranged weapons are not actively equipped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Performance Profile:&lt;/strong> Enabled ElSopa&amp;rsquo;s Potion Redone section&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-7">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated SSEEdit to 4.1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Root Builter to 4.5.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD to Alpha-156&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated KiLoader for Skyrim to 1.0.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Crash Logger to 1.11.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ConsolePlusPlus to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Rock Traps Trigger Fixes to 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated CritterSpawn Congestion Fix to 1.52&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyrim Landscape and Water Fixes to 8.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD - NG to Alpha-13&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyland Bits and Bobs - A Clutter Overhaul to 1.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ENB Binaries to 0.499&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ENB Extender for Skyrim to 1.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lux to 6.4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Embers XD to 2.9.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Thunderbolt - HD Lightning to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simplicity of Snow to 0.16&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Majestic Snow to 2.33&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Snowy Surfaces Sound Collision and Aesthetics to 1.6.6.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simple Snow Improvements - Skyrim to 2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simple Snow Improvements - Giant Obelisks to 1.4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Icy Mesh Remaster to 2.30&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Sowables of Skyrim - Leeks to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Sowables of Skyrim - Potatoes to 2.01&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Sowables of Skyrim - Scrumptious Cabbages to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated High Poly Solstheim Mushroom Trees to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Security Overhaul SKSE - Add-ons to 0.1.9.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Additional Dremora Faces to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated True Directional Movement - Modernized Third Person Gameplay to 2.2.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mysticism - A Magic Overhaul to 2.3.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Adamant - A Perk Overhaul to 5.8.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Adamant - Bard Perks Addon to 1.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Manbeast - A Werewolf Overhaul to 2.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Scion - A Vampire Overhaul to 2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Stormcrown - A Shout Overhaul to 1.1.12&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Artificer - An Artifact Overhaul to 1.0.10&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Artificer - Xavbio Textures Addon to 1.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Thaumaturgy - An Enchanting Overhaul to 1.4.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Apothecary - An Alchemy Overhaul to 1.3.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Gourmet - A Cooking Overhaul to 1.1.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Gourmet - Fishing Patch to 1.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Civil War Lines Expansion to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dremora Lines Expansion to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Misc Dialogue Edits to 1.9.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Narrative Gameplay Consistent Dialogue Tweaks to 1.9.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Neutral Whiterun Guards to 4.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Honorhall Orphanage Bugfixes and Expansion to 2.03&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Unofficial Material Fix - Improved Traps to 4.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Madmen - A Forsworn Overhaul to 2.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Madmen - Patch Collection to 2.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - A Dragon Overhaul to 3.1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Deadly Spell Impacts Patch to 3.1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Bring Meeko to Lod to 1.0b&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Beyond Skyrim Morrowind - Bonemold Weapon Pack to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Falmer Equip Armor to 1.0.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Immersive Death Cycle to 1.03&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Durnehviir Resurrected Patch to 3.1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Audio Overhaul for Skyrim Patch to 3.1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Immersive Sounds Compendium - Sound Record Distributor to 2.3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Weapon Styles - DrawSheathe Animations for IED to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated U Can&amp;rsquo;t Touch Fishto 1.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Fishing - WACCF Patch to 4.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Icy Windhelm to 2.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated COTN - Dawnstar to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated COTN - Dawnstar - Patch Collection to 5.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated COTN - Morthal to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated COTN - Morthal - Patch Collection to 3.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated aljo&amp;rsquo;s Apothecary Patches - OCW Patch to 4.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Sowables of Skyrim - Leeks - Snowy Version to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Sowables of Skyrim - Potatoes - Snowy Version to 2.01&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Sowables of Skyrim - Scrumptious Cabbages - Snowy Version to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Extended Cut Saints and Seducers - Mysticism Rebalance to 2.01&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyrim Extended Cut - Saints and Seducers - WACCF Patch to 4.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated aljo&amp;rsquo;s Apothecary Patches - SECSS Patch to 4.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated College of Winterhold - Quest Expansion to 1.15&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Thaumaturgy - WACCF ACE Patch to 4.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Beyond Skyrim Morrowind - Bonemold Weapon Pack - WACCF Patch to 4.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Beyond Skyrim Morrowind - Bonemold Weapon Pack - Thaumaturgy WACCF Patch to 4.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Beyond Skyrim Morrowind - Bonemold Weapon Pack - Tamrielic Distribution WACCF Patch to 4.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dawnguard Arsenal - WACCF Patch to 4.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated UNDERDOG Animatons to 1.9.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Improved Table Transition Animations to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Northerner Diaries - Immersive Edition to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Yet Another Music Merge to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Yet Another Music Merge - ECSS Patch to 1.1-ECSS&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="outputs-5">Outputs&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regenerated Nemesis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated Synthesis Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated LODGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated TexGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated DynDOLOD (and Performance)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-41807">Release 4.18.0.7&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-10-07&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>We might as well call this the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/99619">&lt;em>Artificer&lt;/em>&lt;/a> Update. Simon&amp;rsquo;s newest overhaul tackles the Unique Artifacts of the game which required a bit of reconfiguring on my part. It also clashes with &lt;em>Weapons Armor Clothing and Clutter Fixes&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em> changes, though since it&amp;rsquo;s just on unique items it&amp;rsquo;s not the biggest problem in the world. Anyway, in cases where Artificer kept vanilla values, I carried over the WACCF changes. But if Artificer rebalanced the item altogether, chances are I went with Simon&amp;rsquo;s changes. Until there&amp;rsquo;s an official patch saying otherwise, that&amp;rsquo;s how I handled the conflicts and I&amp;rsquo;ll likely make tweaks to this in future patches.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also did some cleaning up to match &lt;em>Aurora&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em> previous removal of optional sections. I kept all of the mods I personally used and moved them to respective sections. Last but not least, I added &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/100562">&lt;em>Dremora Lines Expansion&lt;/em>&lt;/a> to give them some well-needed dialogue attention. Other than that, the update is full of mod updates and minor bug fixes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This update is save-safe.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Pro-tip:&lt;/strong> Artificer&amp;rsquo;s Oghma Infinium grants two extra perk points when read, raising the maximum number of perks to 57 for those who progress through the main quest to that point. This may be a valuable bump for most builds.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-8">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Controls:&lt;/strong> Removed Sprint Swimming&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Controls:&lt;/strong> Removed Sprint Swimming MCM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Widescreen Support:&lt;/strong> Replaced Constructible Object Custom Keyword System - 21x9 Aspect Ratio Support with a working alternative&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Undead, Daedra, &amp;amp; Dragons:&lt;/strong> Added Additional Dremora Faces&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Undead, Daedra, &amp;amp; Dragons:&lt;/strong> Added Additional Dremora Faces - Mysticism Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alternative Assets:&lt;/strong> Moved Flame Atronach to Undead, Daedra, &amp;amp; Dragons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alternative Assets:&lt;/strong> Moved Deiform Alduin and patches to Undead, Daedra, &amp;amp; Dragons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alternative Assets:&lt;/strong> Cathedral - 3D Thicket and Dead Shrub to Improved Trees&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alternative Assets:&lt;/strong> Removed section including remaining mods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ancient Dwemer Metal:&lt;/strong> Removed optional section entirely&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Crafting:&lt;/strong> Added Artificer - An Artifact Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Crafting:&lt;/strong> Added Artificer - USSEP Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Crafting:&lt;/strong> Added Artificer - Xavbio Textures Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Crafting:&lt;/strong> Added Artificer - Xavbio Textures Addon - Old Gods Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Crafting:&lt;/strong> Added Artificer - Unique Uniques Patch, modifying to match Unique Uniques Re-Ported&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Crafting:&lt;/strong> Added Artificer - Dragon Priest Staves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NPC Dialogue &amp;amp; Behavior:&lt;/strong> Added Dremora Lines Expansion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NPC Dialogue &amp;amp; Behavior:&lt;/strong> Adjusted AI Overhaul - TPF Patch to reflect recent changes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Quest Start Adjustments:&lt;/strong> Added The Choice is Yours - NGCDT Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Survival &amp;amp; Fishing:&lt;/strong> Removed Mysticism - Survival Spells Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Survival &amp;amp; Fishing:&lt;/strong> Added Starfrost - Survival Spells Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Faction HQs:&lt;/strong> Added aljo&amp;rsquo;s Apothecary Patches - OCW Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Animations:&lt;/strong> Removed Vanargand Animations - Sprint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Animations:&lt;/strong> Removed Vanargand Animations - Male Idle Walk and Run&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Animations:&lt;/strong> Added Vanargand Animations II - Sprint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Animations:&lt;/strong> Added Vanargand Animations II - Male Idle Walk And Run&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Final Patches:&lt;/strong> Updated Unique Artifacts Patch to account for Artificer&amp;rsquo;s inclusion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Copied MiddenVelehk&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code>00075C7F&lt;/code> appearance from Additional Dremora Faces&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Configuration:&lt;/strong> Fixed a handful of values in the SkyrimUncapper.ini, these were erroneously overwritten by an automatic update to the file.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-8">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Root Builder to 4.5.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD to Alpha-152&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Spell Perk Item Distributor to 6.6.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Container Item Distributor to 1.1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Beautifully Overhauled and Objectively Better Icons Enriched for SkyUI to 2.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPCs Names Distributor to 2.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated powerofthree&amp;rsquo;s Tweaks to 1.8.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Navigator - Navmesh Fixes to 1.5.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mannequin Management to 4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated CritterSpawn Congestion Fix to 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyrim Landscape and Water Fixes to 8.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD - Resources to Alpha-45&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyland AIO to 4.31&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated OSHA-Compliant Sovngarde Mesh Fixes to 2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Snowy Surfaces Sound Collision and Aesthetics to 1.6.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simple Snow Improvements - Skyrim to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mysticism - A Magic Overhaul to 2.3.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Adamant - A Perk Overhaul to 5.8.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated True Directional Movement - Modernized Third Person Gameplay 10 2.2.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Better Third Person Selection to 0.5.9&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Apothecary - An Alchemy Overhaul to 1.3.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Thaumaturgy - An Enchanting Overhaul to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated AI Overhaul to 1.8.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Narrative Gameplay Consistent Dialogue Tweaks to 1.9.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Dragon Cult - A Draugr Overhaul to 1.4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - A Dragon Overhaul to 3.1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Deadly Spell Impacts Patch to 3.1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Deiform Alduin Particle Lights Patch to 3.1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Immersive Death Cycle to 1.02&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Durnehviir Resurrected Patch to 3.1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Audio Overhaul for Skyrim Patch to 3.1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Baited - A Fishing Artifact Overhaul to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated COTN - Falkreath - Patch Collection to 1.20&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated COTN - Dawnstar - Patch Collection to 4.6 (no real changes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Anga&amp;rsquo;s Mill - Cities of the North Addon Patch Collection to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Hand to Hand - An Adamant Addon to 1.5.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPC Animation Remix to 1.6.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated SD&amp;rsquo;s Lotta Patches to 2023.9.27&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="outputs-6">Outputs&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regenerated FaceGen (again, sorry!)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim - Sorcerer Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated DynDOLOD (and Performance)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-41806">Release 4.18.0.6&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-09-08&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh joyous days! &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bTG1vVzgsFM">DroppedIceCream released a showcase and review&lt;/a> of this list! Go check it out! Of the many things said that made me happy, hearing that it was one of the most stable lists he&amp;rsquo;s tried made me especially proud. That said, &lt;em>Skill of Sneaking&lt;/em> currently causes crashes so I&amp;rsquo;m releasing an update to roll that back to a stable version. Sorry, sneaky folks!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fortunately, Aurora updated in the last few days which means this update also gives you Xavbio&amp;rsquo;s newest retextures, Yuril&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/98260">Windhelm Graveyard&lt;/a>, and a few more fixes from SME. I also went through Aurora mod by mod and found a few small differences between the lists that were unintentional. Those have been fixed. Sadly, &lt;em>Ethereal Elven Overhaul&lt;/em> was removed for neck seam issues so the FaceGen files needed to be regenerated yet again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This update is save-safe.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-9">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Applied changes from &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sme/changelog/#release-261">Skyrim Modding Essentials 2.6.1&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/aur/changelog/#release-150">Aurora 1.5.0&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Texture &amp;amp; Mesh Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed Windhelm Entrance Offset Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Architeture:&lt;/strong> Added FYX - Windhelm Graveyard - Spaghetti Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Animations:&lt;/strong> Removed Vanargand Animations - Female Idle Walk And Run&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Animations:&lt;/strong> Added Vanargand Animations II - Female Idle Walk And Run&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Music:&lt;/strong> Added Yet Another Music Merge - ECSS Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-9">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD to Alpha-142&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Crash Logger to 1.10&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Navigator - Navmesh Fixes to 1.5.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Downgraded Skill of Sneaking to 1.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Embers XD to 2.8.9&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Misc Effects ENB Light to 1.6.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Narrative Gameplay Consistent Dialogue Tweaks to 1.9&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - A Dragon Overhaul to 3.1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Deadly Spell Impacts Patch to 3.1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Deiform Alduin Particle Lights Patch to 3.1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Durnehviir Resurrected Patch to 3.1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Audio Overhaul for Skyrim Patch to 3.1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="outputs-7">Outputs&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regenerated Nemesis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated FaceGen&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-41805">Release 4.18.0.5&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-09-03&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Another small maintenance update while time allows. Among the mod updates is a notable change to &lt;em>Dragon War&lt;/em> and the inclusion of Delta&amp;rsquo;s newest mod, &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/99193">&lt;em>Dragon Hunting&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, which adds a few more alchemical ingredients to the giant lizards of Skyrim among other changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As &lt;em>Aurora&lt;/em> has not yet updated, certain visual releases such as Xavbio&amp;rsquo;s most recent armor retextures have not been included in this update, but they may be coming soon. In the meantime I&amp;rsquo;ll continue looking into any issues that crop up. So if you find any, please come to the &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/xRrHRsb5e9">Aetherius Modding&lt;/a> server and let me know!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This update is save-safe.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-10">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Applied changes from &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sme/changelog/#release-260">Skyrim Modding Essentials 2.6.0&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>General Fixes:&lt;/strong> Added Excuse Me I&amp;rsquo;m Sliding Here&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Script Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed USSEP Caravan Bug Workaround&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Script Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed WE05 Script Fix (redundant)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Food &amp;amp; Ingredients:&lt;/strong> Added Bottles of Skyrim - Gourmet Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Skeleton &amp;amp; Animations:&lt;/strong> Added Paired Animation Improvements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Survival &amp;amp; Fishing:&lt;/strong> Added Baited - A Fishing Artifact Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New &amp;amp; Expanded Quests:&lt;/strong> Added Dragon Hunting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New &amp;amp; Expanded Quests:&lt;/strong> Added Dragon Hunting - Apothecary Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New &amp;amp; Expanded Quests:&lt;/strong> Added Dragon Hunting - Paarthurnax Quest Expansion Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New &amp;amp; Expanded Quests:&lt;/strong> Added Dragon Hunting - AYOPCoW Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Animations:&lt;/strong> Added Leviathan Animations II - Greatsword Sneak Locomotion And Attacks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Resolved conflicts between Fishing artifact adjustments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Resolved conflict betweeen ElSopa&amp;rsquo;s Potions Redone and Dragon Hunting on Dragon Infusion &lt;code>000E6DF5&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-10">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD to Alpha-140&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Keyword Item Distributor to 3.0.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Base Object Swapper to 2.6.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Navigator - Navmesh Fixes to 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Zero Bounty Hostility Fix to 0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simply Optimized Scripts to 1.0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skill of Sneaking to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD - Resources to Alpha-42&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD - NG to Alpha-12&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated LOD Model Library for DynDOLOD to 1.3.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Particle Patch for ENB to 1.2.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Embers XD to 2.8.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simple Degradation to 1.5.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Narrative Gameplay Consistent Dialogue Tweaks to 1.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - A Dragon Overhaul to 3.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Deadly Spell Impacts Patch to 3.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Deiform Alduin Particle Lights Patch to 3.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Dragon Cult - A Draugr Overhaul to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Trade &amp;amp; Barter to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Immersive Death Cycle to 1.01&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Durnehviir Resurrected Patch to 3.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Audio Overhaul for Skyrim Patch to 3.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Open Animation Replacer to 2.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Open Animation Replacer - IED Conditions to 1.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Immersive Equipment Displays to 1.7.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Icy Windhelm to 2.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated House of Horrors - Quest Expansion to 1.12&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="outputs-8">Outputs&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regenerated Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim - Landscape Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-41804">Release 4.18.0.4&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-08-23&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It was inevitable with so much time passing between updates: I missed some things. This update is much smaller than the last and mainly exists to clean up things that should&amp;rsquo;ve been in 4.18.0.3. The outstanding bugs I mentioned previously are still being looked into. None are game-breaking, don&amp;rsquo;t worry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This update is save-safe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>* If you downloaded this update early, you may notice that the two COTN Missives patches are present but disabled in the load order. This was intentional as enabling them made the boards invisible in Falkreath and Winterhold. The cause of this was the rogue master, &lt;code>Missives.esp&lt;/code>, coming after the patches in the load order. If you move both plugins down in priority to be after &lt;code>Missives.esp&lt;/code>, you may re-enable them.&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-11">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Script Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed MQ105SprintTriggerScript Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Script Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed dunFolgunthurBossBattle Script Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Script Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed Shroud Hearth Barrow Script Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Script Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed The Taste of Death Improved Shutdown&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Script Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed Soul Cairn Script Tweaks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Script Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed DLC2AudioRepeaterActivator01Script Tweak&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Script Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed DLC2TribalWerebearScript Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Script Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed DLC2dunFrostmoonTriggerScript Optimization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Script Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed DLC2dunNchardakDoorSeal Script Infinite Loop Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Script Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed DLC2dunSeekerInvisScript Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Script Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed DLC2MiraakScript Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Script Fixes:&lt;/strong> Added Scripts Carefully Reworked Optimized and Tactfully Enhanced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Added Gourmet - Hearthfire Crispy Dumplings Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Content Integration:&lt;/strong> Removed Bonemold Weapon Pack - NPC Distribution (redundant)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Forwarded Madman changes for Nada Ildene &lt;code>000133A0&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Restored Magnitudes to Magelight &lt;code>00043323&lt;/code> and Candlelight &lt;code>00043324&lt;/code> to prevent issue with Player Spell Lighting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Configuration:&lt;/strong> Changed Contextual Crosshair&amp;rsquo;s INI to force crosshair on for ranged weapons and spells as it was not consistent previously&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-11">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD to Alpha-135&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Taste of Death Improved Shutdown to 1.3.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DLC2TribalWerebearScript Fix to 1.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated RemoveAllItems Freeze Fix to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Photo Mode to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NORDIC UI - Miscellaneous Patches to 1.8.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD - Resources to Alpha-39&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Word Wall Transparency Fix for ENB to 0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated OSHA-Compliant Sovngarde Mesh Fixes to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mundus - A Standing Stone Overhaul to 1.11&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Aetherius - A Race Overhaul to 2.11.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Aetherius - Starting Spells Addon to 2.0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Narrative Gameplay Consistent Dialogue Tweaks to 1.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Madmen - A Forsworn Overhaul to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Madmen - Patch Collection to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated COTN - Morthal - Patch Collection to 2.15&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-41803">Release 4.18.0.3&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-08-21&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been awhile. I was away from home for work and during that time a number of interesting mods hit the Nexus, some of them are included in this update. &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/96876">Gourmet - A Cooking Overhaul&lt;/a> takes over for Apothecary&amp;rsquo;s Food Addon. Not much has changed as far as how food works, but obtaining and making food has been overhauled quite a bit. From the author of Lawless - A Bandit Overhaul comes &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/98579">Madmen - A Forsworn Overhaul&lt;/a>, bringing some of the same enemy design philosophies to the Reach as we have with draugr and bandits (and dragons)!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Outside of that it&amp;rsquo;s been a few quality of life or fixes added here or there. There are some bug reports I still wish to investigate but that would require more time. For now I wanted to get this update out to fix a number that has already been accounted for.&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-12">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>General Fixes:&lt;/strong> Added Zero Bounty Hostility Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Script Fixes:&lt;/strong> Added USSEP Caravan Bug Workaround&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Texture &amp;amp; Mesh Fixes:&lt;/strong> Added Windhelm Entrance Offset Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Grass &amp;amp; Terrain Fixes:&lt;/strong> Added Green Water Cubemap Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SKSE Plugins - Fixes:&lt;/strong> Added DPI Scaling Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SKSE Plugins - Tweaks:&lt;/strong> Removed Improved Camera&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Yuril&amp;rsquo;s Mesh Edits:&lt;/strong> Added FYX - Water Mesh Optimization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lux Lighting:&lt;/strong> Added FYX - 3D Shack Kit Walls - Lux Patch (BOS)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Crafting:&lt;/strong> Removed Simple Degradation - NPC Tempering&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Removed Vendor Tweaks - Food and Cooking&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Removed Apothecary - Food and Drink Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Removed Apothecary - Food and Drink Addon - USSEP Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Removed Apothecary Anniversary Update - Food and Drink Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Apothecary - Bottles Of Skyrim Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Added Gourmet - A Cooking Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Added Gourmet - USSEP Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Added Gourmet - SimonRim Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Added Gourmet - AI Overhaul Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Added Gourmet - Cooking Pots and Baking Ovens&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NPC Dialogue &amp;amp; Behavior:&lt;/strong> Added Visiting Advisor Outfit Tweak&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounter Zones:&lt;/strong> Removed Blade &amp;amp; Blunt - Health Regeneration Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enemy Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Added Madmen - A Forsworn Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enemy Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Added Madmen - Patch Collection&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Immersion:&lt;/strong> Removed Soups of Skyrim - Apothecary Food and Fishing Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Immersion:&lt;/strong> Added Buy and Sell Torches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Immersion:&lt;/strong> Added Immersive Death Cycle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Skeleton &amp;amp; Animations:&lt;/strong> Removed Draw 2 - Dual Weapon Equip-Unequip Animations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Skeleton &amp;amp; Animations:&lt;/strong> Added Open Animation Replacer - IED Conditions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Skeleton &amp;amp; Animations:&lt;/strong> Added Weapon Styles - DrawSheathe Animations for IED&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Survival &amp;amp; Fishing:&lt;/strong> Removed Apothecary - True Homecooked Meals - Survival Mode Improved Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Survival &amp;amp; Fishing:&lt;/strong> Added Gourmet - Survival Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Survival &amp;amp; Fishing:&lt;/strong> Added Gourmet - Fishing Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Cities of the North:&lt;/strong> Added Gourmet - COTN Cooking Pots and Baking Ovens Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Towns &amp;amp; Villages:&lt;/strong> Added Spaghetti&amp;rsquo;s Orc Strongholds - AIO&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Saints and Seducers:&lt;/strong> Removed Apothecary Anniversary Update - SECSS Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Saints and Seducers:&lt;/strong> Added aljo&amp;rsquo;s Apothecary Patches - SECSS Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Saints and Seducers:&lt;/strong> Added Gourmet - Extended Cut Saints and Seducers Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New &amp;amp; Expanded Quests:&lt;/strong> Removed College of Winterhold - Quest Expansion - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New &amp;amp; Expanded Quests:&lt;/strong> Added The Heart of Dibella - Quest Expansion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Items:&lt;/strong> Removed Actual Sweet Roll Variants - Apothecary Food Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Items:&lt;/strong> Removed Actual Sweet Roll Variants - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Items:&lt;/strong> Removed aMidianBorn Armor Variants Lite - Guard Dialogue Overhaul Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Items:&lt;/strong> Added aMidianBorn Armor Variants Lite - Modular Armory and Wolf Armors and Weapons Retextured Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Items:&lt;/strong> Added Actual Sweet Roll Variants - Gourmet Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Creatures and Enemies:&lt;/strong> Removed Forsworn Gravesingers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Creatures and Enemies:&lt;/strong> Removed Forsworn Skinchangers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Content Integration:&lt;/strong> Added Gourmet - Tamrielic Distribution Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Content Integration:&lt;/strong> Added Gourmet - Tamrielic Distribution &amp;amp; Hand to Hand Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Content Integration:&lt;/strong> Added Gourmet - Tamrielic Distribution &amp;amp; Rare Curios Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Removed fJumpFallHeightMinNPC &lt;code>000EC6C1&lt;/code> changes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Removed edits to LItemFoodInnCommon &lt;code>00098E5F&lt;/code> and LItemFoodInnCommon10 &lt;code>0010E0E1&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Removed various edits to removed Food and Drink mods&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-12">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD to 3.00 Alpha-134&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Synthesis to 0.26&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated powerofthree&amp;rsquo;s Papyrus Extender to 5.6.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Keyword Item Distributor to 3.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Base Object Swapper to 2.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated FormList Manipulator to 1.7.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Universal Unwanted Effects Clearer to 0.3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Beautifully Overhauled and Objectively Better Icons Enriched for SkyUI to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPCs Names Distributor to 2.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Navigator - Navmesh Fixes to 1.4.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Rock Traps Trigger Fixes to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPC Stuck in Bleedout Fix to 0.1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated dunFolgunthurBossBattle Script Fix to 1.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Soul Cairn Script Tweaks to 1.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Flute Animation Fix to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Assorted Mesh Fixes to 0.89&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skill of Sneaking to 1.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Soft Shadows to 2.0 (257)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD - NG to Alpha-11&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD - Resources to 3.00 Alpha-38&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated LOD Model Library for DynDOLOD to 1.3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyland AIO to 4.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyland Bits and Bobs - A Clutter Overhaul to 1.5.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ENBSeries to 0.494 (No version change)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lux to 6.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Embers XD to 2.8.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Diverse Candles - Base Object Swapper to 1.2b&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Misc Effects ENB Light to 1.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Animated Forge Water to 0.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simplicity of Snow to 0.15&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Cathedral - 3D Mountain Flowers - Base Object Swapper to 0.1.22&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Unique Markarth Doors to 0.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Security Overhaul SKSE - Add-ons to 0.1.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mysticism - A Magic Overhaul to 2.3.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Stormcrown - A Shout Overhaul to 1.1.10&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simple Degradation to 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Apothecary - An Alchemy Overhaul to 1.3.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Apothecary Anniversary Update to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Bandit Lines Expansion to 1.08&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Civil War Lines Expansion to 1.07&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Zim&amp;rsquo;s Trainers Expansion to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Blade and Blunt - A Combat Overhaul to 3.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Enemies Respect Encounter Zones to 1.4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Ill Met Bolar&amp;rsquo;s Oathblade to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated C.O.I.N. - Coins of Interesting Natures to 2.1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Container and Arrow Weight Restrictions to 3.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simplest Horses to 0.9.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Headhunter - Bounties Redone to 1.51&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated XP32 Maximum Skeleton Special Extended to 5.04&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Immersive Equipment Displays to 1.7.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Assorted Animation Fixes to 1.02&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Survival Mode Improved to 1.3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Morthal Where&amp;rsquo;s Wares to 1.1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Spaghetti&amp;rsquo;s Cities AIO - CotN Dawnstar Patch to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Spaghetti&amp;rsquo;s Cities AIO - CotN Winterhold Patch to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Spaghetti&amp;rsquo;s Cities AIO - CotN Falkreath Patch to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Saints and Seducers - Mysticism Rebalance to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Extended Cut Saints and Seducers - Mysticism Rebalance to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated College of Winterhold - Quest Expansion to 1.14&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated House of Horrors - Quest Expansion to 1.11&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Only Cure - Quest Expansion to 1.02&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPC Animation Remix to 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Jarl Sitting Animation Replacer to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated lilebonymace&amp;rsquo;s Patches to 2.33&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="outputs-9">Outputs&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regenerated Synthesis - Sorcerer Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated Nemesis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated FaceGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated TexGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated DynDOLOD (and Performance)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-41802">Release 4.18.0.2&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-07-10&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A bigger update than I originally planned, this one could almost be considered 4.18.1! Aurora changed a lot on the visual side of things, especially with character appearance, so brace yourself for that when you jump back into your save file. You might need to type &lt;code>showracemenu&lt;/code> into the console to make adjustments to your Dragonborn since their look has likely changed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that we have the inclusion of &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/95196">&lt;em>Sorcerer&lt;/em>&lt;/a>. Like a few other SimonRim mods this hangs on the edge of the list&amp;rsquo;s scope. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to include it mostly due to its built in rebalancing of magic merchant inventories. The staff and scroll crafting is a little more &amp;ldquo;new mechanics&amp;rdquo; but truthfully it&amp;rsquo;s not anything new alongside Dragonborn&amp;rsquo;s vanilla crafting, &lt;em>Oblivion&lt;/em>, and &lt;em>Arachnomancy&lt;/em> which are already in the list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People who play in 1st Person mode will see some differences due to &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/93962">&lt;em>Improved Camera&lt;/em>&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are a few more settings I need to tweak for complete compatibility but, for now, I think it&amp;rsquo;s working pretty well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This update is save-safe!&lt;/strong> Let me know if you run into any issues. There are still a handful of inconsequential things I want to squash but no luck on those just yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-13">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Applied changes from &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sme/changelog/#release-250">Skyrim Modding Essentials 2.5.0&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/aur/changelog/#release-14">Aurora 1.4.0&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Essential Mods:&lt;/strong> Added Navigator - Navmesh Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>General Fixes:&lt;/strong> Added NPC Stuck in Bleedout Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>General Tweaks:&lt;/strong> Added YASTM - Yet Another Soul Trap Manager&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SKSE Plugins - Tweaks:&lt;/strong> Added Improved Camera&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Appearance:&lt;/strong> Added High Poly Vanilla Hair Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Armor &amp;amp; Weapons:&lt;/strong> Manually updated Elemental Staffs - Mysticism Patch to match Mysticism 2.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Crafting:&lt;/strong> Added Sorcerer - A Staff and Scroll Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Crafting:&lt;/strong> Added Sorcerer - COTN Winterhold Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Crafting:&lt;/strong> Added Sorcerer - Obscure&amp;rsquo;s College of Winterhold Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Items:&lt;/strong> Added Beyond Skyrim Morrowind - Bonemold Weapon Pack - Thaumaturgy WACCF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Items:&lt;/strong> Added Beyond Skyrim Morrowind - Bonemold Weapon Pack - Tamrielic Distribution WACCF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Animations:&lt;/strong> Moved Self-targeting Staff Animation Fix to Skeleton &amp;amp; Animations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Content Integration:&lt;/strong> Modified Tamrielic Distribution to include &lt;code>Tamrielic Distribution - BS Bonemold Weapon Pack.esp&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Updated MerchantWCollegeUragChest &lt;code>0010C430&lt;/code> to include Sorcerer additions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Creation Club Resolution Patch:&lt;/strong> Removed edit to ccBGSSSE037_VarlaStone (no longer needed with YASTM)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Creation Club Resolution Patch:&lt;/strong> Adjusted Dunmeri Tunics edits to be sensible&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-13">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Weapons Armor Clothing and Clutter Fixes to 2.9.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Assorted Mesh Fixes to 0.85&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Photo Mode to 1.1.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyland Bits and Bobs - A Clutter Overhaul to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Particle Patch for ENB to 1.2.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simplicity of Snow to 0.12&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mysticism - A Magic Overhaul to 2.3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Adamant - A Perk Overhaul to 5.8.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Brawl Lines Expansion to 1.02&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Open Animation Replacer to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Hand to Hand - An Adamant Addon to 1.5.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Thaumaturgy - WACCF ACE Patch to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="outputs-10">Outputs&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regenerated FaceGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated LODGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated TexGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated DynDOLOD (and Performance)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-41801">Release 4.18.0.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-07-03&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Just a quick fix for a few issues I noticed personally. For starters, I&amp;rsquo;ve removed multiple Apothecary patches in lieu of a unified Anniversary Update patch. That should make the recipes more consistent and up to date. Then I noticed a lot of issues with the &lt;em>New Armory Series - Lunar Weapons&lt;/em> integration. That&amp;rsquo;s on me as I didn&amp;rsquo;t properly check over it after reverting away from the TPF 5.0 beta. They should have the proper enchantments and tooltips now, and vanilla Silent Moons weapons should no longer appear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other than that, tiny quality of life changes. Stealing items undetected will give Sneak exp based on the value of what was stolen. Potions are no longer distractingly bright (but still emit some light). And &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/91701">Photo Mode&lt;/a>! Access it from the System Menu or just hit &lt;code>P&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This update is save-safe for 4.18 users.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-14">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SKSE Plugins - Tweaks:&lt;/strong> Added Skill of Sneaking&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Interface:&lt;/strong> Added Photo Mode&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ElSopa&amp;rsquo;s Potions Redone:&lt;/strong> Added ElSopa Potions Redone - Less Emissive and Fixed Inventory Size&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ElSopa&amp;rsquo;s Potions Redone:&lt;/strong> Added ElSopa Potions Redone - Less Emissive and Fixed Inventory Size - Xtudo ELIF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Removed Apothecary - Fishing Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Removed Apothecary - Rare Curios Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Removed Apothecary - Saints and Seducers Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Removed Apothecary - Hearthfire Crispy Dumplings Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Added Apothecary Anniversary Update&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Added Apothecary Anniversary Update - Food and Drink Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Survival &amp;amp; Fishing:&lt;/strong> Removed Apothecary - Food and Drink Addon - Survival Mode Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Saints &amp;amp; Seducers:&lt;/strong> Added Apothecary Anniversary Update - SECSS&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Items:&lt;/strong> Removed Ancient Nord Stalhrim - Ebony Assets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Final Patches:&lt;/strong> Edited Enchantable Special Item Fix - TPF Patch to include Lunar Weapons, adjusted incorrect Silver Weapons stats&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution Patch:&lt;/strong> Removed Cooked Boar Meat removal as it&amp;rsquo;s properly handled by the Apothecary Anniversary Update&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution Patch:&lt;/strong> Removed Poisoned Apple recipe edits to no longer require Solvency (Alchemy 60)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution Patch:&lt;/strong> Incorporated necessary Apothecary - Hearthfire Crispy Dumplings Patch changes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution Patch:&lt;/strong> Modified New Armory Series - Lunar Weapons effects to better match Thaumaturgy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Synthesis Patches:&lt;/strong> Removed Mortal Enemies Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-14">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated MQ105SprintTriggerScript Fix to 1.0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Assorted Mesh Fixes to 0.83&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lux (main plugin) to 6.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lux Orbis (main plugin) to 3.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Embers XD to 2.7.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Adamant - A Perk Overhaul to 5.8.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Stormcrown - A Shout Overhaul to 1.1.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simplicity of Seeding to 0.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Ancient Nord Stalhrim to 1.2.4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Tamrielic Distribution to 1.3.3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-4180">Release 4.18.0&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-06-29&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This update has been simmering for a long time and I apologize to everyone who&amp;rsquo;s had to wait patiently while its aroma drifted over them. But the wait is over: &lt;strong>4.18 is here!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the visuals. I&amp;rsquo;ve removed some more deviations I&amp;rsquo;ve made from Aurora such as &lt;em>eFPS&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Enhanced Landscapes&lt;/em> so that the visuals are more in line with Phoenix&amp;rsquo;s amazing work. I&amp;rsquo;ve also switched back to &lt;em>Realistic Water Two&lt;/em> which is Aurora&amp;rsquo;s water mod of choice. We&amp;rsquo;re still using RAID Weathers and The Vanilla ENB 2 since I want stealth mechanics to remain predictable in a game with no stealth meter. &lt;em>Frozen Electrocuted Combustion&lt;/em> has also been removed. It&amp;rsquo;s a good mod but there are some weird interactions and ultimately the effects take away some of the visual oomph of the late-game Destruction perks. (I still haven&amp;rsquo;t sorted out the LOD unload bug in the winter, unfortunately. If you experience it, just save and reload where you are.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gameplay is where the meat of the update lies. &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/90659">Stormcrown&lt;/a>&lt;/em> has been added alongside the &lt;em>Adamant - Bard Perks Addon&lt;/em> to move shouts into a perk tree everyone can benefit from and add more functionality to Speech tree respectively. As such, shouts as a whole have a different approach compared to &lt;em>Forceful Tongue&lt;/em> and I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the Example Builds section to account for the changes. Enemy resistances have also changed slightly with a switch to &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/59394">Enemy Resistance Tweaks&lt;/a>&lt;/em>. Last but not least of the big gameplay changes is the removal of &lt;em>Honed Metal&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s been in the list a long time but it&amp;rsquo;s been hard to balance it the way I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted &lt;em>and&lt;/em> its features are quickly becoming redundant. Instead of removing it in a few months I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to rip the bandaid off now. The &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sss/gameplay-guide">gameplay guide&lt;/a> has been updated to reflect this as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>THIS UPDATE IS NOT SAVE-SAFE.&lt;/strong> Please start a new game. Please.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Unless you&amp;rsquo;ve been using the 4.17.1 beta. Then you can install this after first Uninstalling Honed Metal via its MCM. &lt;em>Stormcrown&lt;/em> also made some changes since 1.1.4 that might result in funkiness so a new game is &lt;em>encouraged&lt;/em> but not required.)&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-15">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Applied changes from &lt;a href="https://publish.obsidian.md/tpf/meta/changelogs/sme/sme-2-4-2">Skyrim Modding Essentials 2.4.2&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sme/changelog/#release-243">2.4.3&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://publish.obsidian.md/tpf/meta/changelogs/aur/aur-1-3">Aurora 1.3&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Utilities &amp;amp; Frameworks:&lt;/strong> Removed Constructible Object Custom Keyword System - Separate Weapon and Armor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Utilities &amp;amp; Frameworks:&lt;/strong> Added Constructible Object Custom Keyword System - Light Usability Tweaks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Utilities &amp;amp; Frameworks:&lt;/strong> Added Custom Skills Framework&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>General Fixes:&lt;/strong> Added Self-targeting Staff Animation Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Script Fixes:&lt;/strong> Added MQ105SprintTriggerScript Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Script Fixes:&lt;/strong> Added DLC2AudioRepeaterActivator01Script Tweak&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>(Optional) Nordic UI:&lt;/strong> Removed NORDIC UI - Compass Navigation Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mesh Improvements:&lt;/strong> Removed Better Windhelm Ground Meshes - Valunstrad&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mesh Improvements:&lt;/strong> Removed Solitude Objects SMIMed - Solitude Well&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mesh Improvements:&lt;/strong> Removed Solitude Objects SMIMed - Castle Dour Spire&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Yuril&amp;rsquo;s Mesh Edits:&lt;/strong> Removed FYX - Eastern Empire Company Building - eFPS Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Graphics Baseline:&lt;/strong> Removed eFPS - Exterior FPS Boost&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Graphics Baseline:&lt;/strong> Removed Unofficial eFPS Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Graphics Baseline:&lt;/strong> Removed Revamped Assets Skyrim - Weapon Racks Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Removed Enhanced Landscapes (and relevant patches)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Snow &amp;amp; Ice:&lt;/strong> Removed Snowy Landscapes in Snowy Regions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seasons of Skyrim:&lt;/strong> Moved section to match Aurora documentation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seasons of Skyrim:&lt;/strong> Removed Shrubs of Snow&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seasons of Skyrim:&lt;/strong> Added Seasonal Landscapes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seasons of Skyrim:&lt;/strong> Added Sowables of Skyrim - Snowy Versions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lux Lighting:&lt;/strong> Removed Mesh Patches for Lux Orbis (redundant)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Visual FX:&lt;/strong> Removed Frozen Electrocuted Combustion (and relevant patches)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Water &amp;amp; Splash FX:&lt;/strong> Swapped out Water for ENB for Realistic Water Two (and all related patches)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Trees:&lt;/strong> Removed Seasonal Aspen Trees - Turn of the Seasons Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Trees:&lt;/strong> Removed 3D Junipers - Trees and Berries&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Trees:&lt;/strong> Removed Dead Shrubs Resized&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Plants &amp;amp; Mushrooms:&lt;/strong> Removed Cathedral - 3D Sword Ferns&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Plants &amp;amp; Mushrooms:&lt;/strong> Removed Cathedral - 3D Clover Plant&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Plants &amp;amp; Mushrooms:&lt;/strong> Removed Drier Cathedral - 3D Clover Plant&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Plants &amp;amp; Mushrooms:&lt;/strong> Removed Cathedral - 3D Lavender&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Plants &amp;amp; Mushrooms:&lt;/strong> Removed Cathedral - 3D Dragons Tongue&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Plants &amp;amp; Mushrooms:&lt;/strong> Removed Cathedral - 3D Nightshade&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Plants &amp;amp; Mushrooms:&lt;/strong> Removed Cathedral - 3D Deathbell&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Plants &amp;amp; Mushrooms:&lt;/strong> Removed Improved Gourds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Magic &amp;amp; Perks:&lt;/strong> Removed Adamant - Speech Exp Based on Words&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Magic &amp;amp; Perks:&lt;/strong> Removed Forceful Tongue - Shouts Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Magic &amp;amp; Perks:&lt;/strong> Removed Forceful Tongue - SimonRim Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Magic &amp;amp; Perks:&lt;/strong> Removed Dragon Aspect Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Magic &amp;amp; Perks:&lt;/strong> Added Adamant - Bard Perks Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Mechanics:&lt;/strong> Added Stormcrown - A Shout Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Magic &amp;amp; Perks:&lt;/strong> Added Aetherius - Starting Spells Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Magic &amp;amp; Perks:&lt;/strong> Added Aetherius - NPC Spell Absorption Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Crafting:&lt;/strong> Removed Honed Metal&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Crafting:&lt;/strong> Removed Honed Metal Revoiced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Removed HearthFires - Customizable Fertile Soil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Added Simplicity of Seeding&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounter Zones:&lt;/strong> Removed Blade and Blunt - Sneak Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NPC Dialogue &amp;amp; Behavior:&lt;/strong> Removed Misc Dialogue Edits and More Dialogue Options - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NPC Dialogue &amp;amp; Behavior:&lt;/strong> Added Brawl Lines Expansion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NPC Dialogue &amp;amp; Behavior:&lt;/strong> Added NPCs React to Invisibility&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounter Zones:&lt;/strong> Separated part out into a new Enemy Overhauls section&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounter Zones:&lt;/strong> Added Dynamic Random Dragons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enemy Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Removed Resistances &amp;amp; Weaknesses&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enemy Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Removed Resistances &amp;amp; Weaknesses - NPC Armaments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enemy Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Added Enemy Resistance Tweaks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enemy Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Added Lore Friendly Ghosts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Quest Start Adjustments:&lt;/strong> Added Delayed Quest Starts - Blood on the Ice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Immersion:&lt;/strong> Removed Open World Loot - C.O.I.N. Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Miscellaneous:&lt;/strong> Removed Misc Tweaks - No Starting Spells&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Miscellaneous:&lt;/strong> Removed Forceful Tongue - Durnehviir Resurrected Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Miscellaneous:&lt;/strong> Added Stormcrown - Durnehviir Resurrected Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Miscellaneous:&lt;/strong> Added Stormcrown - Unique Dragon Aspect Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Sound FX:&lt;/strong> Removed Forceful Tongue - Audio Overhaul for Skyrim Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Skeleton &amp;amp; Animations:&lt;/strong> Removed Dynamic Animation Replacer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Skeleton &amp;amp; Animations:&lt;/strong> Added Open Animation Replacer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Survival &amp;amp; Fishing:&lt;/strong> Added Fish Plaque Fixes and Improvements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Survival &amp;amp; Fishing:&lt;/strong> Added U Can&amp;rsquo;t Touch Fish&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mandragorasprouts&amp;rsquo; Statues:&lt;/strong> Renamed section from Daedric Shrines&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mandragorasprouts&amp;rsquo; Statues:&lt;/strong> Added Daedric Shrines - All in One - Azura Loading Screen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mandragorasprouts&amp;rsquo; Statues:&lt;/strong> Added Daedric Shrines - Hircine Skull Mask Version&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mandragorasprouts&amp;rsquo; Statues:&lt;/strong> Added Statue of Kynareth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mandragorasprouts&amp;rsquo; Statues:&lt;/strong> Added Kynareth Replaces Talos - Civil War Consequence&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New &amp;amp; Expanded Quests:&lt;/strong> Added Caught Red Handed - NGCDT Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Mechanics:&lt;/strong> Removed Pilgrim - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Mechanics:&lt;/strong> Added Adamant - Bard Perks Addon - Pilgrim Integration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Items:&lt;/strong> Removed Royal Armory - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Items:&lt;/strong> Added Royal Armory - Plugin Replacer - Adjustments and Rebalancing for Thaumaturgy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Animations:&lt;/strong> Added Leviathan Animations II - Greatsword Sprint Attacks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Animations:&lt;/strong> Added Leviathan Animations II - Greatsword Power Attacks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Removed overwrite to &lt;code>000C3691&lt;/code> as its no longer needed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Moved PlacedObject &lt;code>000A9539&lt;/code> changes to CRP to remove Lux - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Moved DerkeethusCell &lt;code>0002C993&lt;/code> changes to CRP to remove Lux - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Moved MAG_PoisonRuneFFLocation &lt;code>0401D74C&lt;/code> changes to CRP to remove SimonRim - TPF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Removed edits to MAG_VoiceUnrelentingForceEffect03 &lt;code>0007F82F&lt;/code> to let Stormcrown do its thing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Swapped Forceful Tongue&amp;rsquo;s WOOP edits for Stormcrown&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Added new shouts to Pilgrim&amp;rsquo;s MAG_ShoutList &lt;code>xx335269&lt;/code> for Talos&amp;rsquo; blessing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Forwarded necessary Aetherius changes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Resolved MAGShockImpact02 &lt;code>00059ED8&lt;/code> in a different way&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Cleaned up files that were no longer needed (hopefully!)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-15">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Fluency Themes to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Root Builder to 4.4.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD to 3.00 Alpha-128&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Payload Interpreter to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Versatile Item and Group Re-Assignment to 1.0.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPCs Names Distributor to 2.1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Weapons Armor Clothing and Clutter Fixes to 2.9.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ConsolePlusPlus to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Keyboard Shortcuts Fix to 1.0.0.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragonactorscript Infinite Loop Fix to 1.3.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Assorted Mesh Fixes to 0.82&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reverted Skyrim Skill Uncapper to vadfromnu&amp;rsquo;s 0.1.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Delphine&amp;rsquo;s Map Reveals Dragon Mounds to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Compass Navigation Overhaul to 2.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Spinning Load Screens to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NORDIC UI - Compass Markers Restored to 1.4.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD Resources to 3.00 Alpha-37&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated xLODGen Resource - SSE Terrain Tamriel to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ENBSeries to 0.494&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lux to 6.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lux Ortbis to 3.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Embers XD to 2.7.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Rudy HQ - More Dramatic Red Mountain Plume to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyrim Remastered - Glaciers and Ice to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Icy Caves to 2.1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Icy Mesh Remaster to 2.20&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Happy Little Logs to 1.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated HQ Vanilla Tiny Rocks to 2.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Stony AF Markarth and Dwemer Ruins to 2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Imperial Armors and Weapons Retexture to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Elven Armors and Weapons Retexture to 1.01&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Orcish Armors and Weapons Retexture to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Ebony Armors and Weapons Retexture to 1.21&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Daedric Armors and Weapons Retexture to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Adamant - A Perk Overhaul to 5.8.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mundus - A Standing Stone Overhaul to 1.10.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mundus - A Standing Stone Overhaul - USSEP Patch to 1.0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Aetherius - A Race Overhaul to 2.11.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Cooking Categories Improvement to 2.0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Misc Dialogue Edits to 1.9.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Hunters Not Bandits to 4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Narrative Gameplay Consistent Dialogue Tweaks to 1.5.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated More Dialogue Options to 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Immersive Rejections to 1.11&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Ashlander Nomads Names to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Daedric Names to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dovah Names to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Reachmen Tribes Names 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Tamrielic Names to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Arena - An Encounter Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Blade and Blunt - A Combat Overhaul to 3.0.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Blade and Blunt - Health Regeneration Addon to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Enemies Respect Encounter Zones to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - A Dragon Overhaul to 3.0.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Deadly Spell Impacts Patch to 3.0.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Deiform Alduin Particle Lights Patch to 3.0.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Dragon Cult - A Draugr Overhaul to 1.3.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated At Your Own Pace - College of Winterhold to 2.1MG&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Choice is Yours (no version change)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Misc Dialogue Edits - Save the Icerunner Patch to 1.9.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated More Dialogue Options - Thieves Guild Reformation Patch to 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Headhunter - Bounties Redone to 1.50&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Destination Weddings to 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Destination Weddings - Compatibility Patches to 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Durnehviir Resurrected Patch to 3.0.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Audio Overhaul for Skyrim Patch to 3.0.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dynamic Animation Casting to 3.2.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Survival Mode Improved to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Turn of the Seasons to 1.0.7.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Hand to Hand - An Adamant Addon to 1.5.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated New Armory Series - Lunar Weapons - A Silent Moons Overhaul to 1.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Civil War Deserters to 2.0.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated GRAHL - Apothecary Patch to 15&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Conditional Armor Type Animations to 1.3c&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Vanargand Animations - Sprint to 1.3c&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Vanargand Animations - Female Idle Walk and Run to 1.3.1c&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Vanargand Animations - Male Idle Walk and Run to 1.3.1c&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Leviathan Animations II - Sprint to 2.4c&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Leviathan Animations II - Female Idle Walk And Run to 2.3c&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Leviathan Animations II - Male Idle Walk And Run to 2.3c&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Goetia Animations - Sprint to 1.0c&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Goetia Animations - Female Idle Walk And Run to 1.2c&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Goetia Animations - Male Idle Walk And Run to 1.3c&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Take A Seat to 1.01&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated lilebonymace&amp;rsquo;s Patches to 2.32&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-41702">Release 4.17.0.2&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-05-18&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This update was left on the backburner for a few reasons but I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to push it out today assuming the next update will require a new game. Why will the next update require a new game, you ask? Because &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/90659">Stormcrown&lt;/a> released and some of you might have talked to Paarthurnax already. There are a few other mods that I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of switching out as well, so I&amp;rsquo;m considering this a good staging point for figuring out the next steps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another reason the update was stalled was because I wanted to update the Example Builds section a bit more. I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten around to all the changes I wanted to implement so the builds are slightly out of date with Simonrim. I plan on giving them all some polishing with the Stormcrown update as the shouts sections will obviously need adjusting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The changelog looks lengthy but there aren&amp;rsquo;t too many big changes. Just some gameplay updates to be aware of, such as the Blade and Blunt - Health Regeneration Addon. With this, you will regenerate Health back to 50% regardless of Survival mechanics, but you&amp;rsquo;ll still need other means of recovery if you want to get back to full Health.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s also a known LOD bug that&amp;rsquo;s most noticeable in the Winter season. If you notice weird flickering or floating snow in your travels, just save and reload in place and it should fix itself. Hopefully this is fully fixed in newer versions of DynDOLOD, but for now it&amp;rsquo;s something we have to live with.&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-16">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Cleaned up archives list, should lower the download size a fair amount&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Applied changes from &lt;a href="https://publish.obsidian.md/tpf/meta/changelogs/sme/sme-2-3-3">Skyrim Modding Essentials 2.3.3&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://publish.obsidian.md/tpf/meta/changelogs/sme/sme-2-4">2.4&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://publish.obsidian.md/tpf/meta/changelogs/sme/sme-2-4-1">2.4.1&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://publish.obsidian.md/tpf/meta/changelogs/aur/aur-1-1">Aurora 1.1&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://publish.obsidian.md/tpf/meta/changelogs/aur/aur-1-2">1.2&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>TPF 5.0 Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed Small Environmental Fixes (AO and Transition)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>TPF 5.0 Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed Small Environmental Fixes - Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Interface:&lt;/strong> Temporarily disabled Compass Navigation Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Graphics Baseline:&lt;/strong> Removed Skyland AIO - Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lux Lighting:&lt;/strong> Removed Lux Via - Morthal Crash Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lux Lighting:&lt;/strong> Switched to Even Brighter Templates&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Trees:&lt;/strong> Removed Happy Little Trees - Ivy on Trees&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Magic &amp;amp; Perks:&lt;/strong> Moved Adamant - Weapons Armor Clothing and Clutter Fixes Patch into lilebonymace&amp;rsquo;s Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Removed Book Covers Skyrim - Apothecary Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Added Apothecary - Book Covers Skyrim Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Alchemy, Cooking, &amp;amp; Farming:&lt;/strong> Moved Apothecary - Weapons Armor Clothing and Clutter Fixes Patch into lilebonymace&amp;rsquo;s Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NPC Dialogue &amp;amp; Behavior:&lt;/strong> Moved Thugs Not Assassins - Timing Is Everything Patch Fix into lilebonymace&amp;rsquo;s Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounter Zones:&lt;/strong> Added Blade and Blunt - Health Regeneration Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Quest Start Adjustments:&lt;/strong> Moved The Choice Is Yours - DLC2 March of the Dead Fix Patch into lilebonymace&amp;rsquo;s Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Quest Start Adjustments:&lt;/strong> Moved The Choice Is Yours - Lod Dialogue Tweak into lilebonymace&amp;rsquo;s Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Miscellaneous:&lt;/strong> Moved Contraband Confiscated - USSEP Patch into lilebonymace&amp;rsquo;s Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New &amp;amp; Expanded Quests:&lt;/strong> Moved House of Horrors - No More Logrolf Houdini Patch into lilebonymace&amp;rsquo;s Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New &amp;amp; Expanded Quests:&lt;/strong> Moved House of Horrors - The Choice Is Yours Patch into lilebonymace&amp;rsquo;s Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Items:&lt;/strong> Added aMidianBorn Armor Variants Lite - Modular Armory and Wolf Armors and Weapons Retextured Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Items:&lt;/strong> Added PrivateEye&amp;rsquo;s Royal Armory - Loadscreen Models Update as a separate mod&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Creatures and Enemies:&lt;/strong> Removed Skinshifters - Forsworn Doppelgangers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Resolved Leveled List conflict between Apothecary and Ish&amp;rsquo;s Respec Mod &lt;code>0009CD41&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Disabled EVG Conditional Idles&amp;rsquo; shield cover animations by default&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-16">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Spell Perk Item Distributor to 6.6.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated MergeMapper to 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Beautifully Overhauled and Objectively Better Icons Enriched for SkyUI to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Universal Cured Serana Eye Fix to 0.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Assorted Mesh Fixes to 0.79&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyrim Landscape and Water Fixes to 7.9&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Don&amp;rsquo;t Stay in the Water to 5.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated CoMAP - Common Marker Addon Project to 4.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Whose Quest Is It Anyway (no version change)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ENBSeries to 0.493&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lux Via to 1.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rolled Embers XD back to 2.7.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Icy Mesh Remaster to 2.14&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Cathedral - 3D Mountain Flowers - Base Object Swapperto 0.1.20&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Unique Red Wave to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mysticism - A Magic Overhaul to 2.2.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Adamant - A Perk Overhaul to 5.7.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Thaumaturgy - An Enchanting Overhaul to 1.3.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Apothecary - An Alchemy Overhaul to 1.3.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lawless - A Bandit Overhaul to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lawless - SimonRim Patch to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lawless - Expanded Enemy Coverage Addon to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lawless - Patch Collection to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - A Dragon Overhaul to 3.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Deadly Spell Impacts Patch to 3.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Deiform Alduin Particle Lights Patch to 3.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Dragon Cult - A Draugr Overhaul to 1.3.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated At Your Own Pace - College of Winterhold to 2.0.1MG&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Paarthurnax - Quest Expansion to 1.12&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Immersive Display Overhaul to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Survival Mode Improved to 1.1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Destination Weddings to 1.4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Durnehviir Resurrected Patch to 3.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Audio Overhaul for Skyrim to 4.1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dragon War - Audio Overhaul for Skyrim Patch to 3.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Caught Red Handed - Quest Expansion to 1.04&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Hand to Hand - An Adamant Addon to 1.4.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Gesture Animation Remix to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="outputs-11">Outputs&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Reuploaded Nemesis (previous upload flagged for some reason)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated Synthesis Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated TexGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated DynDOLOD (and Performance)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-41701">Release 4.17.0.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-04-23&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>There were a few issues with the release of 4.17. Thank you SAEL in particular for catching the bulk of them and bringing them to my attention. The root cause of some was the Embers XD 2.7.4 beta, rather, the existing patches that did not account for it. Since I went through the trouble of fixing those, the beta stays in this version despite it being temporarily &amp;ldquo;retired&amp;rdquo; by mindflux on the Nexus. If that causes issues, I&amp;rsquo;ll revert back to 2.7.3 and undo the fixes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More importantly, &lt;em>NPCs Learn Skills and Spells&lt;/em> has been removed. It was a fun experiment but now that Lawless and The Dragon Cult exist, we have a lot more intention with the enemy overhauling. We don&amp;rsquo;t need SPID buffing up the enemies even more, and it turns out it was buffing them much more than intended. Sorry to everyone who ran into Lv1 bandits summoning atronachs, that should be fixed now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Otherwise, it&amp;rsquo;s a small update that follows its base list, &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/898050">Aurora&lt;/a>, in its official 1.0 release! Congrats to Phoenix for delivering another solid modlist to the community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This update is save-safe.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-17">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Applied changes from &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sme/changelog/#release-232">Skyrim Modding Essentials 2.3.2&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://publish.obsidian.md/tpf/meta/changelogs/aurora/aur-1-0">Aurora 1.0&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Utilities &amp;amp; Frameworks:&lt;/strong> Added Beautifully Overhauled and Objectively Better Icons Enriched for SkyUI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ElSopa&amp;rsquo;s Potions Redone:&lt;/strong> Added ElSopa - Potions Redone - Apothecary Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Magic &amp;amp; Perks:&lt;/strong> Removed NPCs Learn Skills and Spells (as it&amp;rsquo;s incorrectly processing NPCs)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Resolved differences between Embers XD and Frozen Electrocuted Combustion for FireFXShader &lt;code>0001B212&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Resolved differences between Embers XD and No Edge Glow for DarkElfAncestorWrathFXShader &lt;code>0010F56C&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-17">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Keyword Item Distributor to 3.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mesh Patches for Lux Orbis to 1.5.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Embers XD to 2.7.4 Beta (No Version Change)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Stones of Solitude - Majestic Mountains Rocks to 1.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Icy Mesh Remaster to 2.12&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Immersive Rejections to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lawless - SimonRim Patch to 1.6.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Dragon Cult - A Draugr Overhaul to 1.3.2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-4170">Release 4.17.0&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-04-17&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s no changelog here. There was one, once. It was massive and I lost it in the ether. After that there were hundreds of other changes made. I should do better. Another time, perhaps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this is a &lt;strong>huge&lt;/strong> update, make no mistake. If you&amp;rsquo;re coming from 4.16.0.&lt;em>x&lt;/em>, just &lt;strong>make a new save file&lt;/strong>. It&amp;rsquo;s not save-safe. If you&amp;rsquo;re coming from 4.16.1.&lt;em>x&lt;/em> &lt;strong>you probably should also make a new save&lt;/strong> but it&amp;rsquo;s possibly salvageable. So what&amp;rsquo;s changed?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I mentioned in the last release candidate, Phoenix is back and they&amp;rsquo;ve changed their approach to TPF 5.0. It will be built on &lt;strong>Aurora&lt;/strong> which is built on &lt;strong>Skyrim Modding Essentials&lt;/strong>. This makes it very streamlined for Phoenix, building each list right on top of the other. So I&amp;rsquo;ve gone ahead and tossed out pretty much everything visual and also made this list based off of Aurora&amp;rsquo;s release candidate (RC5 currently). It looks fantastic and the textures were selected with a lot more care than I&amp;rsquo;m capable of. I still kept RAID Weathers (and RAID), Water for ENB, and The Vanilla ENB Two, so it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly the same as Aurora, but it&amp;rsquo;s close.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The gameplay sections have moved around in anticipation for TPF 5.0. Phoenix has been posting their documentation and I can see how things are formatted for the future. I don&amp;rsquo;t know which mods will be in TPF 5.0 so I&amp;rsquo;ve more or less smashed the current gameplay mod sections into their new separators and called it a day. When TPF comes out I will take notes on what direction Phoenix went in and adjust, but this list may just continue being an Aurora fork.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Could I have been more discerning and gone through every mod to see if I still liked it? Sure.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Will I do that at a later date? Probably.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What&amp;rsquo;s this then? I suppose technically it&amp;rsquo;s still a SSS 5.0 beta, but the official WJ download has been neglected for awhile so I thought to bring everyone up to speed with this release.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Does this need more polish? On the back end, sure. The game should play great and look great. I just need to clean things up from an organization perspective.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>No, seriously, at some point I&amp;rsquo;ll get around to cleaning up the load order and sorting out the CR patches to look less work-in-progress. But since the list is based off of two of Phoenix&amp;rsquo;s release candidates, perhaps work-in-progress is how it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to look.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken Phoenix&amp;rsquo;s visual overhaul from Aurora, trimmed down the added equipment from TPF 5.0, but otherwise kept its bug fixes and changes to quests/NPCs until TPF 5.0 is officially released. At which point I&amp;rsquo;ll decide if I&amp;rsquo;m going to be a fork off Aurora or a fork off TPF and tweak accordingly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>tl;dr changes from 4.16.2 RC 1:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Visuals overhauled to match Aurora RC5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Phoenix&amp;rsquo;s Weapons &amp;amp; Armor Overhaul removed in lieu for a restored Weapons, Armor, Clothing, and Clutter Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Some of the added weapons and armor (e.g. Stalhrim Extra Crafting) was removed until balance can be better achieved&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optional difficulty modules removed, Aurora optionals maintained&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Thanks for listening to my TED Talk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seriously though, &lt;strong>start a new save file.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="release-4162-rc-1">Release 4.16.2 RC 1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-03-05&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a few weeks since the last release candidate and we&amp;rsquo;ve found some issues that have been ironed out. The Uncapper should work as intended now with its latest update, Hulking Draugr shouldn&amp;rsquo;t lower your attack speed into oblivion, and Simon has released a handful of fixes and updates before taking a well-deserved break. I&amp;rsquo;m still not entirely comfortable calling it a full release but we&amp;rsquo;re close. Provided there&amp;rsquo;s no huge issues with this update, it will go live on Wabbajack.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In other news, Phoenix has returned from their break! Alongside that news are changes to how they&amp;rsquo;re approaching TPF 5.0 and their other lists and those changes will eventually trickle down into SSS. For instance, there will be a visuals-only list that will essentially replace the visuals here once it&amp;rsquo;s released. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently taken visuals into my own hands with this release candidate but honestly I regret it and will love to put that back into Phoenix&amp;rsquo;s hands. On that note, I&amp;rsquo;ve added the new xavbio armor and weapons textures where they&amp;rsquo;ve been patched for &lt;em>Modular Armory&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other major additions for this release include a number of quality of life mods in the crafting world such as &lt;em>Recipe Auto-Learn&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Cooking Categories Improvement.&lt;/em> Crafting menus all around should be nicely sorted and discovering new alchemical effects should be a smidge less trial and error.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This update is safe-save.&lt;/strong> Just save in an interior cell before updating due to the change in DynDOLOD outputs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, full disclosure, Lux updated everything in the final moments before pushing this update so I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to properly test out the changes (which haven&amp;rsquo;t even been posted at this time) or re-run the LODs. There might be minor issues. This is precisely the type of thing I want to avoid by letting Phoenix handle the visuals.&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-18">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SKSE Plugins:&lt;/strong> Added Inventory Interface Information Injector&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SKSE Plugins:&lt;/strong> Added Recipe Auto-Learn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Interface:&lt;/strong> Added Versatile Item and Group Re-Assignment&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Interface:&lt;/strong> Added Cooking Categories Improvement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Weather &amp;amp; Lighting:&lt;/strong> Removed Enhanced Volumetric Lighting and Shadows&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Removed Majestic Mountains - More Accurate Collision - AME Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Added Enhanced Rocks and Mountains - Majestic Mountains Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Trees, Grass, &amp;amp; Plants:&lt;/strong> Added Cathedral - 3D Nightshade&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Trees, Grass, &amp;amp; Plants:&lt;/strong> Added Cathedral - 3D Dragons Tongue&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Trees, Grass, &amp;amp; Plants:&lt;/strong> Merged ENB Light Patch with Caveworm Plate Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Apparel &amp;amp; Weapons:&lt;/strong> Removed Modular Armory - Male Horns for Female Iron Helmet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Apparel &amp;amp; Weapons:&lt;/strong> Added Iron Armors and Weapons Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Apparel &amp;amp; Weapons:&lt;/strong> Added Modular Armory - Iron Armors and Weapons Retexture Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Apparel &amp;amp; Weapons:&lt;/strong> Added Steel Armors and Weapons Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Apparel &amp;amp; Weapons:&lt;/strong> Added Modular Armory - Steel Armors and Weapons Retexture Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Apparel &amp;amp; Weapons:&lt;/strong> Added Orcish Armors and Weapons Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Apparel &amp;amp; Weapons:&lt;/strong> Added Modular Armory - Orcish Armors and Weapons Retexture Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Balance &amp;amp; Crafting:&lt;/strong> Added Alchemy Recipe Expansion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Balance &amp;amp; Crafting:&lt;/strong> Added Alchemy Recipe Expansion - Book Covers Skyrim Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Balance &amp;amp; Crafting:&lt;/strong> Added Alchemy Recipe Expansion - Apothecary Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Non-Player Characters:&lt;/strong> Added Vampire Lines Expansion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Non-Player Characters:&lt;/strong> Added Vampire Lines Expansion - Orc Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounters:&lt;/strong> Added Locational Encounter Zones&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Hid &amp;lsquo;Combat End Reset&amp;rsquo;spell from Seeking Out Sneaks from the effects menu&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-18">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD to 3.00 Alpha-118&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ENBSeries to 0.488&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Root Builder to 4.4.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Papyrus Tweaks to 4.1.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyrim Landscape and Water Fixes to 7.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated powerofthree&amp;rsquo;s Tweaks to 1.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Bash Bug Fix to 3.0.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyrim Skill Uncapper to 2.1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD Resources to 3.00 Alpha-31&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Embers XD to 2.7.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Parallax Spell Impacts 1.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Majestic Mountains - Simplicity of Snow Patch to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Water for ENB to 1.76&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyland - Happy Little Trees Bark to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Modular Armory to 1.3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mysticism - A Magic Overhaul to 2.2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Aetherius - A Race Overhaul to 2.10.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Canis Hysteria - The Werewolf Disease to 1.0.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Forceful Tongue - Shouts Overhaul to 3.0.9.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated C.O.I.N. - Coins of Interesting Natures to 2.1.1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated More Craftable Equipment to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated AI Overhaul to 1.8.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Bandit Lines Expansion to 1.07&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Civil War Lines Expansion to 1.06&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPCs Wear Amulets of Mara to 2.03&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Dragon Cult - A Draugr Overhaul to 1.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Headhunter - Bounties Redone to 1.43&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Survival Mode Improved to 1.0.10&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyrim Extended Cut - Saints and Seducers to 1.0.0.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Saints &amp;amp; Seducers - Mysticism Rebalance to 2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Extended Cut Saints and Seducers - Mysticism Rebalance to 2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mysticism - Survival Spells Addon to 1.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Hand to Hand - An Adamant Addon to 1.4.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated East Empire Company Armor to 2.0.0.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPC Animation Remix to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Tamrielic Distribution to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lux to 6.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lux Via to 1.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Lux Orbis to 3.2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="outputs-12">Outputs&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regenerated Left Hand Weapon Meshes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated LODGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated TexGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated DynDOLOD (and Performance)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-4161-rc-3">Release 4.16.1 RC 3&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-02-13&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a little over a week and I&amp;rsquo;ve a short trip coming up so I wanted to put out an update before then. Thank you everyone that&amp;rsquo;s been helping me test so far (and big thanks to Berna for finding some bugs to squash!) but I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s quite ready for a full release just yet. This update is mostly just updates to existing mods, however one of those mods is &lt;em>The Vanilla ENB Two&lt;/em> which had a huge update since RC 2 came out. Overall it&amp;rsquo;s an amazing step forward and I love how it looks but it does come with a bit of a performance hit. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I tweaked the Performance Profile enough to compensate, but let me know if the hit&amp;rsquo;s too much compared to the last release (and 4.16.0, even) so I can see what I can do about dialing it back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This update is save safe.&lt;/strong> Nothing new has been generated. Have fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-19">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Weather &amp;amp; Lighting:&lt;/strong> Removed Pouring Rain&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Interiors:&lt;/strong> Added Skyland Common and Upper Furniture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Clutter:&lt;/strong> Removed upperclass meshes and furniture from Rudy HQ - Miscellaneous&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Animations:&lt;/strong> Added Improved Table Transition Animations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lux, Lux Orbis, &amp;amp; Lux Via:&lt;/strong> Added Lux - Pilgrim - Daedric Shrines Patch (from Ro)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Add &amp;ldquo;No Grass in Cabin&amp;rdquo; changes (thanks to Berna)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Fixed Lunar Armory loadscreen (also thanks to Berna)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Removed &lt;code>textures/landscape/grass/columbine.dds&lt;/code> from the ENB Complex Grass collection (hat trick for Berna)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-19">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated powerofthree&amp;rsquo;s Papyrus Extender to 5.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Bash Bug Fix to 2.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyrim Skill Uncapper to 2.1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Unique Map Weather to 1.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Water for ENB to 1.74&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Happy Little Trees - Ivy on Trees to 1.1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Animated Forge Water to 0.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Cost of a Mistake - Increased Guild Fines to 3.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Misc Dialogue Edits to 1.8.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Zim&amp;rsquo;s Trainers Expansion to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Misc Dialogue Edits - Save the Icerunner Patch to 1.8.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Blade and Blunt - A Combat Overhaul to 2.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Unequip Quiver to 2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Snowy Surfaces Sound Collision and Aesthetics to 1.6.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Headhunter - Bounties Redone to 1.42&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Hand to Hand - An Adamant Addon to 1.4.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Icy Mesh Remaster to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Vanilla ENB Two to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-4161-rc-2">Release 4.16.1 RC 2&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-02-05&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Whoops, that was a quick update. This one&amp;rsquo;s short but impactful. If your character plans on doing a lot of sneaking around I&amp;rsquo;d advise restarting. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to but the values won&amp;rsquo;t be the intended. If not, you probably won&amp;rsquo;t notice too much difference other than the lighting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>EVLaS&lt;/em> is gone for now. Will it come back? Possibly, but it would require a workable adjustment for &lt;em>The Vanilla ENB Two&lt;/em> in order to prevent some of the intense outdoor shadows you may have encountered. Even with that fix, the shaodws the mod produces don&amp;rsquo;t actually affect your current light level, so hiding in them won&amp;rsquo;t make you stealthier. It&amp;rsquo;s misleading and in a game with no other indicators, not good design. So I had to drop it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also updated &lt;em>DWTD&lt;/em> values so that &lt;em>R.A.I.D.&lt;/em>&amp;lsquo;s settings properly pass through. Since &lt;em>RAID Weathers&lt;/em> was designed with stealth in mind, some of DWTD&amp;rsquo;s features were doubling down on what NPCs were already experiencing. I&amp;rsquo;ve turned off some of those features and left others, such as NPCs hearing less in the rain or searching a small radius in bad weathers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>R.A.S.S. was removed because it was on the fence to begin with, half of the mod was turned off and the other half wasn&amp;rsquo;t looking great in action. &lt;em>S.W.I.F.T.&lt;/em> was removed because it trivialized some of the established methods of fast traveling (carriage, ferry, spells) that existed through other mods. The mod itself is great but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit the list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All in all, an update centered around mods with initializations.&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-20">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Weather &amp;amp; Lighting:&lt;/strong> Removed Enhanced Volumetric Lighting and Shadows (EVLaS)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fire &amp;amp; Visual FX:&lt;/strong> Removed R.A.S.S. - Rain Ash And Snow Shaders&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fire &amp;amp; Visual FX:&lt;/strong> R.A.S.S. - Rain Ash And Snow Shaders - Settings Loader&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Architecture:&lt;/strong> Fixed Windhelm Bridge Stairs&amp;hellip; again&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounters:&lt;/strong> Edited Dynamic Weather and Time Based Detection to properly detect RAID 3 plugins and set the correct settings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Skeletons &amp;amp; Animations:&lt;/strong> Restored Missile&amp;rsquo;s Immersive Equipment Display Presets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Mechanics:&lt;/strong> Removed Skyrim Wayshrines - Immersive Fast Travel&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ENB:&lt;/strong> Increased &lt;em>AmbientLightingIntensityInteriorDay&lt;/em> and &lt;em>AmbientLightingIntensityInteriorNight&lt;/em> to &lt;code>1.00&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="outputs-13">Outputs&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regenerated DynDOLOD (and Performance)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-4161-rc-1">Release 4.16.1 RC 1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-02-04&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This update should really be called &lt;em>Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim Release 5.0 RC 4&lt;/em> as it&amp;rsquo;s essentially a complete rebuild of the list based off of &lt;em>The Phoenix Flavour 5.0 RC 4&lt;/em> (which is currently unavailable). The changes in 4.15.5 was the first step towards this goal. The jump to SSE 1.6.640 in 4.16 put me within spitting distance. So, while I know that it&amp;rsquo;s only been a week since that jump, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to go the rest of the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The core of the list hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed. It&amp;rsquo;s still a Simonrim-centered TPF modlist with &lt;em>Survival Mode&lt;/em> and my other choices, but TPF 5.0 has decided to venture off into the previously labeled &amp;ldquo;TPF-X&amp;rdquo; realm of added content. This update follows TPF down that path&amp;hellip; some of the way. You&amp;rsquo;ll find your Vanilla+ experience peppered with &lt;strong>new enemies, new equipment, expanded quests, more crafting options, and more&lt;/strong>. What you won&amp;rsquo;t find are the new worldspaces (areas), followers, or any content that requires the &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1746860/The_Elder_Scrolls_V_Skyrim_Anniversary_Upgrade">Anniversary Upgrade&lt;/a>. If you have that, keep an eye out for TPF&amp;rsquo;s release as it will integrate most of it very well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of changes here. Seriously. The folder count went from ~800 to ~1400. The plugin count is through the roof. Part of that is due to the conflict resolution patches being separated out by section instead of being altogether. This might not be the case in the final release, however there&amp;rsquo;s no reason not to leave it as is with the way ESL plugins work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, a not-so-shortlist of sectional changes can be found below. Please, &lt;em>please&lt;/em> let me know if you run into any issues. I almost guarantee that you will. I want to fix them.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This update is absolutely not save-safe.&lt;/strong> It is likely that future release candidates will be but not guaranteed. If you want to safely continue your character on v4.16.0.1, my advice would be to manually update SimonMagus&amp;rsquo; mods so long as they&amp;rsquo;re labeled save-safe and you&amp;rsquo;ll be in good shape.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-21">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>This changelog is structured differently because of how much has changed. Instead of an itemized list, I&amp;rsquo;ll go through section by section and list some key differences from each, compared to &lt;a href="https://loadorderlibrary.com/lists/the-phoenix-flavour-50-wip">TPF 5.0 RC 4&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Utilities:&lt;/strong> No big changes here. This section consists of pre-requisites for other mods, most of which were already in the list. I did not carry over &lt;em>Optional Quick Start&lt;/em> from TPF 5.0 as I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of the implementation.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Essential Mods:&lt;/strong> Phoenix created her own &lt;em>Weapons &amp;amp; Armor Overhaul&lt;/em> that supercedes &lt;em>WACCF&lt;/em> here, otherwise this section is mostly untouched. Numerous mods from this section have been moved to sections below.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SKSE Plugins:&lt;/strong> The section has been moved higher. There are a number of new plugins, almost all of which are small quality of life fixes such as &lt;em>Stagger Direction Fix&lt;/em> or &lt;em>Alchemy Plus&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fixes &amp;amp; Tweaks:&lt;/strong> Can you believe there are so many things to fix after USSEP? And it&amp;rsquo;s all in here. Again, not going to get into the weeds over things that are small bug fixes. &amp;ldquo;It just works.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Controls &amp;amp; Camera:&lt;/strong> This section also moved upwards. &lt;em>Sprint Swimming&lt;/em> is the newest addition here, otherwise it&amp;rsquo;s the same as before. I&amp;rsquo;ve switched away from the &lt;em>EasyEase Preset&lt;/em> to &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/82481">SmoothCam Vanilla Enhanced 2&lt;/a> with very minor changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Interface:&lt;/strong> I kept &lt;em>Toggle Compass Hotkey&lt;/em> over &lt;em>Ultimate Immersion Toggle&lt;/em>. I&amp;rsquo;ve also reverted back to regular &lt;em>SkyUI&lt;/em> as the default interface. This allows for more consistency with &lt;em>CoMAP&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Constructible Object Custom Keyword System&lt;/em>, both new additions in this update. There is an optional &lt;em>Nordic UI&lt;/em> section for those who still want the old look but it&amp;rsquo;s not at the same level of consistency. Widescreen support is still present for 21x9 monitors (&lt;em>SkyUI&lt;/em> only; for other ratios or &lt;em>Nordic UI&lt;/em> support you have to install it on your own). I&amp;rsquo;ve tried my best to make sure both UI looks work with the same configuration file.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Graphic Baseline:&lt;/strong> Not much to say here. The Performance Profile does not utilize &lt;em>High Poly Project&lt;/em> otherwise it&amp;rsquo;s not an exciting section to talk about. To look at is a different story.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mesh Improvements:&lt;/strong> Likewise, TPF 5.0 just makes things look prettier here and I saw no reason to change these choices.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Weather &amp;amp; Lighting:&lt;/strong> This is the first major departure from TPF 5.0. I&amp;rsquo;ve switched &lt;em>Obsidian Weathers&lt;/em> out for &lt;em>RAID Weathers&lt;/em> but left everything else the same. Previous versions of the list did not have reliable stealth mechanics which was a sore spot given the reduced HUD. By switching back to &lt;em>RAID&lt;/em> and &lt;em>RAID Weathers&lt;/em> sneaking around is tough but fair, the way I intended.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fire &amp;amp; Visual FX:&lt;/strong> I&amp;rsquo;ve added &lt;em>R.A.S.S. - Rain Ash and Snow Shaders&lt;/em> on top of TPF 5.0. I&amp;rsquo;ve also kept all of my previous additions such as &lt;em>Frozen Electrocuted Combusion&lt;/em>. I&amp;rsquo;m borderline on R.A.S.S. so please let me know what you think.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> I kept pretty much everything here, the most noticeable of which was &lt;em>Enhanced Landscapes&lt;/em> to make exploring a bit more memorable. Then I added a bunch of MystiriousDawn&amp;rsquo;s new HD Parallax textures.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Trees, Grass, &amp;amp; Plants:&lt;/strong> Essentially the same as TPF 5.0, which is the same as TPF 4.0 with the addition of &lt;em>Happy Little Trees&lt;/em> and some of the &lt;em>Cathedral - 3D&lt;/em> plants.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Appearance:&lt;/strong> Unchanged as this section was adopted by SSS in earlier versions.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Architecture:&lt;/strong> No real changes from TPF 5.0 aside from &lt;em>Rally&amp;rsquo;s Market Stalls&lt;/em>. Things look good here.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Misc Structures:&lt;/strong> Again, no real changes. For the most part I&amp;rsquo;ve always agree with Phoenix&amp;rsquo;s visuals and that hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed.&lt;em>Daedric Shrines&lt;/em> was put here as the only addition from a later section of the list.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Interiors:&lt;/strong> Nothing to say here that hasn&amp;rsquo;t already been said.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Dungeons:&lt;/strong> The retexture section of the changelog is quite boring, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Clutter:&lt;/strong> I should note that TPF 5.0 switched from the desaturated version of &lt;em>Book Covers Skyrim&lt;/em> to the saturated version. All the books in the game will be brighter than before.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Valuables:&lt;/strong> For some reason &lt;em>Security Overhaul SKSE&lt;/em> was moved here. Otherwise, nothing interesting to note.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Food &amp;amp; Ingredients:&lt;/strong> I&amp;rsquo;ve added &lt;em>Garlic - A Garlic Mod&lt;/em> to the section. It came out after the last release candidate but I feel that Phoenix would&amp;rsquo;ve loved it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Apparel &amp;amp; Weapons:&lt;/strong> Unchanged from TPF 5.0 as it was already incorporated into SSS awhile back.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Creatures:&lt;/strong> Unchanged from TPF 5.0.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Gameplay Overhauls:&lt;/strong> The SimonRim core of TPF remains untouched.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Balance &amp;amp; Crafting:&lt;/strong> TPF 5.0 expands the crafting a good amount and SSS followed it all the way down that road. The biggest thing to note here is that TPF 5.0 modifies the Smithing tree along with its other changes. &lt;em>Honed Metal&lt;/em> has not been adjusted to compensate so there may be some weirdness with the blacksmith services.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Non-Player Characters:&lt;/strong> Children get more clothes with &lt;em>Prince and the Pauper&lt;/em> returning to the list. Vigilants as well. Otherwise, this is a mostly unchanged section that introduces a few small tweaks to the list.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> TPF 5.0 fleshes this section out even more with a lot of minor tweaks. &lt;em>At Your Own Pace&lt;/em> has been added for the main quest and the College of Winterhold. The other factions have gotten some attention as well to improve their quest pacing.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounters:&lt;/strong> Nothing really changed here. Like Gameplay Overhauls, the core of the list hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Miscellaneous:&lt;/strong> Phoenix added a number of small mods to this section such as &lt;em>Jarrin Root for Babette&lt;/em>. &lt;em>Left Hand Rings&lt;/em> is included so that the Bond of Matrimony can be worn without taking up a valuable enchantment slot. One that I didn&amp;rsquo;t take was &lt;em>Another Redbelly Mine Mod&lt;/em> because, put frankly, I don&amp;rsquo;t care all too much about the dialogue conflict here. It&amp;rsquo;s an easy mine to enter, let&amp;rsquo;s leave it as an iron mine like all the other easy mines to enter.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Skeleton &amp;amp; Animations:&lt;/strong> I left this mostly unchanged which is a departure from TPF 5.0 because it added &lt;em>Movement Behavior Overhaul&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Animated Armoury&lt;/em>. The former was glitchy for me and I didn&amp;rsquo;t think the latter fit the current vision of the list and there are no added weapon types here, so I dropped them. &lt;em>Precision&lt;/em> returns, however, as it was not the true source of the previous issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sound FX:&lt;/strong> I know less about sound than I do visuals. This section was left as is.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Creation Club:&lt;/strong> This list only uses the 4 free Creations that came with Anniversary Edition so the others have been removed, drastically slimming down the next few sections.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Creation Club Base:&lt;/strong> I did my best to preserve what could be used here with the above limitation which wasn&amp;rsquo;t much. In addition, previous enhancements to &lt;em>Saints and Seducers&lt;/em>, &lt;em>Survival Mode&lt;/em>, and &lt;em>Fishing&lt;/em> were moved here.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Creation Club Assets:&lt;/strong> Unchanged from TPF 5.0 aside from the aforementioend trim.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Creation Club Patches:&lt;/strong> Included everything necessary for the utilized Creations.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Creation Club Integreation:&lt;/strong> This has been reduced to Phoenix&amp;rsquo;s patches and &lt;em>Mysticism - Survival Spells Addon&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Beyond Skyrim Bruma, Wyrmstooth, City Overhauls, Other Locations, Interior Overhauls, and New Player Homes:&lt;/strong> Not included in SSS.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>New &amp;amp; Expanded Quests:&lt;/strong> Some of these were introduced in the last update. Most, actually. I did not add &lt;em>Cheesemod for EVERYONE&lt;/em> and &lt;em>New Treasure Hunt&lt;/em>, however.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>New Mechanics:&lt;/strong> &lt;em>Hand to Hand&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Pilgrim&lt;/em>, among others, were already in the list. I&amp;rsquo;ve added &lt;em>Skyrim Wayshrines&lt;/em> and &lt;em>BA Bard Songs&lt;/em>. &lt;em>Wayshrines&lt;/em> provides another alternative to fast traveling but you&amp;rsquo;ll incur fatigue in exchange for the transmission. Left out were some CC-dependent mechanics, &lt;em>Take A Peek&lt;/em>, &lt;em>Skyrim&amp;rsquo;s Got Talent&lt;/em>, and &lt;em>Skyrim&amp;rsquo;s Paraglider&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>New Items:&lt;/strong> A lot. I mean, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of new, lore friendly gear to outfit yourself with here. Before it was just &lt;em>Royal Armory&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Ancient Nord Stahlrim&lt;/em>. Now it&amp;rsquo;s a proper section.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>New Creatures:&lt;/strong> This was called &amp;ldquo;New NPCs &amp;amp; Creatures&amp;rdquo; in TPF 5.0 but I didn&amp;rsquo;t carry over a single NPC so just ignore that first part. You still get plenty of new monsters to fight and a handful more alchemical ingredients to play around with from this section.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>New Animations:&lt;/strong> In addition to the previous animations I&amp;rsquo;ve added to the list, TPF 5.0 adds almost all of Verolevi&amp;rsquo;s animations (with &lt;em>Conditional Armor Type Animations&lt;/em>) to the game. In action all of these new animations looked nice and made sense, so I left them in.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>New Music:&lt;/strong> Nothing has changed here.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Content Integration:&lt;/strong> Without certain CC mods the &lt;em>Crossbow Integration&lt;/em> part of this section got neutered but I kept what I could. You should also see more Bonemold and Chitin and merchants will have more gear from across Tamriel even if you can&amp;rsquo;t go there yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Lux, Lux Orbis, &amp;amp; Lux Via:&lt;/strong> These mods are so big they need their own section. I&amp;rsquo;ve included everything that was necessary given the other choices in the modlist.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-20">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated Crash Logger to 1.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Spell Perk Item Distributor to 6.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Cathedral Weathers and Seasons - Unofficial Update to 2.40&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Particle Patch for ENB to 1.2.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Assorted Mesh Fixes to 0.78&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Aetherius - A Race Overhaul to 2.10.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mundus - A Standing Stone Overhaul to 1.9.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Snowy Surfaces Sound Collision and Aesthetics to 1.6.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Hand to Hand - An Adamant Addon to 1.4.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPC Animation Remix to 1.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="outputs-14">Outputs&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regenerated everything&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-41601">Release 4.16.0.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-01-27&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is mostly a hotfix to deal with some bugs that have been reported. One in particular was considered a critical bug which meant this update goes out sooner rather than later. Below is a list of the issues addressed:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Adjusted Scrambled Bugs settings so that all of Simonrim&amp;rsquo;s perks and effects should act as the author intended.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dragons no longer magically obtain a smaller hitbox vs. projectiles, allowing archers and mages to actually kill them again.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Innkeepers should properly give you a bounty letter when asked. If you decline the quest it won&amp;rsquo;t be offered again immediately.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Windhelm bridge should have its proper textures.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Unique weaponry should have all of their correct meshes/textures and a few stats have been tweaked to match Phoenix&amp;rsquo;s intent.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>A new save is not required. You will receive a warning about &lt;code>Precision.esp&lt;/code> that can be ignored.&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;h4 id="changes-22">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Architecture:&lt;/strong> Added Windhelm Fence 3D&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Gameplay Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Removed Precision&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Gameplay Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Removed Precision Creatures&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> Moved Headhunter - Bounties Redone to Miscellaneous&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Skeleton &amp;amp; Animations:&lt;/strong> Removed Nemesis Creature Behaviour Compatibility&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Configuration:&lt;/strong> Lowered SkillFormulaCaps to 100 (this won&amp;rsquo;t change much of anything as Simonrim bonuses tend not to give raw skill boosts, I&amp;rsquo;m just cleaning up the file)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Configuration:&lt;/strong> Adjusted Scrambled Bugs settings to match Simon&amp;rsquo;s suggestions for his gameplay suite&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-21">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated NVIDIA Reflex Support to 1.1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dwemer Gates Don&amp;rsquo;t Reset to 1.3.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Papyrus Tweaks to 4.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Rally&amp;rsquo;s Nord War Horns to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Pilgrim - A Religion Overhaul to 1.1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Honed Metal Revoiced to 1.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Choice Is Yours to 2.7&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="outputs-15">Outputs&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regenerated Left Hand Meshes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated Nemesis&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h2 id="release-4160">Release 4.16.0&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2023-01-23&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll be clear: &lt;strong>this is a new chapter for Slidikins&amp;rsquo; Strenuous Skyrim.&lt;/strong> I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to rip off the proverbial band-aid and bring the list up to date to Skyrim SE 1.6.640. With that comes a handful of changes and a lot of new opportunities. Since a new game would&amp;rsquo;ve been required anyway, I also took the liberty of cramming in a ton of mods that also would&amp;rsquo;ve meant starting fresh. The end result is this monster of a changelog that I promise is totally the same SSS you&amp;rsquo;ve come to enjoy. Let&amp;rsquo;s get into it!&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mod-substitutions">Mod Substitutions&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Not every SKSE plugin made the jump to 1.6.640. Most of them have been replaced with something comparable, such as &lt;em>PlayerPayCrimeGold Tweak&lt;/em> filling in for &lt;em>No Crime Teleport&lt;/em>. In two cases a substitute didn&amp;rsquo;t exist (such as &lt;em>SSE Gameplay Tweaks&lt;/em>). It&amp;rsquo;s unfortunate but the features lost weren&amp;rsquo;t vital to the list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Outside of SKSE plugins there were a few more changes. wSkeever&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Simplicity of Snow&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Shaders of Solstheim&lt;/em> took over for &lt;em>Better Dynamic Snow/Ash&lt;/em>. &lt;em>The Dragon Cult&lt;/em> replaced &lt;em>Haugbui&lt;/em> which was a fine mod but not the best fit in comparison. You&amp;rsquo;ll see a few others like these in the details below, such as the Lux series that&amp;rsquo;s taken over the lighting.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="visual-changes">Visual Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Since building the list off of TPF the philosophy has mostly been &amp;ldquo;focus on gameplay mods, let TPF handle the visuals.&amp;rdquo; That has changed&amp;hellip; slightly. I&amp;rsquo;ve been stepping out of that box a bit to include things such as MystiriousDawn&amp;rsquo;s parallax landscape textures, &lt;em>Seasons of Skyrim&lt;/em>, and borrowing from TPF 5.0&amp;rsquo;s unreleased modlist. (Yes, that means ENB Complex Parallax is enabled in the regular profile.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even so, I don&amp;rsquo;t like focusing on visuals and don&amp;rsquo;t think this will lead to drastic changes in how the game looks. Expect to find more nuggets of visual changes here and there in future updates. &lt;em>Lux&lt;/em> (and &lt;em>Lux Via&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Lux Orbis&lt;/em>) are the latest mods grabbed from TPF 5.0. Lighting will be noticeably different and stealth mechanics have changed slightly because of it. It&amp;rsquo;ll probably be too easy still, but it&amp;rsquo;s a work in progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="quest-expansions">Quest Expansions&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>JaySerpa&amp;rsquo;s mods have always been on the cusp of making it into the list. I love pretty much all of their ideas but I have to ask myself, &amp;ldquo;Does this fit Vanilla+?&amp;rdquo; at every release. Well, the needle has moved to &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo; for a lot of them, specifically the quest expansions. Alongside those you&amp;rsquo;ll find other mods that enhance the existing quests of the game such as &lt;em>Headhunter&lt;/em>, &lt;em>Destination Weddings&lt;/em>, and &lt;em>Extended Cut - Saints &amp;amp; Seducers&lt;/em>. That&amp;rsquo;s right, &lt;em>Saints &amp;amp; Seducers&lt;/em> is now part of the list!&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="branching-further">Branching Further&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>With these and other changes, SSS has distanced itself from TPF that much more. It&amp;rsquo;s still a TPF fork at its core but it&amp;rsquo;s become impossible to convert TPF 4.16 to SSS 4.16 without a digital scalpel and a ton of time. As such, SSS&amp;rsquo; manual guide has been retired and installation is available only through Wabbajack. This will allow me to pile in some smaller mods (such as wSkeever&amp;rsquo;s various fixes) without making installation more tedious, so expect to see these branches diverge even further as TPF 5.0 develops.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t done justice to all of the changes in 4.16. Take a peek at the details below for a full list. There are some real gems in there.&lt;/p>
&lt;details>
&lt;p>Updated for &lt;a href="https://github.com/Codygits/TPF-Updates/releases/tag/4.16.0">TPF 4.16.0&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="changes-23">Changes&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Creation Club Content:&lt;/strong> Added Saints and Seducers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Essential Mods:&lt;/strong> Removed .NET Script Framework&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Essential Mods:&lt;/strong> Added Crash Logger&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed Dlizzio&amp;rsquo;s Mesh Fixes - Assorted Mesh Fixes Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fixes:&lt;/strong> Removed Skyrim Particle Patch for ENB - Assorted Mesh Fixes - Solitude Mesh Fixes Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fixes:&lt;/strong> Added Animation Queue Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fixes:&lt;/strong> Added Beard Mask Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fixes:&lt;/strong> Added Enchantable Special Item Fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fixes:&lt;/strong> Added Sound Fix for Large Sector Drives&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Tweaks:&lt;/strong> Removed SSE Gameplay Tweaks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Tweaks:&lt;/strong> Removed No Crime Teleport&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Tweaks:&lt;/strong> Added PlayerPayCrimeGold Tweak&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Tweaks:&lt;/strong> Added Whiterun Watchtower Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Start Broken&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Tweaks:&lt;/strong> Added Wade in Water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Tweaks:&lt;/strong> Added Wade in Water Redone&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Interface:&lt;/strong> Added HD Local Map&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Interface:&lt;/strong> Added Show Player in Menus&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Interface:&lt;/strong> Adjusted positioning of Ammo Widget and Oxygen Meter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Graphics Baseline:&lt;/strong> Removed SMIM - Assorted Mesh Fixes Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Graphics Baseline:&lt;/strong> Added Far Object LOD Improvement Project&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seasons of Skyrim:&lt;/strong> Added EC Vanilla Tweaks - Winter Unending&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Weather:&lt;/strong> Added Cathedral Weathers and Seasons - Unofficial Update&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Weather:&lt;/strong> Added Rain Extinguishes Fires&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lighting:&lt;/strong> Removed Lanterns of Skyrim II&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lighting:&lt;/strong> Removed Luminosity Lighting Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lighting:&lt;/strong> Added Lux&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lighting:&lt;/strong> Added Lux Orbis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Removed Better Dynamic Snow&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Removed Better Dynamic Ash&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Removed Point the Way&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Removed MystiriousDawn&amp;rsquo;s HD Skyrim Overhaul - Landscape Textures 2K&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Added Simplicity of Snow&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Added Shaders of Solstheim - Ash and Moss&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Added Lux Via&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Added eFPS - Lux Via Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Added Tundra - HD Texture Replacer with Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Added Dirt - HD Texture Replacer with Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Added River Stone - HD Texture Replacer with Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Added Snow - HD Texture Replacer with Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Added Pine Forest - HD Texture Replacer with Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Added Coast and Marsh - HD Texture Replacer with Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Added Fall Forest - HD Texture Replacer with Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Added Field Grass - HD Texture Replacer with Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Added Volcanic Tundra - HD Texture Replacer with Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Landscape:&lt;/strong> Added Reach - HD Texture Replacer with Parallax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Architecture:&lt;/strong> Added Skyrim Objects SMIMed - Warmaiden&amp;rsquo;s Holes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Architecture:&lt;/strong> Added Whiterun Cobblestone - HD Texture Replacer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Architecture:&lt;/strong> Added Windhelm Bridge Stairs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Architecture:&lt;/strong> Added Simplicity of Settlements - Dragon Bridge&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Clutter:&lt;/strong> Removed Yee Haaaa Horse Saddle Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Clutter:&lt;/strong> Removed Imperial Saddle Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Clutter:&lt;/strong> Removed Shadowmere Saddle Retexture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Food &amp;amp; Ingredients:&lt;/strong> Added Garlic - A Garlic Mod&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Apparel &amp;amp; Weapons:&lt;/strong> Added Dynamic Armor Variants&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Apparel &amp;amp; Weapons:&lt;/strong> Added Dynamic Lowered Hoods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Creatures:&lt;/strong> Removed Dawnguard Rewritten - Arvak&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Creatures:&lt;/strong> Added zzjay&amp;rsquo;s Horse Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Creatures:&lt;/strong> Added Slightly Better - Arvak&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Creatures:&lt;/strong> Added Arvak Burning Hooves Restored&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Gameplay Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Removed Simple Werewolf Favourite Howls Menu&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Gameplay Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Removed More Expensive Transmute for Mysticism&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Gameplay Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Added Mysticism - Survival Spells Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Gameplay Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Added Aetherius - Starting Spells Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Gameplay Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Added Saints and Seducers - Mysticism Rebalance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Gameplay Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Added Extended Cut Saints and Seducers - Mysticism Rebalance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Gameplay Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Added Precision Creatures&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Gameplay Overhauls:&lt;/strong> Added Zim&amp;rsquo;s Trainers Expansion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Loot &amp;amp; Crafting:&lt;/strong> Removed Bounties Are Worthwhile - Leveled Bounty Rewards&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Loot &amp;amp; Crafting:&lt;/strong> Added Oblivion - An Atronach Forge Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Loot &amp;amp; Crafting:&lt;/strong> Added Oblivion - Book Covers Skyrim Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Non Player Characters:&lt;/strong> Added Forsworn and Thalmor Lines Expansion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Non Player Characters:&lt;/strong> Added Carriages and Stables Dialogue Bundle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Non Player Characters:&lt;/strong> Added Carriages and Stables Dialogue Bundle - CFTO Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Assorted Plugins:&lt;/strong> Removed Sales Overflow Solved for real this time&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> Removed The Paarthurnax Resolution&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> Removed Reasonable Quest Rewards - Bounties Are Worthwhile Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> Added Paarthurnax - Quest Expansion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> Added Improved College Entry - Questline Tweaks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> Added Nilheim - Misc Quest Expansion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> Added Caught Red Handed - Quest Expansion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> Added House of Horrors - Quest Expansion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> Added The Only Cure - Quest Expansion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> Added The Whispering Door - Quest Expansion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> Added Skyrim Extended Cut - Saints and Seducers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> Added Missives are in Skyrim&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> Added Headhunter - Bounties Redone&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> Added Destination Weddings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> Added Destination Weddings - Compatibility Patches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> Added Fishing - Reduced Cut&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Vanilla Quests:&lt;/strong> Added Streamlined Fishing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounters:&lt;/strong> Removed Haugbui - A Draugr Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounters:&lt;/strong> Removed Haugbui - Better-Shaped Weapons Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounters:&lt;/strong> Removed Haugbui - SimonRim Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounters:&lt;/strong> Removed Haugbui - CC Fishing Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounters:&lt;/strong> Removed Haugbui - WACCF Patch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounters:&lt;/strong> Added Blade and Blunt - Sneak Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounters:&lt;/strong> Added Cannibal Draugr on Solstheim&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounters:&lt;/strong> Added The Dragon Cult - A Draugr Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounters:&lt;/strong> Added Resistances and Weaknesses - NPC Armaments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounters:&lt;/strong> Added Dragon War - Variants&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Combat &amp;amp; Encounters:&lt;/strong> Added Seeking Out Sneaks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Miscellaneou:&lt;/strong> Removed Miscellaneous Tweaks Collection - No Starting Spells&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Miscellaneous:&lt;/strong> Removed Iron Dusk&amp;rsquo;s Laboratory - Saddlebags&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Miscellaneous:&lt;/strong> Added Simplest Horses&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Assorted Plugins:&lt;/strong> Removed Better Stealing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Assorted Plugins:&lt;/strong> Removed Uninterrupted Invisibility&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Assorted Plugins:&lt;/strong> Removed Uninterrupted Ethereal Form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Assorted Plugins:&lt;/strong> Removed Crafting Skill Leveling Overhaul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Assorted Plugins:&lt;/strong> Removed Fish Anywhere With Water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Assorted Plugins:&lt;/strong> Added Mum&amp;rsquo;s the Word&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Assorted Plugins:&lt;/strong> Added Enhanced Invisibility&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Assorted Plugins:&lt;/strong> Added Missile&amp;rsquo;s Immersive Equipment Display Presets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Assorted Plugins:&lt;/strong> Added Missile&amp;rsquo;s Immersive Equipment Display Presets - Better Head Hunter Displays While Mounted&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Sound FX:&lt;/strong> Added Acoustic Space Improvement Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Skeletons &amp;amp; Animations:&lt;/strong> Removed Read the Room&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Skeletons &amp;amp; Animations:&lt;/strong> Added Nemesis Creature Behaviour Compatibility&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Skeleton &amp;amp; Animations:&lt;/strong> Added Faster Horse Dismount&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Skeleton &amp;amp; Animations:&lt;/strong> Added Take a Seat&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Controls &amp;amp; Camera:&lt;/strong> Removed Alternate Conversation Camera Plus&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Controls &amp;amp; Camera:&lt;/strong> Added Improved Alternate Conversation Camera&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Utilities:&lt;/strong> Added ENB Helper Plus&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Added weights to currency added by C.O.I.N. to match Septim weights&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Added FallowstoneCaveWorldEnd &lt;code>000204C7&lt;/code> overwrite for Shadows of Sunlight.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Removed a ton of old records that have been changed by either Mysticism, AOS, or both.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Updated FVS_VelehkHeart values to match earlier Apothecary update&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Adjusted values in Zim&amp;rsquo;s Trainers Expansion to prevent exploits&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution:&lt;/strong> Adjusted Sneak gamesettings in a number of ways&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution (Creation Club):&lt;/strong> Removed MAG_flameCloak &lt;code>0003AE9F&lt;/code> as it&amp;rsquo;s covered in Mysticism - Survival Spells Addon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution (Creation Club):&lt;/strong> Removed DLC2FoodHorkerAshYamStew &lt;code>0403CD5B&lt;/code> to let the new Survival Mode Improved patch do its job&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution (Creation Club):&lt;/strong> Patched two SECSS ingredients with Apothecary&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conflict Resolution (Creation Club):&lt;/strong> Removed edits to the Steed Stone and Extra Pockets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>FaceGen:&lt;/strong> Removed extraneous data from TPF&amp;rsquo;s FaceGen data (it&amp;rsquo;s much smaller now!)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="updates-22">Updates&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Updated xLODGEN to 97&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD to 3.00 Alpha-111&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Synthesis to 0.25.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated SSE NIF Optimizer to 3.2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated numerous SKSE Plugins to the respective AE version
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Disabled Keyboard Shortcuts Fix until it&amp;rsquo;s compatible&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Disabled NVIDIA Reflex Support until it&amp;rsquo;s compatible&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Disabled Don&amp;rsquo;t Stay in the Water until it&amp;rsquo;s compatible&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Disabled Wash That Blood Off 2 until it&amp;rsquo;s compatible&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Address Library for SKSE Plugins to 8.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated SSE Engine Fixes to 6.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Weapons Armor Clothing and Clutter Fixes to 2.9.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Particle Patch for ENB to 1.2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyrim Landscape and Water Fixes to 7.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Assorted Mesh Fixes to 0.77.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Bug Fixes SSE to 8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Actor Limit Fix to 7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Equip Enchantment Fix to 1.3.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mfg Fix to 1.6.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ENB Light Inventory Fix to 1.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Shadow Boost to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Shadow Diffusion (now Soft Shadows) to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Papyrus Tweaks to 3.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Reading is Good to 1.1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Fix Note Icon for SkyUI to 1.2.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated moreHUD to 5.2.2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Nordic UI - Miscellaneous Patches to 1.8.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Contextual Crosshair to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated A Clear Map of Skyrim and Other Worlds to 4.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Forget Spell to 1.2.5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated DynDOLOD Resources to 3.00 Alpha-30&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simple Activate SKSE to 1.4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Far Object LOD Improvement Project to 1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Frozen Electrocuted Combustion to 5.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Realistic Water Two to 5.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated FYX - Water Splash to 1.0.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Skyrim Flora Overhaul - Plant Textures to 2.73b&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Iconic Statues 4K to 1.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Mysticism - A Magic Overhaul to 2.2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Adamant - A Perk Overhaul to 5.7.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Adamant - Hand to Hand Addon to 1.3.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Aetherius - A Race Overhaul to 2.9.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Scion - A Vampire Overhaul to 2.1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Manbeast - A Werewofl Overhaul to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Forceful Tongue - Shouts Overhaul to 3.0.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Pilgrim - A Religion Overhaul to 1.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Survival Mode Improved to 1.0.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Precision to 2.0.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Armor and Clothing Extension to 1.5.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Ancient Nord Stalhrim to 1.2.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Trade and Barter - Adamant Patch with a hotfix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Armor and Clothing Extension - Spell Perk Item Distributor Patch to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simple Degradation - NPC Tempering to 1.4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated C.O.I.N. - Coins of Interesting Natures to 2.1.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Bandit Lines Expansion to 1.06&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPCs Wear Amulets of Mara to 2.02&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Civil War Lines Expansion to 1.05&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated The Choice is Yours to 2.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Encounter Zones Unlocked to 1.5.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Resistances and Weaknesses to 1.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Enchantments and Potions Work for NPCs to 1.0.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated NPCs Learn Skills and Spells to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Blade and Blunt - A Combat Overhaul to 2.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Archery Rebalance (formerly Quintessential Quivers) to 1.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Horse Stamina HUD to 1.0.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Unequip Quiver to 2.1.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Audio Overhaul for Skyrim to 4.0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Regional Sounds Expansion to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Reverb Interior Sounds Expansion to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Simple Dual Sheath to 1.5.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Sleeping Expanded to 1.22&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Dynamic Animation Replacer to 1.1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Auto Input Switch to 1.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Classic Sprinting Redone to 2.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Better Jumping to 1.8.6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Better Third Person Selection to 0.5.8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated JContainers to 4.2.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated powerofthree&amp;rsquo;s Papyrus Extender to 5.4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated FileAccess Interface for Skyrim SE to 1.4.1b&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ConsoleUtils to 1.4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ENB Helper to 2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Spell Perk Item Distributor to 6.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Console Commands Extender to 1.11&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Keyword Item Distributor to 2.2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Base Object Swapper to 2.5.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Sound Record Distributor to 1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated ENBSeries to v0.384&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updated Blade and Blunt - Vanilla Difficulty Modifiers to 2.0&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="outputs-16">Outputs&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regenerated Left Hand Meshes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated Nemesis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated xLODGEN&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated TexGen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerated DynDOLOD (and Performance)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="previous-changes-dating-back-release-43-can-be-found-herehttpsgithubcomamigoliathslidikins-strenuous-skyrimblobmainchangelogmd">Previous changes dating back Release 4.3 can be found &lt;a href="https://github.com/Amigoliath/Slidikins-Strenuous-Skyrim/blob/main/Changelog.md">here&lt;/a>&lt;/h4></description></item><item><title>Skyrim-Se: Example Builds</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sss/builds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/skyrim-se/sss/builds/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Below are a list of character builds I&amp;rsquo;ve personally created and use in the list. They aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily the most &lt;em>optimized&lt;/em> builds, but they are &lt;em>viable&lt;/em> and &lt;em>varied&lt;/em> so I still get to have a satisfying amount of role-play. Please use them for inspiration or guidance in creating your own characters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In each build you&amp;rsquo;ll find perk builds and recommendations (typically 3) for standing stones, deity worship, and enchantment choices. I&amp;rsquo;ve also included shortlists of key spells and shouts for each build. I have omitted specific equipment recommendations and alchemical combinations for now. Those may come in future updates.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note:&lt;/strong> While these are named after classes from earlier Elder Scrolls games, the names were just a starting concept. The end result tends to be slightly different as I try to incorporate Combat, Magic, and Stealth elements into every build for versatility.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>