<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Phoenix Flavour – Additional Modules</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/</link><description>Recent content in Additional Modules on The Phoenix Flavour</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bg: Automating MCMs</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/automating-mcms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/automating-mcms/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers how to change the default settings in a Mod Configuration Menu to avoid having to reconfigure them in every new save.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/mo2/">Mod Organizer 2&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/creation-kit/">Creation Kit&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/recommended-mods/skyui/">SkyUI and Source 5.1 + 5.2&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="automating-mcms">Automating MCMs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the following, I will explain how to modify a mod directly to change its default MCM options using the example of &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/2182">Realistic Water Two&lt;/a> (RW2).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The mod has several option features which can be toggled in the MCM, including &lt;em>ripples&lt;/em> and &lt;em>waves&lt;/em>. When I am using &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/71126">GKB Waves Reborn&lt;/a>, the RW2 waves features can be disable. When I am &lt;u>not&lt;/u> using &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/72115">Splashes of Storms&lt;/a>, I might as well enable RW2&amp;rsquo;s ripples on water.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="modifying-globals">Modifying Globals&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>MCMs consist of a quest (defined in a plugin) and a script which can be linked to other records, such as &lt;em>globals&lt;/em> or &lt;em>references&lt;/em>. If a setting is controlled via a global, it is very easy to modify in the plugin:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/automating-mcms/change-global.png" alt="RW2 Change Global">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the &lt;strong>Realistic Water Two - MCM Preset.esp&lt;/strong> plugin loaded, the &lt;em>ripples&lt;/em> feature will now be &lt;em>enabled&lt;/em> by default in the RW2 MCM.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="modifying-script-source">Modifying Script Source&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Scripts can only be modified in their source files which must be recompiled in the Creation Kit. Fortunately, &lt;strong>Realistic Water Two&lt;/strong> and many other mods containing scripts ship with the source files included (or they are available for download as optional files).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="editing-source-files">Editing Source Files&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As usual, I recommend creating &lt;em>copies&lt;/em> as opposed to modifying a mod directly.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Create a new folder under &lt;code>\Mod Organizer 2\mods\&lt;/code> and name it &lt;strong>Realistic Water Two - MCM Settings&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Inside, create the &lt;code>\Scripts\Source\&lt;/code> folder structure.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Copy the &lt;code>\Source\Scripts\RealisticWaterTwoMCM.psc&lt;/code> from RW2 into the new &lt;strong>Source&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Open the new copy of &lt;strong>RealisticWaterTwoMCM.psc&lt;/strong> in a text editor such as Notepad++ (I recommend setting the app as the default for .PSC files).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Scroll down to &lt;strong>Line 40&lt;/strong> and change the following:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>bool SkyrimWaves = false
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Save your change and close the file.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>After recompiling the script, the &lt;em>waves&lt;/em> feature will be disabled by default.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="skyui-source">SkyUI Source&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When recompiling an MCM script, you need to have the SkyUI source files that were used when the MCM was originally made. This may be 5.2, 5.1, or an even older version. Generally, I would try 5.2 first. If the version is wrong, the Creation Kit log will complain about it:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/automating-mcms/wrong-skyui-source.png" alt="Wrong SkyUI Source">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="recompiling-script">Recompiling Script&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Before you recompile the script, check the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The &lt;strong>Creation Kit - Source&lt;/strong> should be &lt;u>enabled&lt;/u>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The &lt;strong>SkyUI - Source&lt;/strong> file set should be &lt;u>enabled&lt;/u> (5.1 for RW2).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The mod you are recompiling the script for should be &lt;u>disabled&lt;/u>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
The third step ensures that the Creation Kit creates a new copy of the script instead of overwriting the original.
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run the &lt;strong>Creation Kit&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go to &lt;strong>Gameplay&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Compile Papyrus Script&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/automating-mcms/ck-compile-script.png" alt="CK Compile Script">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will be greeted by a window with a list of all present script source files.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Press &lt;strong>R&lt;/strong> to quickly jump to scripts starting with that letter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check the &lt;strong>RealisticWaterTwoMCM.psc&lt;/strong> and click &lt;strong>Compile&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/automating-mcms/compile-rw2-script.png" alt="Compile RW2 Script">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The window will auto-close if the script was compiled successfully. Also check the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/automating-mcms/script-no-errors.png">log window&lt;/a> which should not contain any errors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Close the Creation Kit.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="finalisation">Finalisation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Any new plugins and/or recompiled scripts will be caught by Mod Organizer 2 in the &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>. Create &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/automating-mcms/rw2-mcm-preset.png">a new mod&lt;/a> to store the file(s). Place it below the original mod and activate it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remember to disable the CK and SkyUI source files unless you have other MCM scripts to recompile.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bg: Clean Install</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/clean-install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/clean-install/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers how to perform a clean install of Skyrim SE, removing all traces of a previous installation of Skyrim and reinstalling the game in a suitable directory.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> None&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="uninstalling-skyrim">Uninstalling Skyrim&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you currently have Skyrim installed, find the game in your Steam Library.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Right-click it and select &lt;strong>Manage&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Uninstall&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Uninstall&lt;/strong> again in the message box that follows to confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/uninstall-skyrim.png" alt="Uninstall Skyrim">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="creation-kit">Creation Kit&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you had the &lt;strong>Creation Kit&lt;/strong> for Skyrim SE installed through Steam, uninstall it in the same way.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="mod-files">Mod Files&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
Skip this step if you never modded Skyrim before.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Steam will uninstall all vanilla files, but it will not touch mods. Any leftover files added by mods must be deleted manually.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Navigate to where the game was installed which is likely:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>C:\Program Files x86\Steam\steamapps\common\&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If there is still a &lt;strong>Skyrim Special Edition&lt;/strong> folder in this location, delete it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="documents-folder">Documents Folder&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
Skip this step if you never ran Skyrim SE on this PC before (folder would not exist).
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Next, we will take a look at the &lt;strong>Documents&lt;/strong> folder. Navigate to:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>C:\Users\&amp;lt;Your User Name&amp;gt;\Documents\My Games\Skyrim Special Edition\&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This directory may contain multiple files and folders:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The &lt;strong>Skyrim.ini&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>SkyrimPrefs.ini&lt;/strong> are the game’s primary configuration files.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There may also be a &lt;strong>saves&lt;/strong> folder which, you guessed it, contains your save games.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lastly, the Documents folder may also include mod-generated files such as logs.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Warning:&lt;/strong> If you have save files that you want to keep, back them up now.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Delete the entire Skyrim Special Edition folder.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The folder and INI files will be regenerated upon launching the game after the reinstallation.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-success" role="alert">
And that is all. Skyrim SE is now completely removed from your system.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="game-language">Game Language&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Skyrim supports a bunch of different languages natively, but mods do not. Since many mods also do not require translations in the first place and some of the ones that do have third-party translations available, it is theoretically possible to play modded in Skyrim in a language other than English.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, it would complicate your setup immensely. Translations, where available, may be outdated or incomplete. They may not cover voice acting. They may require editing of dozens of texture templates in Photoshop. They may not exist for some of your mods at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Translating any records (and certain textures!) untouched by existing patches plus fixing conflicts between translations and mods will add a hefty amount of work on top of everything else. &lt;strong>I do not recommend it, especially not for a beginner.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>An English-language installation of Skyrim is &lt;u>mandatory&lt;/u> for this guide.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Right-click &lt;strong>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Special Edition&lt;/strong> in your Steam games library.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select &lt;strong>Properties&lt;/strong> and switch to the &lt;strong>Language&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ensure that the language is set to &lt;strong>English&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/steam-skyrim-english.png" alt="english">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="installation-directory">Installation Directory&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The location Skyrim is installed to matters.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For one, it is highly recommended to install the game to your fastest drive, ideally an SSD, which will reduce load times. Running Skyrim from an HDD may negatively impact performance, causing stuttering and frame drops.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, Skyrim must not be located within any UAC-protected folders.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="uac-protected-folders">UAC-Protected Folders&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Your Steam installation is probably located under &lt;code>C:\Program Files x86\Steam\&lt;/code> and, by default, all Steam games are installed inside the Steam directory under &lt;code>\Steam\steamapps\common\&amp;lt;Game&amp;gt;\&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem is that &lt;code>C:\Program Files\&lt;/code> and &lt;code>C:\Program Files x86\&lt;/code> are so-called &lt;strong>UAC-protected folders&lt;/strong> (UAC = user account control). UAC-protected folders in Windows are special because they require admin privileges for read/write permissions which can break various modding tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Because of this, Skyrim SE must be installed to a location outside any UAC-protected folders.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="steam-libraries">Steam Libraries&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When installing a game through Steam, you can select any of your &lt;strong>Steam Libraries&lt;/strong> as the installation folder. The default Steam Library is within the Steam installation itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you installed Steam in&lt;code> C:\Program Files x86\&lt;/code> you will need to create a new Steam Library in a different location.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
Skip ahead to &lt;strong>Reinstalling Skyrim&lt;/strong> if you already have a second Steam Library outside UAC-protected folders.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>By default, you can only have one Steam Library per hard drive. If you want to create a second Steam Library on the same hard drive that you installed Steam on, please use LostDragonist’s &lt;a href="https://github.com/LostDragonist/steam-library-setup-tool/wiki/Usage-Guide">Steam Library Setup Tool&lt;/a> and follow the instructions from the link.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to create a new Steam Library on another hard drive, follow these steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> in Steam and go to the &lt;strong>Storage&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find the little ➕ icon near the top to add a new &lt;strong>Steam Library&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the desired hard drive.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Once set up, the new Steam Library can be selected as the installation directory upon installing a new game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/add-steam-library.png" alt="Add Steam Library">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reinstalling-skyrim">Reinstalling Skyrim&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now you can reinstall Skyrim. Find the game in the Steam Library tab and click the big blue Install button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>As the installation location choose a Steam Library on your fastest hard drive and outside UAC-protected folders.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Proceed when the download is completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/install-skyrim.png" alt="Install Skyrim">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="test-run">Test Run&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At this point, we should see if Skyrim launches properly. Running the game once serves multiple purposes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The &lt;code>\Documents\My Games\Skyrim Special Edition\&lt;/code> folder including its INI files will be regenerated.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The registry keys will be set up which is required for modding tools to recognise your installation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Certain issues with your vanilla game can be detected now (i.e., file corruption during the installation).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Always remember to launch Skyrim once after updating or reinstalling it, or after verifying game files.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Launch the game through Steam.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A message box will pop up, informing you that Skyrim SE will now be configured based on your hardware. If Skyrim is unable to detect your hardware, it is likely because you have a newer graphics card which is not recognised; you can ignore the warning.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> twice to confirm (INI file edits are covered in a different article).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>PLAY&lt;/strong> option in the launcher and wait until you are in the Skyrim main menu.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
&lt;strong>Anniversary Edition:&lt;/strong> Skyrim will prompt you with a message box, then proceed to download the creations. Wait for it to finish.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Quit the game from the main menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-success" role="alert">
If you got this far, everything appears to be running smoothly and you are ready to start modding.
&lt;/div>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="if-you-are-currently-working-through-the-core-module-return-to-step-1bgcore-modulestep1nexus-mods">If you are currently working through the Core Module, return to &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/core-module/step1/#nexus-mods">Step 1&lt;/a>.&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="recommended-next-step-mo2-setupbgadditional-modulesmo2-setup">Recommended next step: &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/mo2-setup/">MO2 Setup&lt;/a>.&lt;/h4></description></item><item><title>Bg: Cleaning Plugins</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/cleaning-plugins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/cleaning-plugins/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers how to &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; plugins, including the official master files and creations, with SSEEdit.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/sseedit/">SSEEdit&lt;/a> (including Quick Auto Clean), &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/loot/">LOOT&lt;/a> (optional), &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/loot-warning-checker">LOOT Warning Checker&lt;/a> (optional)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="quick-auto-clean">Quick Auto Clean&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
If you are unsure whether you should &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; any plugins, read &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/knowledge-base/cleaning-plugins/">this article&lt;/a> first.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Plugin &amp;ldquo;cleaning&amp;rdquo; used to be a semi-involved process with multiple steps but has since been simplified. It is done with &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/sseedit/">SSEEdit&lt;/a> in the &lt;strong>Quick Auto Clean&lt;/strong> mode. SSEEdit comes with a preconfigured executable for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can clean plugins either by manually running SSEEdit in -QAC mode or by using &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/loot-warning-checker/">LOOT Warning Checker&lt;/a> which is slightly faster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will demonstrate both methods using the official master files as an example.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
When cleaning plugins is needed, you can use LOOT to find plugins that are &amp;ldquo;unclean&amp;rdquo;. However, keep in mind that LOOT&amp;rsquo;s masterlist is limited and may be outdated or incomplete. If you missed any plugins, DynDOLOD NG should warn you about them later.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="backups">Backups&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When modifying offical files (the official master files or creations), I am in the habit of creating &lt;em>copies&lt;/em> rather than modifying the files in the default installation folder. This has the advantage that you can move or verify files without having to repeat the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
In the case of an actual update to the game, (some of) the official files are usually modified in which case you do need to repeat the process with the new version(s).
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Create a new mod in MO2 and name it &lt;strong>Official Master Files - Cleaned&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Copy the following ESMs from your installation folder into the new mod folder:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Update.esm&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dawnguard.esm&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hearthfires.esm&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dragonborn.esm&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place the new mod below the originals in Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-danger" role="alert">
Skyrim.esm cannot and &lt;em>should not&lt;/em> be cleaned. It consists exclusively of new records and has no masters.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/cleaning-plugins/overwrite-omf.png" alt="OMF Backups">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For creations I tend to copy all plugins that need cleaning into a similar &lt;strong>Creation Club - Cleaned&lt;/strong> mod before processing them. LOOT will tell you which creations have ITMs and/or deleted references.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For plugins from mods I would not create separate copies, but add to the &lt;strong>Notes&lt;/strong> tab in Mod Organizer 2 that the plugin was modified as a reminder to yourself. This way, you will know that you need to check and possibly re-clean the plugin when the mod is updated.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="manual-cleaning">Manual Cleaning&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Plugins can be &amp;ldquo;cleaned&amp;rdquo; with SSEEdit Quick Auto Clean &lt;u>one at a time&lt;/u>. When cleaning the official master files, start with Update.esm and proceed according to their load order (Dawnguard &amp;gt; HearthFires &amp;gt; Dragonborn). When cleaning plugins from mods, clean masters before dependencies.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run &lt;strong>SSEEdit QAC&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check the plugin you wish to clean and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/cleaning-plugins/cleaning-1.png" alt="Cleaning 1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The remainder of the process is fully automated and will take a few minutes. Simply wait for SSEEdit to return &lt;code>Quick Clean mode finished&lt;/code> at which point you can close the tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="loot-warning-checker">LOOT Warning Checker&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/loot-warning-checker/">LOOT Warning Checker&lt;/a> plugin will list all plugins that the LOOT Masterlist considers in need of cleaning with a handy &lt;strong>Fix&lt;/strong> button that will automatically run SSEEdit QAC. For plugins that are in the masterlist, this is slightly faster than launching QAC manually.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/cleaning-plugins/fix-to-clean.png" alt="Cleaning 2">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bg: Creating ESL Plugins</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/creating-esl-plugins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/creating-esl-plugins/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers how to flag plugins as ESL and compact Form IDs if necessary.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/sseedit/">SSEEdit&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="about-esl-plugins">About ESL Plugins&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before starting to ESL-ify plugins in your load order, I strongly suggest familiarising yourself with the format and when/how it should be used. Refer to the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/knowledge-base/plugin-basics/">Plugin Basics&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/knowledge-base/esl-plugins/">ESL Plugins&lt;/a> articles.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="esl-checklist">ESL Checklist&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can ESL-ify a plugin if:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>It contains fewer than 2048 new records (or none at all).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It contains new records, but the Form IDs only use the final three characters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It does not contain new CELL records.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>If a plugin contains new records and the Form IDs use more than the final three characters, they need to be &lt;strong>compacted&lt;/strong> first. Remember that compacting Form IDs will break all dependencies.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="esl-ifying">ESL-ifying&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can apply the ESL flag to any ESP or ESM plugin in SSEEdit.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Load your plugins into SSEEdit.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="form-ids">Form IDs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>First, you need to find out whether the plugin&amp;rsquo;s Form IDs are compatible with the ESL format.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Right-click the plugin you wish to ESL-ify and select &lt;strong>Compact FormIDs for ESL&lt;/strong>.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>This will trigger the general warning window if you did not disable it.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If the plugin contains no new Form IDs or only Form IDs that only use the final three characters, SSEEdit will return that there was &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/creating-esl-plugins/sseedit-nothing-to-do.png">nothing to do&lt;/a>. The plugin can be safely ESL-ified.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the plugin contains new Form IDs that need to be reformatted (compacted), &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/creating-esl-plugins/sseedit-renumber-formids.png">SSEEdit will notify you&lt;/a> about the amount of records that need their Form IDs renumbered and that this will break dependencies. If you are certain that there are no dependencies or that all dependencies are currently active and loaded, go ahead and click &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> to continue.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="esl-flag">ESL Flag&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After compacting Form IDs or ensuring that there are no incompatible Form IDs, you can add the ESL flag.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Select the plugin you wish to ESL-ify to open the &lt;strong>File Header&lt;/strong> in the right pane.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click the empty space next to &lt;strong>Record Flags&lt;/strong> and select &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check &lt;strong>ESL&lt;/strong> in the window that pops up and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Close SSEEdit and save your change(s).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/core-module/esl-flag-plugin.png" alt="ESL Flagging">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="full-esl">Full ESL&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Adding the ESL flag to an ESP will create an ESP-FE hybrid that loads in ESP space but does not count toward the 256 ESM/ESP plugin limit. If you want to move the plugin into ESM space, you need to rename its file extension from &lt;strong>.ESP&lt;/strong> to &lt;strong>.ESL&lt;/strong>. This will create a full ESL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the plugin overwrites &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/knowledge-base/references">references&lt;/a>, you &lt;u>must&lt;/u> also add the &lt;strong>ESM&lt;/strong> flag in SSEEdit to ensure that the list of Overriden Forms is populated and the plugin works as intended. I would generally recommend ESM-flagging full ESLs as they are all meant to load in ESM space and there is no downside to doing this.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Read more about &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/knowledge-base/references/#overriden-forms-onam">Overriden Forms&lt;/a>.
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Bg: Downgrade Skyrim</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/downgrade-skyrim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/downgrade-skyrim/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers how to revert to an older version of Skyrim.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/clean-install">Clean Install&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>If there has been a recent Skyrim SE update, this guide (and possibly the rest of the modding community) may not have caught up yet in which case &lt;u>downgrading to the last supported version of Skyrim is recommended&lt;/u>. The process is made painless by halgari’s automatic downgrade patcher.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Determine which version of &lt;strong>Skyrim SE&lt;/strong> you are on and which version you require (&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/skyrim-script-extender/#version-check">instructions&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Download the corresponding full patcher from &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/57618?tab=files">the mod page&lt;/a> (click &lt;strong>Manual Download&lt;/strong>).
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You will probably find the required version under &lt;strong>Old Files&lt;/strong> (use CTRL+F to search).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move the downloaded executable to your installation under &lt;code>\Steam\steamapps\common\Skyrim Special Edition\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Run the executable and wait for it to finish (should take only a few seconds).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Alternatively, you can use halgari’s &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/61756">Unofficial Skyrim Downloader&lt;/a>. I will add instructions for this at a later date.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>To prevent Skyrim from automatically updating, consider &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/update-proofing">Update Proofing&lt;/a> the game.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bg: Extracting BSAs</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/extracting-bsas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/extracting-bsas/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers various methods of extracting BSAs.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> Depends on the method&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="extraction-methods">Extraction Methods&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You need to extract a BSA if:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>You want to install a Skyrim LE mod that contains a BSA (it would crash the game).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You want assets from the BSA to overwrite loose files.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You want to selectively modify or remove assets from the BSA.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>(Going through MO2 is easily the most convenient option. Use BAE for selective extraction or for BSAs outside of MO2.)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="through-mod-organizer-2">Through Mod Organizer 2&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If a mod is already installed via Mod Organizer 2, you can extract it through the MO2 interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
Please make sure you have &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/92044?">BSA Extractor 2&lt;/a> installed. Check the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/mo2/#bsa-extractor-2">Mod Organizer 2&lt;/a> page for instructions.
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In Mod Organizer 2, switch to the &lt;strong>Archives&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Here, you will find all currently installed archives (BSAs). If they are checked, it means there is a plugin of the same name to load it.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Right-click the BSA and select &lt;strong>Extract&lt;/strong>.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>If a mod has multiple BSAs and you want to extract all of them, right-click the &lt;strong>mod name&lt;/strong> instead.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>\Mod Organizer 2\mods\&amp;lt;mod name&amp;gt;\&lt;/code> and confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This will extract the BSA into the mod folder. You can delete the BSA afterwards.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
You can also extract the BSA to a different location or a new mod folder if you only want partial/temporary access.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/extracting-archives/extract-through-mo2.png" alt="Extract through MO2">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="via-bethesda-archive-extractor">Via Bethesda Archive Extractor&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/bae/">Bethesda Archive Extractor&lt;/a> is probably the most versatile tool for extracting BSAs (perhaps the name gave it away). It allows you to unpack one BSA at a time, either in its entirety or in parts. You can also extract files and folders via simple drag-and-drop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The instructions linked above cover how to set BAE as the default app for BSAs.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>View any BSA by double-clicking it or by going through the MO2 &lt;strong>Filetree&lt;/strong>, right-clicking the BSA, and selecting &lt;strong>Open&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Extract&lt;/strong> to select a target folder to extract all currently checked assets to (all assets are checked by default).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Uncheck the BSA and check files or folders to selectively extract from the archive:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/extracting-archives/bae-selective-extraction.png" alt="BAE Selective Extraction">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="via-cathedral-assets-optimizer">Via Cathedral Assets Optimizer&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can create a dedicated profile in &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/cao/">Cathedral Assets Optimizer&lt;/a> for extracting BSAs.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>New&lt;/strong> button to create a new profile and use the &lt;strong>SSE&lt;/strong> profile as the basis.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Disable everything except for the &lt;strong>Extract BSA&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Delete Backups&lt;/strong> options in the &lt;strong>BSA&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;strong>Delete Backups:&lt;/strong> CAO will usually create backups of the extracted BSAs in the same folder. If you want to recover the BSAs it is usually easier to reinstall the mod through Mod Organizer 2 which is why I recommend setting CAO to delete the backups.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>To extract a BSA using CAO, click &lt;strong>Open Directory&lt;/strong> and navigate to the location of the BSA. Click &lt;strong>Select Folder&lt;/strong>. CAO will extract the assets from &lt;u>all BSAs within that folder&lt;/u> into the same folder.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bg: Filter for Conflicts</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/filter-for-conflicts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/filter-for-conflicts/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers how to create and apply a filter for conflicts in SSEEdit.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/sseedit/">SSEEdit&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="sseedit-filter">SSEEdit Filter&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SSEEdit has an indepth, customisable filter system with the ability to save settings as presets. A &lt;em>filter for conflicts&lt;/em> can be extremely helpful for &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/knowledge-base/conflict-management/">Conflict Management&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="conflict-resolution-filter">Conflict Resolution Filter&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Conflicts can be identified by applying a filter in SSEEdit.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Load up your plugins in SSEEdit.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click anywhere in the left pane and select &lt;strong>Apply Filter&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>Add&lt;/strong> button at the top to create a new filter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Name it &lt;strong>Conflict Resolution&lt;/strong> and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Your new filter will be selected automatically. Check the following options:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/core-module/cr-filter.png" alt="CR Filter">&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
The two options near the top will visualise conflicts which makes finding them infinitely easier. Flattening CELL records helps with viewing the Cell and Worldspace categories without having to click through blocks and sub-blocks.
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button at the top to save the new preset.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>Filter&lt;/strong> button at the bottom to apply it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This may take several minutes. You can proceed once the log returns &lt;code>Done: Applying Filter&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you wish to remove the filter, right-click in the left pane and select &lt;strong>Remove Filter&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
The next time you wish to filter for conflicts, right-click in the left pane, select &lt;strong>Apply Filter&lt;/strong>, make sure your preset is selected, and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Bg: INI Configuration</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/ini-config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/ini-config/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers recommended tweaks for the vanilla INI files made through BethINI.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/bethini">BethINI&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="modifying-the-ini-files">Modifying the INI Files&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To learn more about the default INI files and their contents, please consult the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/knowledge-base/ini-files/">INI Files&lt;/a> article. It also covers how to use &lt;u>profile-specific INI files&lt;/u> in Mod Organizer 2 which I highly recommend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can modify the INI files manually (through MO2 or a text editor) though this requires a decent bit of knowledge on what the settings do, especially in terms of their performance impact.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead, I recommend using the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/bethini/">BethINI&lt;/a> tool to modify the default set to at least apply one of its optimised presets instead of the vanilla preset.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bethini">BethINI&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before running BethINI, make sure that Mod Organizer 2 is &lt;u>closed&lt;/u>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run &lt;strong>BethINI.exe&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Choose &lt;strong>Skyrim Special Edition&lt;/strong> as the game.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bethini-setup">BethINI: Setup&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Switch to the &lt;strong>Setup&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Game:&lt;/strong> Should have &lt;em>Skyrim Special Edition&lt;/em> selected.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Game Path:&lt;/strong> Should point to the default installation folder:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>\Steam\steamapps\common\Skyrim Special Edition\&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mod Organizer 2:&lt;/strong> Should point to your Mod Organizer 2 instance.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>INI Path:&lt;/strong> Should point to your Documents folder &lt;u>or&lt;/u> your MO2 profile if using profile-specific INI files.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>BethINI will restart if you change the INI Path.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
If BethINI asks about modifying the &lt;strong>SkyrimCustom.ini&lt;/strong>, I recommend clicking &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>. I personally do not find it more convenient to outsource, as it were, some settings to the Custom INI. Of course, your mileage may vary.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/ini-config/bethini-setup.png" alt="BethINI Setup">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="bethini-basic">BethINI: Basic&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Switch to the &lt;strong>Basic&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Resolution:&lt;/strong> Set to match your monitor&amp;rsquo;s resolution.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Read more about resolutions, performance, and widescreen support &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/knowledge-base/resolution/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check &lt;strong>Recommended Tweaks&lt;/strong> and make sure &lt;strong>BethINI Tweaks&lt;/strong> are toggled on.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select either the &lt;strong>Low&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Medium&lt;/strong>, or &lt;strong>High&lt;/strong> preset.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Which preset you should select obviously depends on your hardware and monitor resolution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unless you are quite confident in your hardware, I would always recommend selecting the &lt;strong>Medium&lt;/strong> preset as a baseline. Many of the most performance-intense settings can still be toggled and modified individually.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Windowed Mode&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Borderless&lt;/strong> as well as any settings relating to VSync and framerate can be left untouched as &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/recommended-mods/essential-mods/#sse-display-tweaks">SSE Display Tweaks&lt;/a> should override them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Antialiasing:&lt;/strong> FXAA is an older antialiasing technique that performs better than TAA but causes some blurriness. I recommend leaving FXAA off and enabling TAA as most PCs should be more than able to run it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>64-Bit Render Targets&lt;/strong> is required to be enabled for certain ENB presets to look as intended but comes at a noticeable performance cost. You can disable it for now and re-enable it later if you end up installing an ENB preset that requires it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/ini-config/bethini-basic.png" alt="BethINI Basic">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="bethini-general">BethINI: General&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Switch to the &lt;strong>General&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>There is nothing that I recommend modifying in this tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to especially emphasize that you should leave the Papyrus settings &lt;u>untouched&lt;/u>. Since the Skyrim LE, a number of Papyrus tweaks have been floating around that were never more than placebo at best and actively harmful at worst.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="bethini-gameplay">BethINI: Gameplay&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Switch to the &lt;strong>Gameplay&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Once again, I do not recommend making changes here.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>NPCs Use Ammo&lt;/strong> sounds like a great option on paper, but does not work well in practice. In vanilla, archer NPCs spawn with a few arrows in their inventory which are not actually depleted as they fire them. Enabling this INI setting would cause them to rapidly burn through their arrows, then rendering them useless in combat.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bethini-interface">BethINI: Interface&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Switch to the &lt;strong>Interface&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Subtitles&lt;/strong> can be toggled here or ingame.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Bethesda Modding Platform&lt;/strong> should be &lt;u>enabled&lt;/u>.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>You can use &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/recommended-mods/utilities-frameworks/#qui">QUI&lt;/a> to disable the menu options as they should not be used.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mod Manager Menu&lt;/strong> should be &lt;u>disabled&lt;/u>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lock Sensitivity&lt;/strong> is best configured ingame where you can immediately test your settings.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bethini-detail">BethINI: Detail&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Switch to the &lt;strong>Detail&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Water:&lt;/strong> I recommend also checking &lt;em>Reflect Objects&lt;/em> when on the Medium preset.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Particles&lt;/strong> should be set to &lt;mark>2000&lt;/mark>, or &lt;mark>7500&lt;/mark> if using an ENB.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Depth of Field&lt;/strong> should remain toggled, even if you do not intend to use it because disabling it breaks underwater visuals. You can turn it down all the way ingame instead.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lens Flare&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Anamorphic Lens Flare&lt;/strong> do not look particularly good and should be disabled.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Always disable them when using ENB.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Shadow Resolution&lt;/strong> should be set to &lt;mark>2048&lt;/mark>, unless severely CPU-bottlenecked.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ambient Occlusion&lt;/strong> has a noticeable performance impact but adds a great deal of depth and should be enabled &lt;u>except&lt;/u> when using ENB which has its own, more advanced form of AO.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/ini-config/bethini-detail.png" alt="BethINI Detail">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="bethini-view-distance">BethINI: View Distance&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Switch to the &lt;strong>View Distance&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Grass Fade&lt;/strong> distance can be increased to &lt;mark>10000&lt;/mark> or higher with a relatively low performance cost.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Level 16:&lt;/strong> Set to at least &lt;mark>248705&lt;/mark> to prevent distant mountain peaks from looking completely white.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bethini-visuals">BethINI: Visuals&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Switch to the &lt;strong>Visuals&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Grass&lt;/strong> settings (density, diversity) should be left untouched here as grass overhauls tend to come with plugin INIs which modify these settings to work well with the rest of the mod.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Projected UV Diffuse Normals&lt;/strong> should always be left &lt;u>enabled&lt;/u> for consistent snow coverage.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>This requires a matching projecteddiffuse.dds texture for your snow01.dds texture.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Improved Shader&lt;/strong> (for snow) should always be left &lt;u>disabled&lt;/u>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bethini-finalisation">BethINI: Finalisation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When you are happy with your changes, return to the &lt;strong>Basic&lt;/strong> tab and click &lt;strong>Save and Exit&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can always re-run BethINI to modify the settings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bg: LOD &amp; Occlusion</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/lod-occlusion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/lod-occlusion/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers regeneration of Tree and Object LOD with DynDOLOD as well as Terrain LOD and Occlusion with SSELODGen. ACMOS instructions are optionally available.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/mo2/">Mod Organizer 2&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/sselodgen/">SSELODGen&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/dyndolod/">DynDOLOD&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/acmos-road-generator/">ACMOS Road Generator&lt;/a> (optional)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="regenerating-lods--occlusion">Regenerating LODs &amp;amp; Occlusion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As the final step in building a modded setup, you should regenerate all &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/knowledge-base/distant-lods/">distant LODs&lt;/a> (Terrain, Tree, Object). This will integrate your installed mods so distant terrain will match your close-up landscape textures, distant trees will use the models from your tree overhaul, buildings will be visible at a distance, and so forth.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
Please note that the current instructions expect you to generate &lt;a href="https://dyndolod.info/Help/Ultra-Tree-LOD">ultra tree LOD&lt;/a> which has a performance impact but looks &lt;a href="https://dyndolod.info/sites/dyndolod/files/images/3d-ultra-tree.webp">much better&lt;/a> than regular tree LOD. The extent of the performance impact can be modulated via the tree mesh rules.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Additionally, I recommend regenerating &lt;strong>Occlusion&lt;/strong>. Occlusion is an optimisation method which unloads parts of the game when they are not visible to the player to improve performance. SSELODGen and DynDOLOD can rebuild Occlusion data for exterior cells so that their LODs are not rendered when the area is hidden from view. This also fixes errors in vanilla Occlusion data such as the infamous &lt;a href="https://dyndolod.info/sites/dyndolod/files/images/occlusion.webp">hole in the Sea of Ghosts&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
For any further questions or if you are unable to resolve an issue, please consult the extremely extensive &lt;a href="https://dyndolod.info/">DynDOLOD documentation&lt;/a>. You can ask for support on the STEP forum in the &lt;a href="https://stepmodifications.org/forum/forum/223-dyndolod-xlodgen/">DynDOLOD / xLODGen section&lt;/a> as well as on our Discord server.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>All credits for the SSELODGen and DynDOLOD settings go to the &lt;a href="https://stepmodifications.org/wiki/SkyrimSE:2.2.0">STEP team&lt;/a>.&lt;/strong> I have relied on their recommended settings for many years because &lt;a href="https://stepmodifications.org/forum/topic/15184-xlodgen-terrain-settings-compare/page/3/#entry242523">their testing process is rigorous&lt;/a>. You may be able to get better visuals or better performance for your specific combination of mods by experimenting with the settings yourself, but that is very time-consuming.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The process for regenerating full LODs is somewhat involved and will take a good amount of time. With some routine and if everything goes smoothly you should be able to complete it in 30-60 minutes. If you have many mod-added worldspaces, it may take a little longer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following steps must be completed:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Regenerate Terrain LOD with SSELODGen.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Optional) Add roads/paths to Terrain LOD.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create billboards with TexGen.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerate Object and Tree LOD with DynDOLOD.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regenerate Occlusion with SSELODGen.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
When regenerating LODs early on in the construction of a setup to create a visual baseline, I recommend skipping ACMOS and Occlusion, and only generating Terrain/Tree/Object LOD for the Tamriel worldspace.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A note on Occlusion:&lt;/strong> While Occlusion can also be generated with DynDOLOD at the same time as Tree and Object LODs, I find it more convenient to separate the two processes. Unlike DynDOLOD, Occlusion rarely needs to be rebuilt and you will save a lot of time by keeping your existing Occlusion output when regenerating DynDOLOD.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="map-overhauls">Map Overhauls&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Map overhauls require some special treatment when regenerating LODs because it uses uses &lt;strong>Terrain LOD&lt;/strong> meshes and textures (LOD Level 32) which you may not want to overwrite.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, map overhauls also tend to have important modifications to the &lt;strong>Tamriel&lt;/strong> worldspace parent record. Make sure these edits are forwarded into the final layer before regenerating LODs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When using &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/5804">A Quality World Map&lt;/a> or any paper map mod, make sure to place these mods &lt;u>below&lt;/u> your SSELODGen Terrain LOD output in the mod order. They must also be present as &lt;u>loose files&lt;/u> to overwrite (instructions for unpacking BSAs can be found &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/extracting-bsas/">here&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-success" role="alert">
&lt;p>If you choose not to use a paper world map mod, I strongly recommend &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/56367">A Clear Map of Skyrim and Other Worlds&lt;/a> (ACMOS) which utilises SSELODGen and DynDOLOD to drastically improve world map quality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Instructions for using ACMOS are included on this page.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="seasons-of-skyrim">Seasons of Skyrim&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When using &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/62861">Seasons of Skyrim&lt;/a> with the relevant resources and related mods, LODs will be generated separately for each season. This means that the generation process will take 5 times as long and produces 5 times as many files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seasons of Skyrim support will be added to these instructions at a later date.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Unless you are creating a temporary set of LOD files for testing, &lt;u>your mod and load order should be finalised&lt;/u> before regenerating LODs. &lt;strong>This should be the final step.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If using A Clear World Map for Skyrim and Other Worlds, download the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/acmos-road-generator/">ACMOS Road Generator&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I strongly recommend also installing &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/recommended-mods/lod-resources/">Far Object LOD Improvement Project&lt;/a>, especially when using ACMOS.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If using &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/dyndolod/">DynDOLOD&lt;/a> NG, remember that &lt;em>deleted large references&lt;/em> must be undeleted first (&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/cleaning-plugins/">cleaning plugins&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="terrain-lod-generation">Terrain LOD Generation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Terrain LOD is generated with &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/sselodgen/">SSELODGen&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Make sure the &lt;strong>SSE-Terrain-Tamriel-Extend ESM&lt;/strong> is &lt;u>activated&lt;/u>. You can load the plugin at the top of your ESMs in the load order, right below the official master files and creations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also ensure that any other resources for Terrain LOD generation provided by mods are active.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="sselodgen-configuration">SSELODGen Configuration&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Launch SSELODGen through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Check all worldspaces (unless you are doing temporary LODs for Tamriel only).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure only &lt;strong>Terrain LOD&lt;/strong> is checked.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
The LOD Level 32 settings are specific for ACMOS, but the resulting files are mostly overwritten if you are using a different map overhaul. They should not break anything when ACMOS is not present.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Gamma:&lt;/strong> Depending on your landscape texture choice, the generated Terrain LOD may be too dark compared to close-up textures. For example, the STEP team sets gamma to &lt;code>1.25&lt;/code> in combination with &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/21954">Cathedral Landscapes&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Match the settings below and click Generate.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Settings must be configured for &lt;u>each&lt;/u> of the four LOD Levels. Switch between them via the &lt;strong>Settings for&lt;/strong> drop-down.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-success" role="alert">
Your SSELODGen configuration will be saved and you will not have to re-apply it the next time you run the tool.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/lod-occlusion/xlodgen-level-4.png" alt="Level 4">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/lod-occlusion/xlodgen-level-8.png" alt="Level 8">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/lod-occlusion/xlodgen-level-16.png" alt="Level 16">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/lod-occlusion/xlodgen-level-32.png" alt="Level 32">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="roads-generation">Roads Generation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If using &lt;strong>A Clear Map for Skyrim and Other Worlds&lt;/strong>, generate roads and paths for the map next.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run &lt;strong>ACMOS Road Generator.exe&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Point &lt;strong>Path to LOD&lt;/strong> to where you generated LODs to.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Output Path&lt;/strong> should point to the same folder so the existing files are overwritten.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set &lt;strong>Select Roads&lt;/strong> to &lt;em>Paths only&lt;/em> if you installed FOLIP and &lt;em>Roads&lt;/em> if you did not.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Generate&lt;/strong> and wait for the process to complete.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="sselodgen-output">SSELODGen Output&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can now import your Terrain LOD into Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Move the &lt;strong>Output&lt;/strong> folder to &lt;code>\Mod Organizer 2\mods\&lt;/code> and rename it to &lt;strong>Terrain LOD&lt;/strong> (or similar).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Press F5 to refresh Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place the new mod below the &lt;strong>Outputs&lt;/strong> separator at the bottom of your mod order.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Activate it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you have map mods other than &lt;em>A Clear Map of Skyrim and Other Worlds&lt;/em>, ensure that they overwrite your Terrain LOD output. For example, you can remove the conflicting files from the output or place the map mod below it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Disable all SSELODGen resources.&lt;/strong> This includes the SSE-Terrain-Tamriel-Extend ESM as well as resources from mods.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="texgen">TexGen&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before running DynDOLOD, we need to generate additional resources with &lt;strong>TexGen&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run &lt;strong>TexGen&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The first two &lt;strong>LOD Textures&lt;/strong> options should be &lt;u>checked&lt;/u>. Match the resolution to yours.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>For 1080p monitors, use the 1440p option (or 720p if you expect to have serious performance issues).&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For billboard &lt;strong>Units per pixel&lt;/strong> also match your resolution.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Generate billboards for &lt;strong>Tree&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Rendered&lt;/strong>. Also check &lt;strong>HD Tree&lt;/strong> which is required for ultra tree LODs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Leave the other settings unchanged and click &lt;strong>Start&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/lod-occlusion/texgen-settings.png" alt="TexGen Settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="texgen-output">TexGen Output&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When the process has completed, the output needs to be imported into MO2.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Locate the &lt;strong>TexGen_Output&lt;/strong> folder under &lt;code>\Modding Tools\DynDOLOD\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move the folder to &lt;code>\Mod Organizer 2\mods\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Press F5 to refresh Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place the mod below the &lt;strong>Terrain LOD&lt;/strong> output and activate it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="dyndolod">DynDOLOD&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before running DynDOLOD, we need to modify some of the settings:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>\Modding Tools\DynDOLOD\Edit Scripts\DynDOLOD\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the &lt;strong>DynDOLOD_SSE.ini&lt;/strong> in a text editor.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In &lt;strong>Line 11&lt;/strong>, enable Expert mode by default: &lt;code>Expert=1&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;u>If using ACMOS:&lt;/u> In &lt;strong>Line 47&lt;/strong>, enable LOD Level 32 generation: &lt;code>Level32=1&lt;/code>.*&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Save your changes and close the INI file.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=2>**This will enable generation of LOD Level 32 assets for ACMOS for a higher quality world map.*&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="dyndolod-configuration">DynDOLOD Configuration&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Run &lt;strong>DynDOLOD&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;u>If using DynDOLOD NG:&lt;/u> Make sure the log notes that the Large Ref Bug Workarounds are enabled:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/lod-occlusion/large-ref-bug-workaround-enabled.png" alt="Large Ref Workarounds">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Check all worldspaces (unless you are doing temporary LODs for Tamriel only).
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Right-click &amp;raquo; Select all.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check &lt;strong>Candles&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>FXGlow&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pick one of the three presets: &lt;strong>Low&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Medium&lt;/strong>, or &lt;strong>High&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Even on less powerful PCs the &lt;strong>Low&lt;/strong> preset should not have a performance impact. The performance loss from the &lt;strong>Medium&lt;/strong> preset should be negligible on most machines at least matching the recommended specs for vanilla. The &lt;strong>High&lt;/strong> preset obviously has the most noticeable performance impact but also yields solid results.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
The overall performance impact also depends on the mesh rules which can be individually tweaked.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>If you are unsure about the preset, pick &lt;strong>Medium&lt;/strong> and see how it goes. You can always regenerate DynDOLOD later if the performance impact is too much.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/lod-occlusion/dyndolod-settings-1.png" alt="Dyn Settings 1">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="tree-mesh-rules">Tree Mesh Rules&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The previously select &lt;strong>Preset&lt;/strong> affects the &lt;strong>Mesh Rules&lt;/strong> in the central box. These determine the level of quality for different distant objects, with some (types of) meshes having very specific settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Scroll to the very bottom of the list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Double-click the &lt;strong>tree&lt;/strong> mesh rule and apply one of the presets listed below.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The following presets are recommended by the &lt;a href="https://stepmodifications.org/wiki/SkyrimSE:2.2.0#Performance_Examples">STEP Guide&lt;/a>. From my testing, the &lt;strong>Best Quality&lt;/strong> preset is very performance hungry indeed even on strong hardware (@1440p, i7 10700k, RTX 3080, 16GB RAM) and I prefer the &lt;strong>Performance/Quality&lt;/strong> preset. Once again, I would recommend it as a baseline that you can adjust later on.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>LOD Level 4&lt;/th>
&lt;th>LOD Level 8&lt;/th>
&lt;th>LOD Level 16&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Best Performance&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Billboard4&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Billboard4&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Billboard1&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;mark>Performance / Quality&lt;/mark>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Level0&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Level4&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Level1&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Best Quality&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Level0&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Level1&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Level2&lt;/code>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/lod-occlusion/tree-mesh-rules.png" alt="Tree Mesh Rules">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;mark>&lt;u>If you are using ACMOS&lt;/u> also change the &lt;strong>LOD Level 32&lt;/strong> settings for the following mesh rules:&lt;/mark>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>tree&lt;/strong> to &lt;code>Billboard6&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>/&lt;/strong> (catch-all) to &lt;code>Level0&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/lod-occlusion/mesh-rules.png" alt="Mesh Rules">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="additional-settings">Additional Settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Follow the instructions below to modify the DynDOLOD settings at the bottom.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Uncheck &lt;strong>Occlusion data&lt;/strong>. We will generate Occlusion with SSELODGen.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check &lt;strong>Ultra&lt;/strong>. This will disable regular tree LOD.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check &lt;strong>Glow Windows&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>High&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check &lt;strong>Upgrade NearGrid References to FarGrid&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check &lt;strong>Fake lights child world&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;u>If you use &lt;strong>DynDOLOD NG&lt;/strong>&lt;/u> also modify the following two options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Check &lt;strong>Large reference bugs workarounds&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Uncheck &lt;strong>Downgrade FarGrid references to NearGrid&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;u>If you play at &lt;strong>4K&lt;/strong>&lt;/u> increase the resolution of the generated files:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Max tile size LOD&lt;/strong> to &lt;code>2048&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Max tile size full&lt;/strong> to &lt;code>512&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Max tile size billboard&lt;/strong> to &lt;code>512&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/lod-occlusion/dyndolod-settings-2.png" alt="Dyn Settings 2">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="preset">Preset&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The DynDOLOD configuration resets between runs, but you can change it as a preset to save time. &lt;strong>This is optional&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>Save Preset&lt;/strong> button on the bottom left in DynDOLOD.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I recommend saving the preset &lt;em>not&lt;/em> into the DynDOLOD Presets folder but outside of your DynDOLOD installation (for example into the Modding Tools folder). This way, you will not accidentally delete it when updating DynDOLOD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also rename it to reflect your mesh rule preset choice or the specific setup you created it for.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
The next time you regenerate DynDOLOD, you can import your settings via the &lt;strong>Load Preset&lt;/strong> button. You can still adjust them; however, any changes you make will &lt;u>not&lt;/u> be automatically saved in the preset.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/lod-occlusion/dyndolod-save-preset.png" alt="DynDOLOD Save Preset">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="dyndolod-generation">DynDOLOD Generation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;mark>After configuring all settings, click &lt;strong>Run&lt;/strong> to start the LOD generation.&lt;/mark> This may take 10-15 minutes or longer, depending on your settings and the size of your setup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once DynDOLOD has completed, it may open an HTML with errors in a browser window. &lt;strong>Do not ignore these logs.&lt;/strong> They can be very helpful for troubleshooting and I suggest you address them immediately, then re-run DynDOLOD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=2>*I intend to add instructions on how to deal with the most common issues at a later date. Refer to the &lt;a href="https://dyndolod.info/">DynDOLOD documentation&lt;/a> in the meantime.*&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="dyndolod-output">DynDOLOD Output&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When the process has completed, the output needs to be imported into MO2.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Locate the &lt;strong>DynDOLOD_Output&lt;/strong> folder under &lt;code>\Modding Tools\DynDOLOD\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move the folder to &lt;code>\Mod Organizer 2\mods\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Press F5 to refresh Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place the mod below the &lt;strong>TexGen Output&lt;/strong> and activate it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Load &lt;strong>DynDOLOD.esm&lt;/strong> as the last ESM and &lt;strong>DynDOLOD.esp&lt;/strong> at the bottom of your load order.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="occlusion">Occlusion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Finally, we will generate Occlusion with SSELODGen.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run &lt;strong>SSELODGen&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the right pane, &lt;em>right-click&lt;/em> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Select all&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;u>Uncheck&lt;/u> &lt;strong>Terrain LOD&lt;/strong> and &lt;u>check&lt;/u> &lt;strong>Occlusion&lt;/strong> instead.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Increase the &lt;strong>Quality&lt;/strong> to &lt;strong>3&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Increasing the quality will improve performance by occluding more areas at the cost of a longer generation time. Since you will rarely regenerate Occlusion, taking the time now is worth it.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The other settings should be left unchanged according to the &lt;a href="https://dyndolod.info/Help/Occlusion-Data">documentation&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click &lt;strong>Generate&lt;/strong> and &lt;u>step away&lt;/u> while SSELODGen is running. Occlusion generation can be very resource-intense and it is safer not to touch your keyboard until it has completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/lod-occlusion/occlusion-settings.png" alt="Occlusion Settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="occlusion-output">Occlusion Output&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When the process has completed, the output needs to be imported into MO2.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Check the &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> in Mod Organizer 2. It should only contain &lt;strong>Occlusion.esp&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click the &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> and select &lt;strong>Create Mod&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Name your new mod &lt;strong>Occlusion&lt;/strong> (or similar).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place it below &lt;strong>DynDOLOD Output&lt;/strong> and activate it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Leave the plugin at the bottom of your load order, right below &lt;strong>DynDOLOD.esp&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;mark>All LODs have been regenerated! Feel free to jump ingame and marvel at the effect.&lt;/mark>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bg: Managing Creations</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/managing-creations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/managing-creations/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers the installation of Curation Club and importing Creations into MO2.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/mo2/">Mod Organizer 2&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="curation-club">Curation Club&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Curation Club&lt;/strong> is a plugin for Mod Organizer 2 which simplifies importing Creations as mods.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download the latest main file of &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/60552?tab=files">Curation Club&lt;/a> (click &lt;strong>Mod Manager Download&lt;/strong>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In MO2, switch to the &lt;strong>Downloads&lt;/strong> tab in the right pane.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click the downloaded mod and select &lt;strong>Open File&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract the &lt;strong>curationclub&lt;/strong> folder to &lt;code>\Mod Organizer 2\plugins\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
To quickly access the &lt;strong>plugins&lt;/strong> folder, you can click &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/mo2-plugins-folder-shortcut.png">the folder icon&lt;/a> above the left pane and select &lt;strong>Open MO2 Plugins Folder&lt;/strong>.
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Restart Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/managing-creations/curation-club-installation.png" alt="Curation Club Installation">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="importing-creations">Importing Creations&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Running &lt;strong>Curation Club&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2 will now import all creations present in your default (Steam) installation folder into Mod Organizer 2 where you can manage them like any other mod.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
Because &lt;strong>Curation Club&lt;/strong> moves the creations out of the data folder rather than creating copies, you may want to create a backup first. Just copy all files starting with cc from &lt;code>\Steam\steamapps\common\Skyrim Special Edition\Data\&lt;/code> to a convenient location.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Run &lt;strong>Curation Club&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/managing-creations/run-curation-club.png" alt="Run CC">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The default naming scheme &lt;code>Creation Club - {creation}&lt;/code> is perfect for me (but feel free to change it to your preferences).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are following the Core Module or if you are already using Root Builder, check the box for &lt;strong>Root Builder Support&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to import your creations.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-success" role="alert">
You can now manage your Creations through Mod Organizer 2 like any other mod.
&lt;/div>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="if-you-are-currently-working-through-the-core-module-return-to-step-1bgcore-modulestep1free-creations">If you are currently working through the Core Module, return to &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/core-module/step1/#free-creations">Step 1&lt;/a>.&lt;/h4></description></item><item><title>Bg: Optimising SLE Assets</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/optimising-sle-assets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/optimising-sle-assets/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers how to use CAO for porting textures, meshes, and animations to Skyrim SE.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/cao/">Cathedral Assets Optimizer&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="optimising-with-cao">Optimising with CAO&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can process textures, meshes, and animations with &lt;strong>Cathedral Assets Optimizer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I recommend creating a new profile first.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open &lt;strong>Cathedral Assets Optimizer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;strong>New&lt;/strong> button to create a new profile and name it &lt;strong>SSE - Optimise SLE Assets&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use the default &lt;strong>SSE&lt;/strong> profile as the basis.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Configure as shown in the pictures below.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/optimising-sle-assets/cao-extract-bsa.png" alt="CAO Extract BSA">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/optimising-sle-assets/cao-optimise-meshes.png" alt="CAO Optimise Meshes">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/optimising-sle-assets/cao-optimise-textures.png" alt="CAO Optimise Textures">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/optimising-sle-assets/cao-optimise-animations.png" alt="CAO Optimise Animations">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="usage">Usage&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can run any Skyrim LE mod containing meshes, textures, &lt;u>or&lt;/u> animation files through CAO using this profile.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the assets are still packed in a BSA, they will be extracted and the archive deleted as it would crash Skyrim SE otherwise. You can use the CAO &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/cao/#create-bsa-profile">Create BSA profile&lt;/a> to repack the assets after processing if you so wish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Should a mesh still have issues after processing (causing crashes or visual bugs), try using a higher level of optimisation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bg: Porting SLE Plugins</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/porting-sle-plugins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/porting-sle-plugins/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers how to use the Creation Kit and SSEEdit for porting plugins.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/creation-kit/">Creation Kit&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/sseedit/">SSEEdit&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="form-version">Form Version&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>All plugins that were created for Skyrim LE should at least be resaved in the Skyrim SE Creation Kit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Skyrim SE, some records in the vanilla game files have the new &lt;strong>form version 44&lt;/strong> as opposed to the previous &lt;strong>form version 43&lt;/strong> and it has been discovered that the form version of user-made SLE plugins changes from 43 to 44 when resaving them in the Creation Kit. If this is not done, the plugin &lt;u>may&lt;/u> cause issues when loaded in Skyrim SE (including save game corruption and apparently crashes).&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Form version 43 in SSE plugins are not always problematic. Refer to this &lt;a href="https://davidjcobb.github.io/skyrim-writings/articles/form-versions-43-and-44.html">excellent article&lt;/a> by DavidJCobb if you are interested in learning about the difference between form versions and when it matters.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="mo2-warning">MO2 Warning&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Mod Organizer 2 will detect plugins with Form Version 43 when they are present in the load order. Again, this does not necessarily mean that the plugin contains corrupted data, but it should be resaved to be safe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using xEdit scripts to check for wrong form versions in your load order is unnecessary given the MO2 warning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/porting-sle-plugins/mo2-form-43-warning.png" alt="MO2 Warning">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="sseedit-plugin-header">SSEEdit Plugin Header&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can see a plugin&amp;rsquo;s form version in the &lt;strong>Plugin Header&lt;/strong> in SSEEdit:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/porting-sle-plugins/form-version-43.png" alt="Wrong Form Version">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="resaving-plugins">Resaving Plugins&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Converting a plugin is as easy as opening and saving it in the SSE Creation Kit. This should be done with &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/20061">SSE Creation Kit Fixes&lt;/a> installed as the CK still misses some forms that require conversion.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run the &lt;strong>Creation Kit&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the little folder icon in the toolbar to open a plugin.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/porting-sle-plugins/ck-open-plugin.png" alt="CK Open Plugin">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can only ever load one active plugin in the Creation Kit. If you have multiple SLE plugins, resave them one at a time.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Select the plugin you wish to resave and click &lt;strong>Set as Active File&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to load the plugin.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This will load the plugin and its masters. Wait until the CK says &amp;ldquo;done&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/porting-sle-plugins/ck-done-loading.png" alt="CK Done">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/porting-sle-plugins/ck-save-plugin.png">Save icon&lt;/a> in the toolbar.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Close the Creation Kit.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-success" role="alert">
And that&amp;rsquo;s it! The plugin has been resaved successfully.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/porting-sle-plugins/form-version-44.png" alt="Correct Form Version">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="water-flow">Water Flow&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="landscape">Landscape&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>Bg: Regenerating Facegen</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/regenerating-facegen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/regenerating-facegen/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers how to use the Creation Kit to regenerate facegen for all NPCs.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/creation-kit/">Creation Kit&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/synthesis/">Synthesis&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/cao/">Cathedral Assets Optimizer&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="about-facegen">About Facegen&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Please check the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/knowledge-base/facegen/">Facegen&lt;/a> article for more information about facegen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should regenerate facegen when:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Changes to Head Parts, Tint Layers, etc, were made in the NPC&amp;rsquo;s record.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New meshes for head parts (hair, eyes, mouth) were installed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New textures for tint masks (make up, war paints, dirt overlays) were installed.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I recommend regenerating facegen for all NPCs (vanilla and mod-added) as one of the final steps when building a setup. The process is detailed below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you only need to regenerate facegen for specific NPCs, please check &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/regenerating-facegen/#regenerating-specific-facegen">the instructions at the bottom of this page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before you regenerate facegen please ensure that &lt;strong>conflict resolution is completed&lt;/strong> at least for NPC records. The Synthesis patcher will pull data from the final overwriting record, so if NPC-modifying records are currently being overwritten and reverted to vanilla you would end up with mismatched facegen if you resolved the conflict later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Any asset replacers for head parts and tint masks as well as any plugins modifying NPC appearance should be installed before regenerating facegen. All mods adding new NPCs should also be installed for perfect consistency across the board.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
I recommend &lt;u>deleting&lt;/u> any facegen files from mods that add new NPCs as they will now be regenerated using assets from your setup to be consistent with each other and with the vanilla NPCs.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="ck-fixes-ini-tweak">CK Fixes INI Tweak&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>By default, the Creation Kit will generate facetint textures of 512x512 resolution which yields small file sizes but looks fairly blurry. The resolution can be increased using &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/creation-kit/#creation-kit-fixes">SSE Creation Kit Fixes&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Double-click &lt;strong>SSE Creation Kit Fixes&lt;/strong> in your mod order.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Switch to the &lt;strong>INI Files&lt;/strong> tab and select the &lt;strong>skyrim64_test.ini&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Modify the following line:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>[CreationKit_FaceGen]
TintMaskResolution=1024
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>You can further increase the resolution to &lt;code>2048&lt;/code> if you intend to build a setup mostly for screenarchery and closeup pictures. Any resolution above &lt;code>1024&lt;/code> is overkill for normal gameplay and will generate very large files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Remember to save your change before closing the window.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=2>*I also added &lt;code>Increased tint mask resolution to 1024.&lt;/code> to the Notes tab for the mod.*&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
Remember that the vanilla game will only display tint masks in 512x512 resolution unless you added the appropriate tweak to the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/skyrim-script-extender/#skse-ini-edits-for-skse">SKSE.ini&lt;/a>.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="synthesis-patcher">Synthesis Patcher&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To speed up the process of regenerating facegen for all NPCs that are present, we are going to use a very handy &lt;a href="https://github.com/KingKai-1906/Synth-NPCs-Face-Data">Synthesis patcher&lt;/a> by Sr. Kaio made for this express purpose. It will copy all NPC records into a single output plugin which can then be loaded into the Creation Kit for exporting facegen.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Run &lt;strong>Synthesis&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a new group (see picture) and name it &lt;strong>Facegen Helper&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/synthesis-new-group.png" alt="Synthesis New Group">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add a &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/synthesis-add-patcher-from-git.png">patcher from Git&lt;/a> and switch to &lt;strong>Input&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>As the repository link, enter &lt;code>https://github.com/caiobraz/Synth-NPCs-Face-Data&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select &lt;strong>SynthNPCsWithFaces.csproj&lt;/strong> from the &lt;strong>Projects&lt;/strong> drop-down.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the blue checkmark to confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/regenerating-facegen/add-synth-patcher.png" alt="Add Synth Patcher">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Give Synthesis a moment to import the new patcher. Once it is &lt;mark>Ready&lt;/mark>, run the patcher.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/regenerating-facegen/synth-patcher-ready.png" alt="Synth Patcher Ready">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Generating the plugin should only take a few seconds, depending on how many plugins are present.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Close Synthesis when it is done.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="patcher-output">Patcher Output&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Back in Mod Organizer 2, the newly generated plugin will have been caught by the &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ensure no other files are located in the &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> before right-clicking it and selecting &lt;strong>Create mod&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Name your new mod &lt;strong>Facegen Helper&lt;/strong> and confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I recommend keeping an &lt;strong>Outputs&lt;/strong> separator at the bottom of your mod order and placing the new plugin here.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Feel free to jump into SSEEdit and have a look at the plugin&amp;rsquo;s contents. It should contain copies of all NPC records (and therefore require all plugins that add NPCs) as well as all head parts so they are also loaded. Conveniently, the patcher.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="exporting-facegen">Exporting Facegen&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With the helper plugin in place, we can now jump into the &lt;strong>Creation Kit&lt;/strong> to export facegen.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Make sure the &lt;strong>Facegen Helper&lt;/strong> plugin is active in the load order.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Your &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> should be completely clean and empty.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Run the &lt;strong>Creation Kit&lt;/strong> through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the little &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/porting-sle-plugins/ck-open-plugin.png">folder icon&lt;/a> in the toolbar to open a plugin.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select &lt;strong>Facegen Helper.esp&lt;/strong> and click &lt;strong>Set as Active File&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Confirm and wait for the Creation Kit to load up the plugin. Proceed once it is &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/porting-sle-plugins/ck-done-loading.png">done&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="npc-records">NPC Records&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>NPC records can be found under &lt;strong>Actors&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Actor&lt;/strong> in the Creation Kit where you can see a long list of NPCs that are currently part of the active plugin and any loaded masters.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Check the box to &lt;strong>Show only active (*) forms&lt;/strong> near the top left in the Creation Kit.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/regenerating-facegen/ck-show-only-active-forms.png" alt="Active Forms">&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
This is partially why we are using a helper plugin: Only NPC records present in the active plugin will show up in the list, filtering out any records that do not need to have facegen exported (such as children).
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Facegen can be exported by selecting one or several NPCs and pressing CTRL + F4. Now you can go through and select NPCs to export facegen one race at a time.*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=2>**Going one race at a time is a completely arbitrary way of splitting up the sheer amount NPCs so you do not try to export all at once and risk crashing the Creation Kit. You can also go for roughly 50-100 at a time.*&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You must &lt;u>skip&lt;/u> &lt;mark>NordRaceAstrid&lt;/mark> (between NordRace and NordRaceVampire).&lt;/strong> Selecting her will break all facegen.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Sort the NPC records by &lt;strong>Race&lt;/strong> (click the column and feel free to expand it).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the first NPC of a race, press and hold SHIFT, scroll down to the last NPC and select it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Press &lt;strong>CTRL + F4&lt;/strong> to export facegen for all highlighted NPCs and confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For every batch of NPCs you will have to wait a moment for the Creation Kit to process all records.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Close the Creation Kit once you have exported facegen for all NPCs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="managing-the-output">Managing the output&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At least 16GB of facegen files will now sit in your &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> in Mod Organizer 2. To bring down the total file size, I recommend packing all files into BSAs.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Packing the assets into archives means that they will be overwritten by any loose facegen files. This is why I recommended deleting other mods&amp;rsquo; facegen files earlier.
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Right-click the &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> and select &lt;strong>Create Mod&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Name the new mod &lt;strong>Facegen Output&lt;/strong> or similar and confirm.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Note that the name will be used by CAO for the BSAs and plugins created in the next step.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Activate the new mod in the load order.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="creating-bsas">Creating BSAs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Use the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/cao/#create-bsa-profile">Create BSA&lt;/a> profile in &lt;strong>Cathedral Assets Optimizer&lt;/strong> to pack up the assets.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open &lt;strong>Cathedral Assets Optimizer&lt;/strong> and select the &lt;strong>SSE - Create BSA&lt;/strong> profile.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>For instructions on how to create this profile, see the link above.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Open Directory&lt;/strong> and navigate to the mod folder: &lt;code>\Mod Organizer 2\mods\Facegen Output\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the folder and click &lt;strong>Run&lt;/strong> in Cathedral Assets Optimizer.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Packing 16GB+ worth of assets will take a few minutes and I recommend stepping away in the meantime. You can check the tool&amp;rsquo;s progress in the log tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="finalisation">Finalisation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Once CAO has completed you can close it and return to Mod Organizer 2. Press F5 to refresh the UI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The loose files will have been replaced with a set of plugins and archives. Make sure the plugins are active in the load order and that assets are overwriting correctly. If you have other BSA-packed facegen that you want to overwrite, place the plugins those BSAs are attached to below the Facegen Output plugins. Loose files will already overwrite.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Disable Facegen Helper.&lt;/strong> The patch is only necessary for exporting facegen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feel free to hop ingame and admire the results!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="regenerating-specific-facegen">Regenerating specific facegen&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you only need to export facegen for specific NPCs, you do not need to generate any Synthesis patches. Do be sure that the NPC&amp;rsquo;s record is not being unintentionally overwritten and modify the &lt;strong>SSE Creation Kit Fixes&lt;/strong> INI &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/regenerating-facegen/#ck-fixes-ini-tweak">as detailed above&lt;/a>. Make sure all asset replacers for head parts and tint masks are active as well and delete existing facegen for that NPC.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Load up the plugin in which the NPC is created in the &lt;strong>Creation Kit&lt;/strong> (this can be a vanilla master file or a mod).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find the NPC(s) in question under &lt;strong>Actors&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Actor&lt;/strong> and select it/them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hit &lt;strong>CTRL + F4&lt;/strong> to export facegen and confirm.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Wait for the CK to process everything and close it when it is done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Mod Organizer 2, be sure to move the facegen assets out of the &lt;em>&lt;strong>Overwrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>. You can place them in the original mod&amp;rsquo;s folder or in a separate one (the latter is recommended because otherwise you have to repeat the process when the mod is updated).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bg: Root Builder</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/root-builder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/root-builder/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers the purpose and installation of the Root Builder plugin for MO2.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/mo2/">Mod Organizer 2&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="about-root-builder">About Root Builder&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Root Builder&lt;/strong> is a plugin for Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It allows us to install and manage files that must go into the root folder through Mod Organizer 2. When we launch the game or any tool through Mod Organizer 2, all root folder files will be &lt;em>temporarily&lt;/em> moved into the actual root folder by the plugin. When the game or tool is closed, those files will automatically be removed again from the root folder. Pretty neat, huh?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are multiple advantages to using &lt;strong>Root Builder&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The root folder will always stay clean and vanilla, and there will be no overlap between multiple modded setups.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This allows you to run a personal setup and a Wabbajack list independently from each other.*&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All files are managed through Mod Organizer 2 for easy activation/deactivation, version control, custom notes, etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Potential support for the GOG version of Skyrim in this guide later on!)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=2>**All setups must run the same version of Skyrim to share a root folder. However, most Wabbajack lists that are not on the latest version use the Stock Game folder system (see below) and will thus not interfere at all.*&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
If we were to dump all root folder files into the root folder it would quickly become difficult to tell which files are vanilla and which are mod-added, and, if they are mod-added, which version is currently installed. This gets nowhere near as bad as an unmanaged data folder, but it is inconvenient and we do not like inconvenience.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>With Mod Organizer 2 and Root Builder we can build an almost completely self-contained modded setup.*&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=2>**We could use the Stock Game folder system and create an entire new copy of the vanilla game files (i.e., the root folder) to make the setup fully self-contained. However, that would add about 13GB of files without offering any meaningful benefits for most regular users.*&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Is Root Builder perfect? I would not say that. However, the issues that I have encountered with the plugin (in about a year of heavy use) are very minor and easy to fix. While not everyone likes the plugin, I personally find it invaluable and highly recommend it.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Root Builder&lt;/strong> is hosted on the Nexus.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download the latest version of &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/31720?tab=files">Root Builder&lt;/a> (click &lt;strong>Mod Manager Download&lt;/strong>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In Mod Organizer 2, switch to the &lt;strong>Downloads&lt;/strong> tab in the right pane.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click the downloaded mod and select &lt;strong>Open File&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract the &lt;strong>rootbuilder&lt;/strong> folder to &lt;code>\Mod Organizer 2\plugins\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
To quickly access the &lt;strong>plugins&lt;/strong> folder, you can click &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/mo2-plugins-folder-shortcut.png">the folder icon&lt;/a> above the left pane and select &lt;strong>Open MO2 Plugins Folder&lt;/strong>.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Restart Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/root-builder-installation.png" alt="Root Builder Installation">&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="if-you-are-currently-working-through-the-core-module-return-to-step-2bgcore-modulestep2mo2-separators">If you are currently working through the Core Module, return to &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/core-module/step2/#mo2-separators">Step 2&lt;/a>.&lt;/h4></description></item><item><title>Bg: Skyrim Script Extender</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/skyrim-script-extender/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/skyrim-script-extender/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers the Skyrim Script Extender, including the importance of Skyrim versions as well as the installation of SKSE with Root Builder and of related mods.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/tool-setup/mo2/">Mod Organizer 2&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/root-builder/">Root Builder&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="the-skyrim-script-extender">The Skyrim Script Extender&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you have any previous modding experience at all, you will likely have heard of the &lt;strong>Skyrim Script Extender&lt;/strong>, or &lt;strong>SKSE&lt;/strong> for short. Of all the mods and tools out there, the Script Extender is definitely among the most vital ones: It extends the scripting capabilities of the engine, allowing mod authors to implement features that would not have been possible otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
&lt;strong>SKSE is required by many mods, including most of the essentials.&lt;/strong> Modding Skyrim on XBOX or PS5 is not comparable to modding on PC largely because SKSE cannot be installed on consoles. The same is true for the PC Game Pass version of Skyrim.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>A popular example of an SKSE-dependent feature is the &lt;strong>Mod Configuration Menu&lt;/strong>, or &lt;strong>MCM&lt;/strong> for short, which is part of the UI overhaul mod &lt;strong>SkyUI&lt;/strong>. There are also a multitude of SKSE-based plugins which, among other things, fix engine-level bugs that could not have been addressed otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="skse-and-skyrim-updates">SKSE and Skyrim Updates&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>All updates to &lt;strong>Skyrim SE&lt;/strong> change the main executable, &lt;strong>SkyrimSE.exe&lt;/strong>, which requires the &lt;strong>Script Extender&lt;/strong> to be updated in turn because it is &lt;u>version-dependent&lt;/u> and will only work with the specific version of Skyrim SE it was compiled for. For example, SKSE SE version &lt;strong>2.0.20&lt;/strong> functions only with the last pre-Anniversary Edition version of Skyrim SE, &lt;strong>1.5.97&lt;/strong>. The new SKSE AE was made for the post-AE versions of Skyrim SE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whenever Skyrim updates, the modding community tends to catch up within a few weeks to months. Staying indefinitely on an older version will eventually mean that you cannot use newer mods or update existing mods. Therefore it makes sense to move on to the current version once all (or at least most) of the mods in your setup have been updated.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Skyrim SE 1.5.97:&lt;/strong> Last pre-AE version of Skyrim SE (requires SKSE 2.0.20)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Skyrim SE 1.6.317:&lt;/strong> Skyrim SE patch that accompanied the AE release (requires SKSE 2.1.0)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Skyrim SE 1.6.353:&lt;/strong> Post-AE version of Skyrim SE with most mods ported (requires SKSE 2.1.5)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Skyrim SE 1.6.640:&lt;/strong> Current version of Skyrim SE (requires SKSE 2.2.3) &amp;laquo; &lt;u>this is what we are running&lt;/u>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>(&lt;a href="https://en.uesp.net/wiki/Skyrim:Special_Edition_Patch">Full Skyrim SE version history with changelogs&lt;/a>.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The issue of version dependency not only affects SKSE and the base game, but also SKSE and SKSE plugins. While some SKSE-dependent mods only use functions added by SKSE in their scripts and do not require a specific version of SKSE to actually work, there are also the so-called &lt;strong>SKSE plugins&lt;/strong>*. These files with the &lt;strong>.DLL&lt;/strong> extension are dependent on a specific SKSE version the same way SKSE is dependent on a specific Skyrim SE version.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=2>**SKSE plugins (DLLs) are not to be confused with Skyrim plugins (ESMs, ESPs, ESLs). The former are written in C or C++ and specific to the Script Extender. The latter are created in the Creation Kit or community-made tools, and specific to Creation Engine games.*&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="downloading-skse">Downloading SKSE&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before we install SKSE, we need to know which version of the game we are running by performing a &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/skyrim-version-check/">Skyrim Version Check&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please also follow the instructions for &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/update-proofing">Update Proofing&lt;/a> Skyrim.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once we figure out which version of Skyrim we have installed, we know which version of SKSE to grab. The Script Extender is available on its &lt;a href="https://skse.silverlock.org/">official website&lt;/a> and on the Nexus.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
Read carefully and make sure you are downloading the correct file.
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download the &lt;strong>Skyrim Script Extender&lt;/strong> for &lt;strong>Steam&lt;/strong> from the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/30379?tab=files">Nexus page&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The current version of SKSE for AE, build 2.x.x, should correlate with the current Skyrim SE version, runtime 1.6.xxx.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="installing-skse">Installing SKSE&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SKSE is an unusual mod in that it consists of both &lt;strong>root folder files&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>data folder files&lt;/strong>. We will use the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/">Root Builder&lt;/a> plugin in order to manage all parts of the mod in Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="new-separator">New Separator&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
The instructions below are intended for those following the Core Module.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>For the next batch of mods, we will want a new separator:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Create a new separator in Mod Organizer 2 (&lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/mo2-create-separator.png">reference picture&lt;/a>) and name it &lt;strong>Script Extender&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Leave it at the bottom of the left pane, below the &lt;strong>Creation Club&lt;/strong> separator.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="root-folder-files">Root Folder Files&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To manage SKSE through MO2, we first need a new mod folder.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In Mod Organizer 2, click the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/create-empty-mod.png">crossed tools icon&lt;/a> above the mod order and select &lt;strong>Create empty mod&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter &lt;strong>Skyrim Script Extender&lt;/strong> as the name and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click your new mod in the mod order and select &lt;strong>Open in Explorer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the Explorer, right-click and select &lt;strong>New&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Folder&lt;/strong> (or press Shift + CTRL + N).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Name the new folder &lt;strong>Root&lt;/strong> and open it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;strong>Root Builder&lt;/strong> copies all files inside &lt;code>\Mod Organizer 2\mods\&amp;lt;Mod Name&amp;gt;\Root\&lt;/code> into the root folder when launching an application through Mod Organizer 2 and removes them after the application is closed again.
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open the SKSE archive you previously downloaded.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract &lt;strong>skse64_1_6_xxx.dll&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>skse64_loader.exe&lt;/strong> to &lt;code>\Mod Organizer 2\mods\Skyrim Script Extender\Root\&lt;/code>.*&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=2>**There used to be a third DLL, skse64_steam_loader.dll, that was part of SKSE but is no longer required as of SKSE 2.2.3.*&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/skse-root-folder.png" alt="SKSE Root">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back in Mod Organizer 2, the new &lt;strong>Skyrim Script Extender&lt;/strong> mod will be greyed out because MO2 does not recognise the Root folder as a valid mod directory. This is just a UI limitation and nothing to worry about.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Right-click the new mod and select &lt;strong>Ignore missing data&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check the box to activate it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="skse-executable">SKSE Executable&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A minor disadvantage of adding SKSE in this fashion is that MO2 will not automatically recognise it. We need to set up the executable manually.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open the &lt;strong>Executables&lt;/strong> settings in Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/mo2-executables-settings.png" alt="Open Executable Settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click the small blue plus icon and select &lt;strong>Add from file&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>\Mod Organizer 2\mods\Skyrim Script Extender\Root\&lt;/code> and double-click the &lt;strong>skse64_loader.exe&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Optional) Rename the executable in MO2 to &lt;strong>Skyrim Script Extender&lt;/strong> and move it to the top of the list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to save your changes and close the window.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
The &lt;strong>Redirect&lt;/strong> feature in &lt;strong>Root Builder&lt;/strong> will automatically move an executable file from a mod folder into the root folder if it is launched through MO2. This is why we can simply point MO2 at the mod folder here.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/mo2-skse-executable.png" alt="SKSE Exec">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="skse-scripts">SKSE Scripts&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Going back to the downloaded SKSE archive, you will notice two folders inside: &lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>src&lt;/strong>. The latter is short for &amp;ldquo;source&amp;rdquo;, meaning it contains the source code for mod authors which we do not need.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong> folder contains scripts which are a required component of SKSE. Those scripts are regular assets belonging into the &lt;strong>data folder&lt;/strong> and can therefore be handled by Mod Organizer 2 as usual. We can add them to the existing &lt;strong>Skyrim Script Extender&lt;/strong> mod folder.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Inside the downloaded SKSE archive, double-click the &lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong> folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extract the &lt;strong>Scripts&lt;/strong> folder to &lt;code>\Mod Organizer 2\mods\Skyrim Script Extender\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>When you now launch SKSE through Mod Organizer 2, the executable and two DLLs will be temporarily copied into the actual root folder by the Root Builder plugin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meanwhile, the scripts will be loaded in MO2’s virtual data folder and recognised by the game just as if you had installed them directly into the actual data folder. Unchecking the mod in MO2 is sufficient to completely disable it.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-success" role="alert">
This is how the entirety of SKSE can be installed through Mod Organizer 2.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="skse-ini">SKSE INI&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Two of SKSE&amp;rsquo;s features need to be enabled in an INI file:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>iTintTextureResolution&lt;/strong> allows you to adjust the texture resolution of tint masks. By default, Skyrim&amp;rsquo;s tint masks (this includes war paints, make-up, or dirt masks applied to faces) can only have a resolution of 512 x 512 pixels which can look very blurry. Even if you install 2048 x 2048 pixel (2K) retextures, they will look like 512 x 512 in-game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>ClearInvalidRegistrations&lt;/strong> is intended to clean up orphaned OnUpdate() events and prevent saves from bloating or breaking as a result of uninstalling certain mods.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="creating-skse-ini">Creating SKSE INI&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The SKSE INI must be located under &lt;code>\Data\SKSE\SKSE.ini&lt;/code>. We can use Mod Organizer 2 and create it from scratch.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/create-empty-mod.png">crossed tools icon&lt;/a> above the mod order and select &lt;strong>Create empty mod&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Name the new mod &lt;strong>Skyrim Script Extender - SKSE INI&lt;/strong> and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click the new mod and select &lt;strong>Open in Explorer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Inside the new mod folder, create another new folder called &lt;strong>SKSE&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Within that &lt;strong>SKSE&lt;/strong> folder, right-click and select &lt;strong>New&lt;/strong> &amp;raquo; &lt;strong>Text Document&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rename the new file to &lt;strong>SKSE.ini&lt;/strong>.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Make sure to change the file extension from TXT to INI.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After changing the file extension and confirming, a warning window will pop up. Click &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/skse-ini-creation.png" alt="SKSE INI Creation">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="skse-ini-edits-for-skse">SKSE INI Edits for SKSE&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Next, we need to populate our new INI file.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Go back into &lt;strong>Mod Organizer 2&lt;/strong> and press F5 to refresh.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Double-click &lt;strong>SKSE INI&lt;/strong> in your mod order and switch to the &lt;strong>INI Files&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the &lt;code>\SKSE\SKSE.ini&lt;/code> file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Copy and paste the following into the empty file:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>[Display]
iTintTextureResolution=2048
[General]
ClearInvalidRegistrations=1
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
You can set the texture resolution for face tints to any resolution you like, although anything above 2048 (2K) is simply overkill unless you are planning to take a lot of close-up screenshots. Keep in mind that you will also have to install higher resolution retextures for tint masks later on for this setting to make a difference.
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Hit &lt;strong>CTRL+S&lt;/strong> to save your edits and close the window.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check the box for the new mod to enable it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/skse-ini-mo2.png" alt="SKSE INI Creation">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="other-skse-ini-settings">Other SKSE INI Settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
The below INI settings &lt;strong>should not&lt;/strong> be added to your SKSE INI. The section is FYI only and can be skipped.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Beyond the two settings that we added, there are other options that are largely relics of the SLE days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One allows you to adjust memory allocation, but while memory was a real issue in Skyrim LE, the 64bit engine upgrade in Skyrim SE all but solved the problem. The settings were very recently enabled in SKSE for SE; however, most people use the memory manager from SSE Engine Fixes instead (another mod, to be installed soon).&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>[Memory]
DefaultHeapInitialAllocMB=
ScrapHeapSizeMB=
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>There is also an option to enable diagnostics. I am not entirely certain if this is valid in SKSE for SE to begin with (the changelog makes no mention of it), but it would be irrelevant anyway. What it logs are missing master files and missing plugins in a save. You will be able to see the former in Mod Organizer 2 and the latter upon attempting to load a save after disabling plugins that it relies on.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>[General]
EnableDiagnostics=1
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;h2 id="address-library-for-skse">Address Library for SKSE&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To alleviate the problem of SKSE and SKSE plugins breaking with every Skyrim update, &lt;strong>meh321&lt;/strong> (the author of a number of groundbreaking mods) released &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/32444">Address Library for SKSE&lt;/a>. This modder&amp;rsquo;s resource &lt;u>allows SKSE plugins to become version independent from SKSE&lt;/u> by storing their offsets in a separate database.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
Due to the substantial changes that were made to the SkyrimSE.exe in the AE update, patch &lt;strong>1.6.317.0&lt;/strong>, there is now a new version of Address Library exclusively for post-AE Skyrim SE, covering versions &lt;strong>1.6.x&lt;/strong>. Various SKSE plugins for SKSE AE were updated to use this version of Address Library.
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open the Nexus page for &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/32444">Address Library for SKSE&lt;/a> and switch to the &lt;strong>Files&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Locate the &lt;strong>All in one (Anniversary Edition)&lt;/strong> main file and click the &lt;strong>Mod Manager Download&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/address-library-download.png" alt="Address Library Download">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In the right pane of Mod Organizer 2, switch to the &lt;strong>Downloads&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Double-click the downloaded file and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to install the mod.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It will now appear in your mod order. Check the box to activate it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="test-run">Test Run&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Finally, we should give SKSE a test run.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SKSE only functions properly if Skyrim SE is launched via skse_loader.exe.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also remember that the game must always be launched via Mod Organizer 2 in order for it to recognise the virtual data folder.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
Always start the game by running the Script Extender through Mod Organizer 2.
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Make sure all new mods are checked in the left pane.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the &lt;strong>Skyrim Script Extender&lt;/strong> from the executables drop-down menu.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Run&lt;/strong> to launch the Skyrim Script Extender through Mod Organizer 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/mo2-run-skse.png" alt="MO2 Run SKSE">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of opening the launcher, running the game through SKSE will bring you into the main menu directly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you are in the main menu, open the &lt;strong>console&lt;/strong>, a dev tool that will become quite handy, particularly for troubleshooting. You can bring it up by pressing the &lt;strong>tilde&lt;/strong> key (location marked in blue below, in case you have trouble finding it):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/tilde.jpg" alt="Tilde">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In the console, type &lt;strong>skse&lt;/strong> and hit &lt;strong>Enter&lt;/strong> (capitalisation is irrelevant).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It should return the version of SKSE you just installed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If everything works, close the console (press the tilde key again).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Quit the game.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/skse-check-ingame-ae.jpg" alt="SKSE Check">&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="if-you-are-currently-working-through-the-core-module-return-to-step-2bgcore-modulestep2meta-files">If you are currently working through the Core Module, return to &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/core-module/step2/#meta-files">Step 2&lt;/a>.&lt;/h4></description></item><item><title>Bg: Skyrim Version Check</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/skyrim-version-check/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/skyrim-version-check/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers how to check the currently installed version of Skyrim.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/clean-install">Clean Install&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Follow these steps to find out which version of Skyrim you currently have installed:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Navigate to &lt;code>\Steam\steamapps\common\Skyrim Special Edition\&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-click the &lt;strong>SkyrimSE.exe&lt;/strong> inside and select &lt;strong>Properties&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Switch to the &lt;strong>Details&lt;/strong> tab and check under &lt;strong>Product version&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/sse-1-6-640.png" alt="Version Check">&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-success" role="alert">
&lt;strong>Currently recommended version:&lt;/strong> Skyrim SE 1.6.640 (Steam).
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
If your version of Skyrim SE does not correspond to the version specified above, you need to &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/downgrade-skyrim">downgrade&lt;/a>.
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Bg: Update Proofing</title><link>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/update-proofing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/update-proofing/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This module covers how to prevent Skyrim from automatically updating.&lt;p>
&lt;strong>Prerequisite(s):&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://thephoenixflavour.com/bg/additional-modules/clean-install">Clean Install&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The version-specific nature of SKSE and related mods makes forced updates of the base game quite disruptive. They can completely break a modded setup, potentially rendering you unable to play until the modding scene has caught up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fortunately, update-proofing Skyrim is simple:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In your games library in Steam, right-click &lt;strong>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Special Edition&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select &lt;strong>Properties&lt;/strong> and switch to the &lt;strong>Updates&lt;/strong> tab.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure &lt;strong>Automatic updates&lt;/strong> are set to &lt;strong>Only update this game when I launch it&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://thephoenixflavour.com/Pictures/bg/additional-modules/update-proofing.png" alt="update proofing">&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
Of course, this would still force you to update whenever you attempt to launch the game through its default executables. However, SKSE comes with its own launcher which you must always use to launch the game for it to work properly. Launching the game through SKSE will &lt;u>not&lt;/u> prompt Steam to update, meaning you can stay on an older version of the game for as long as you desire.
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>